so far we learned how to manually
discover a number of very dangerous
vulnerabilities we seen how to how they
work and how to exploit them in today's
video I'd like to show you a tool that
will allow you to automatically discover
vulnerabilities and web applications
it'll allow you to discover the
vulnerabilities that we learned plus
much more the reason why I didn't teach
you this at the start because I wanted
you to learn how to do it manually and I
also wanted you to know how these
vulnerabilities occur so to understand
the reason behind them also these are
just tools so this program is just a
tool it can make mistakes and it can
show false positives it can also miss
vulnerabilities in some cases therefore
I wanted you to know how to do this
stuff manually so if the program doesn't
work or if the program misses something
then you'll be able to find it the best
way to use these programs is as a backup
or as just a tool to help you with your
penetration testing so usually the tool
is very simple I'm going to go on my
applications and then I'm gonna type in
zap
and it's asking me if I want to save the
current session when I search for
something so I'm gonna say no
and this is the main view of the tool so
on the left here you'll see the websites
that you're targeting on the right you
can attack and set the website URL and
in here you'll see the results for your
attacking or for your scan if we go here
on the COG on the left it'll allow you
to modify the options for the program so
you can modify certain aspects of it the
way the fuzzer works the way the spider
works the way the scan works I'm going
to leave everything the same another
thing that you can modify is the
policies used in the scan so something
similar to the scans that we were using
with an maps the intensive scan and all
that so I'm going to press on the plus
I'm going to press on the active scan
and if you press on this on the Left
here
and I'm gonna press on the default plus
policy now you can create your own
policies by using the Add button I'm
gonna press on the default one and I'm
gonna go on modify to see you to show
you the aspects that you can modify so
right here you can modify the name the
threshold and the strength for the
global policy clicking on each of these
categories will allow you to modify the
specific scans that will be performed
for example and the injection tab here
we can see all the injection scans that
the program is going to try for example
you can see SQL injections here you can
see cross-site scripting here and
pressing on the threshold right here we
can set this to default low medium or
high setting it to the default we'll
just default to the values selected here
which is medium right now or you can
have for example if SQL injection is
what you're looking for if you're what
you're looking for is access for the
database then you can set this to high
so that it'll try everything and it will
try to find it in even difficult places
so I'm gonna close all of this I'm
leaving everything the same and I'm
gonna start my attack against the metal
day script so we have it in 10 2014 204
running in the Metasploit able machine
and if we go on the tilde right here
that's the URL so literally I'm just
gonna copy this
and paste it here
and then I'm gonna attack now the tool
is first gonna try to find all the URLs
and then it's going to try and attack
these URLs based on the scan policy that
we used I'm gonna pause the video and
resume it once the scan is over
so the scan is over now and you can see
on the left here we have our website
clicking on it will show you some
results of the spider when it was
looking for the files the very
interesting part is the alerts here
right here you can see all the
vulnerabilities that have been
discovered
on the left here you can see that we
have seven red flags so these are the
high priority alerts we have three
orange flags and five yellow flags and
zero blue so these are organized in the
order of their severity
clicking on any of these categories will
expand it and show the threats that have
been found related to that threat for
example clicking on the path traversal
you'll see all the or else that can be
exploited to read files from the server
clicking on any of these you'll see the
HTTP request that was sent in order to
discover this you'll see the response
that why the tool thinks that this is
vulnerable and we can see that in the
response the tool was able to get the
contents of etc' password right here you
can see the URL that the tool used to
exploit this vulnerability and in here
you can see a description of what the
current vulnerability is and how it has
been exploited
in here you can see the risk of it so
this is very high you can see the
confidence so how confident the tool
about the existence of this
vulnerability you can see that it's been
injected into a page and the attack is
trying to get et Shi password so let's
try and right click on this and open it
in browser and as you can see now it
exploited it for us and it showed us the
output for this vulnerability and we can
read the contents of etc' password and
you can see that the exploit has been
exploited in this URL right here
let's have a look at another example
for example a cross-site scripting and
again the tool also checks for post and
get parameters so sometimes when the
parameter when the injection is sent
into text boxes or even sent without
text boxes if it's sent in a post
parameter you won't see it in the URL so
it actually checks for post and get and
you can see here it found a
vulnerability in a post request and the
register page and it also found one in a
get page again right click and open in
browser will execute it for us and we
can see the code has been executed again
we can have the URL of the execution
right here if you wanted to use it with
beef or any other tools and we can see
it in here as well the URL that's being
used to exploit this vulnerability let's
just have one more example of an SQL
injection
again click on it it will show you why
it believes that there is an SQL
injection here
it will show you the URL and to show you
the attack that I used a used and one
equals one
and it's in the parameter password and
if you remember we actually did exploit
this parameter opening this in the
browser will show us that the injection
has been is working and it's using a
username and a password called zap so
the tool is very simple very powerful
and very useful you can play around with
it you can play around with the proxy
and with the options and see how you can
enhance the results and achieve even
better results so far in this course
we've seen how to discover and exploit a
large number of vulnerabilities we've
seen how we can exploit these
vulnerabilities such as SQL injections
file inclusion and code execution and
even file upload and get a reverse shell
so that we'll actually have access to
the server itself in the file upload
example we were able to upload a we've
leash L which gives us a lot of
capabilities and a lot of features in
simpler examples like decode execution
and in the SQL injection we only managed
to get a reverse shell so in this
section we're gonna see how we can
interact with the reverse shell with
weebly's shell and we'll see what can we
do now that we actually have access to
the target server so I'm gonna start
with the reverse shell because it
doesn't give us as much capabilities as
we've Lee and then we'll see how we can
escalate that to a Wiggly shell and then
we'll see what we can do after that so
first of all here I'm just going to
listen on port 80 8 8 8
that I just want to get a reverse
connection on this computer now I'm
gonna get my IP by running if config
and my IP is 10 2014 to 13
so I'm just going to go to my DB WI and
exploit the code execution vulnerability
just so that we can have a reverse shell
and then we'll see how we can interact
with it so I'm going to do this quickly
because we've already spoke about it in
the code execution lecture
so I'm just going to set the security
level to low
and then go on the command execution
make this bigger
and as you remember we used to put an IP
address so I'm just going to put
anything
and then semicolon and then the code
that we want to run and I want to get a
connection using netcat so I'm going to
do SCE
and then put the port now this is the
same code that we used in the SQL
injection we on your lapses in PHP code
it's the same code that we used with the
file inclusion vulnerabilities as well
so we'll actually be getting the same
access as what we're getting in here
when we exploit the other
vulnerabilities the SQL injection and
the local file inclusion so if we go
here
now we actually have a complete bash
shell so we can run any bash commands we
want the exact same commands that we've
seen in the Linux basics section at the
start of this course
now in all of the previous lectures we
used to stop once we get to this point
and in the file upload as I said we got
a weave Lachelle which gives us more
more capabilities so the for the first
thing I'm gonna teach you what can you
do now with this access with the reverse
shell access then once we know what you
can do with that we're gonna see how you
could escalate this and convert it to a
Weebly shell which allows you to get do
more attacks or allow you to do more
things on the target computer once we
have a Weebly shell so we'll be at the
same level at as what you'd gain when
you exploit a file upload vulnerability
we'll see what could you do with that so
you'll learn a large number of powerful
attacks like running system commands
even if there is security on the target
server you'll learn how to navigate to
other websites on the same server read
for upload and download files access the
database and bypass security
measurements that might prevent you from
doing these things so in the next
lecture I'm gonna start from here and
we're gonna keep building up on our
access and we'll see what can we do on
the target server
now we actually have a complete bash
shell so we can run any bash commands we
want the exact same commands that we've
seen in the Linux basics section at the
start of this course so I won't be going
about how you do man and how you do help
to see how you use the commands I'm
going to skip through that and I want to
show you a few commands that are useful
when you first gain access to a server
so the first thing you want to check is
what's my privileges at the moment and
the privileges depend on how you gained
your access so it depends on the page
that you gained your access through so
we got our access through this current
page so dependent on what privileges
this page is running us we will get the
same privileges when we get our reverse
shell same goes for SQL the same goes
for everything really so I'm gonna do
Who am I
and as you can see now my privileges rww
data so I'm not rude I'm not admin I'm
not MSF admin I'm www data and this is
very important because when you're root
you can do anything you want on the
server when you are another user then
you have less privileges or less
permissions to do stuff on the current
web server
so another thing that you want to check
is the kernel version of the computer so
you can do you name a
and this will display a lot of
information other than the kernel
version so you see the computer name and
you can see the version of the kernel
that this is important if you're trying
to run a local exploit to escalate your
privileges to a higher privileges or
maybe even get root privileges which
will give you access to do anything you
want on the on the whole server not only
on this website
as I said you can run any of the
commands that we learned so far
so you can do allies to list the current
files and we can see that there is help
index and source you can do PWD to say
to see where you are and we are
currently at VAR w WD v wi vulnerability
is and x AK so you can navigate through
this exactly the same way you'd navigate
with a normal Linux system so we can do
a CD dot dot to go back do a PWD and
we're at vulnerabilities again CD dot
and another CD dot dot now if I do a PWD
you'll see that I'm as bar www and this
is the document root at the moment so if
I do an LS L to get more information and
note we can see here the permissions and
before the permissions now if you see
you see notice that there is a D here
that D means that this is a directory
it's not a file and when you don't see
the D that means it's a file in here now
you can see that we have access to all
the other websites so we can access the
Tiki Wicki website we can also access
the Matilda website and you can access
the DV wi right here
so what this shows you is if you manage
to hack into any website then most of
the time you can actually navigate to
the same websites on the same server and
this is what I said in the information
gathering section I said it's very
important because sometimes your target
website will not have any
vulnerabilities but you might find
something on the same server and from
that you can navigate to your website so
for example we gained our access through
dvwa and let's say Mattel a day was our
actual target but we couldn't find
anything in it so we hacked into the
server through dvwa and I can navigate
now to Mattel a day so I can just do CD
Mattila day
and then I can do an LS L to see the
files you can remove files using the RM
command
you can delete files you can do anything
you want really now in the other
websites in Mattila day even though we
never actually got access to Mathilde we
got our access through DB WI
now one of the very important commands
is cat which allows you to read files
and one very important file that you
always want to read is the et Cie
password now we actually try to read
this using the local file inclusion
vulnerability but I want to show you now
so if you do a cat etc' password
you can see that we can read all the
content of this file right here and what
this file has it shows you the users
installed on the current computer and it
shows you the directory for these users
now in this particular setup all the
websites are stored in var www so their
soul and var www and then you can put DV
WI to access the DV WI website or you
can put Matilda day to access Matilda
most of the time you won't see this in
most websites they actually create a
user for each website and the user
usually corresponds to the website name
so for example let's say your example
your target was Facebook then the user
would be called Facebook or Facebook
user or something similar to that so
what you'd want to be doing is
you want to go through this file and see
the path for that for your target
website so let's say you hacked into
this website through Google and Facebook
is on the same server then look for a
user called Facebook and then just
navigate to that file now you can see
that the www data user right here and
you can see that it has its directory
stored ad VAR w w w again if you open
that you'll see all the websites in here
so if we just do CD bar then you can
list whatever you want so the take on
lesson from this is that on a reversal
you can basically run any command any
Linux command you have dependent on the
privileges that you have the privileges
depend on the page or the source that
gave you the access so whatever
privileges that resource is running
you'll actually get the same privileges
the same permissions and once you are in
a server the server is just a computer
so once you gain access to that server
you can increase your privileges you can
escalate them and try to access other
websites on the same server how you
access the other websites it's in the
ATC password you list that and you see
the user corresponding to your target
website and just open their directory
using the CD command
now I'm going to attach a list of the
Bosch commands that you can run so that
you can go through them try them and see
how they work for you
I mentioned earlier that we've Lee allow
us to run a number of very useful
functions on the target server if we
manage to upload its shell to that
server so in this lecture we'll see how
we can convert our basic shell access to
a weave leash L so I'm going to create
first of all I actually have connection
here coming from my MIT exploitable
machine and my privileges are just
normal www data
as you can see now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to create my weave leash l
first so we've done this in the file
upload vulnerability so it's very simple
all you have to do is just run Weebly
and then generate to create a shell or
create a backdoor and then we're going
to have to set a password for that
backdoor and I'm going to set it to 1 2
3 4 5 6 and then state where do you want
to save it and I'm gonna save it in root
and I'm gonna call it shell
now in the file upload vulnerability we
actually created the shell with PHP
format right now I'm not going to create
it in PHP because I have to download it
from the Metasploit abel machine when
PHP files are downloaded the source code
will not be downloaded with them so if I
create it as PHP
and download it from the Metasploit abel
machine it's not gonna work properly as
I wanted so what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
call it it as I'm gonna create it as txt
and then rename it once I download it
add the Metasploit abel machine
all I have to do now is upload it
somewhere that is accessible by the met
exploitable machine so in real-life
scenarios you want to be able to upload
it to somewhere where you can directly
access the shell in this lecture because
we're doing it in our local command our
local environment I'm actually gonna
just put it in my web server in my Cali
machine which is accessible by MIT
exploitable so I'm just gonna do CP to
copy and I'm gonna copy your route
she'll txt and I'm gonna copy it to VAR
www
HTML which is my document root in Cali
and I'm also gonna start my web server
so I'm just going to do service
Apache to start
and now a patch is running so I
literally have I basically have a web
server now which contains this current
file let's see if the file exists so I'm
just gonna come here and I'm gonna go to
my local host so pretty much I can just
do localhost but I'm gonna put my IP
which is 10 2014 to 13 and we call the
chalghi XD
as you can see now we can see the code
for the actual back door this is very
important so when you upload it to a
server make sure that you can access the
shell directly like this and make sure
that when you access it you can see the
code without anything on the sides with
no ads with no banners with nothing
showing up around it so you can
literally access the bear code once you
do that and you have this URL all you
have to do is just download it from the
Metasploit able machine so at the moment
this is my meter exploitable machine so
for I do a you name a just to confirm
you can see that I'm actually connected
and inside the Metasploit able machine
so all I have to do is download it but I
can't download it anywhere I need to
download it somewhere again accessible
by my Kali machine so I can connect to
it so you want to you want to download
it somewhere within the document root
within the VAR www or whatever document
root your current web site uses so if I
do a PWD
you can see that I'm inside VAR w w dvwa
vulnerabilities so I'm gonna do CD back
to go one one step back and if I do an
LS here
you can see the files that we have in
this current directory
now let's try to download the file and
this current directory now sometimes you
want to be able to download files
depending on your privileges or
permissions so I'm just gonna do a
double you get and this is the download
command so W get can be used on Linux
systems to download any files so you
literally just do W get and the T and
then you put the URL that you want to
download so the URL that we want to
download is HTTP
10 2014 to 13
and then we called the file shell txt
now I'm going to give it some time to
download
and then I'm gonna do an LS again
and as you can see we have a file called
shell dot txt now this file is uploaded
on the Metasploit Abel machine inside
DVD DVD WI vulnerabilities again if we
do PWD you can see that we have DV WI
followed by vulnerabilities so let's go
and try to browse it in here and make
sure that it exists 10 2014 to 12 which
is that's where our DV WI is and then
we're going to go to vulnerabilities
and our file is called shell the txt
I didn't put the dvwa before it
and as you can see we can access the
file now which is uploaded inside dvw
I've ulnar abilities we can see our
shell dot txt now again this is not good
enough because it's not getting executed
so now all we have to do is change its
extension to PHP again and again we're
going to do that from our basic shell
access right here so we're gonna do mV
shell dot txt
- shell dot php'
and then do allies to make sure that the
process was done properly and we can see
that our shell is called shell dot php'
now we can connect to the shell using
our weave Lee client so we're just going
to do weave Lee
give the shell URL so our URL the shell
is stored now at HTTP so this is where
you uploaded the shell so it's it's
exactly the same URL as this but with
dot PHP because we change the file
extension I'm actually going to copy
this
and I'm gonna set this to PHP
and then we're going to put the password
which is one two three four five six
make sure you put the same password that
you said when you created the back door
hit enter and as we can as you can see
were inside the target computer we're
inside this target and we can run all
the commands that we've li allow us to
do so we can just do an LS I PWD and all
the next commands plus all the commands
that we Li allow us to do all the
functions that we allow us to do which
we're gonna have a look on in the next
videos
in this video we're gonna see how to
interact with weave Li and some of the
basic commands so I'm going to connect
to the shell that we already uploaded in
the previous video so all I'm going to
do is weave Li the URL where the shell
is located followed by the password can
hit enter and I'm in so the first thing
we're gonna do is run the help command
so if you just type in help you'll see
all the commands that you can run using
weave Lee so these are all the functions
that you can do
so you can see the name of the function
followed by the description of what that
function does so the first thing the
first thing that we're going to have a
look on is system info which basically
displays information about the current
server that we have access to so for any
of these commands all you have to do is
type it and it'll run now some of them
require options and we'll see how we do
that so the first thing you want to do
before you even run the D command is you
just tap the command
so in our case it's system info
and then type - age to see the options
and the required some of them have
required commands and some of them have
only optional arguments that you can
give so for this one you can specify
what kind of information you want by put
in - info but generally you can just run
system info and it will show you
information about the current operating
system so I'm just gonna run it normally
so I'm just going to type system info
and as you can see it collects
information about the current server so
you can see the IP you can see where
your shell is located
you can see the folder where the shell
is located you can see information about
the operating system so you can see it's
a Linux operating system you can see the
kernel version and as I said before this
is useful when you're trying to find
local buffer overflow exploits so that
you can escalate your privileges you can
see where the config is and again we're
going to talk about that in the future
we can see the PHP version again very
useful when you're trying to bypass
functions when you're trying to exploit
vulnerabilities and again we can see
that it's a Linux operating system and
our current user is www data so it's the
result of the Who am I command and you
can also see the document root which
basically refers to the directory which
Apache uses as its base so you can see
that or we know already that in our MIT
exploitable all the websites are stored
and var www and then after that if you
put DV WI you'll be in DB WI if you put
Matilda you'll be in Matilda so again
this is very important information if
you're trying to navigate from web one
website to another
speaking of navigating from one website
to another we seen before how we can do
cat
et Cie password and that will give us
the locations that will give us the
users on the current operating system
and the locations where the the document
root is and I told you that you can use
these locations to navigate within the
server and go from one website to
another missile they also have a
function that will automatically display
this information for you without doing
cat et Cie password and the function is
called if you just do the help
the function is called
audit et Cie password so again all you
have to do is just type in audit
et Cie password
and before I run this again I'm gonna do
the minus H to see the help and here you
see why is this useful now you're gonna
you might think that why would I even
need this function all I have to do is
just do cat ITC password and I'll see
the results why would I need this
function why would I use it and what's
handy in here is the vector argument so
what this argument allows you to do is
it specifies the method of reading that
file because depending on how you gained
your shell access depending on the
configuration on the server on the web
applications on the current user and a
lot of variables you might not be able
to read what's inside that file so you
might do cut
et Cie password and you get nothing or
you'll get permission denied so what's
useful with this command is you can
specify a number of methods to read that
file and these the methods are listed in
here in the vector argument and if you
can't get it with one method then just
try the next one so I'm going to show
you how to do this now and this is very
useful because you have this vector
argument with a lot of the functions in
we've Lee and it's really handy because
as I said depending on the permissions
some of the functions might not work and
you can just use a different vector and
it'll work
so for our example we can just do audit
et Cie password and this will actually
work but what I want to do is I want to
show you how to use the vector in case
that didn't work for you so all you have
to do is just put in the vector argument
followed by the vector that you want to
use so an example would be a file right
here so all we have to do is just type
in file
and we can see that this particular
vector didn't work
so you can just try a different vector
and we're gonna go with F read
again this one didn't work so we try
another one and let's go with the
file get contents
again no log let's go and try posix get
PW ID
and here we go so like I said in your
example or in your case try all the
vectors some of them will work some of
them might not work depending on the
configuration
so it's really handy option to use if
the normal cut etc' password didn't work
so we already seen in previous lectures
how we can run Linux commands on the
target server all you have to do is just
literally type in the command for
example we can type in PWD to see where
we are we can navigate back see the dot
we can list what we have and we can do
anything we want on the target server
unfortunately this is this isn't always
the case in many cases you might gain
access upload your shell and have we've
Lee working but every time you run a
command you won't see the result or you
might get permission denied and this
will happen because the server is
configured in a way to prevent you from
running commands on that server so what
we're going to do is we're gonna use a
function that comes in with we've Lee so
let's first type in help to see all the
functions or the commands that we can
use and the function that we're going to
use is called shell SH and as you can
see in the description it says it allows
us to execute shell commands so using
the function is very simple all you have
to do is type in shell SH and then type
the command that you wanna run so you
can type in again PWD and you'll see the
current working directory now this will
just use the default way that we've been
using so far anyway so if the default
white doesn't really work this will
probably not work for you either what I
want to show you here is what this
function allows you to do so it actually
allows us to run Linux commands using a
number of methods so it's very similar
to the idea of the e.t.c password when
we were reading it and in this case if
you can't run commands on the target
server then it's probably because your
user is configured in a way that's not
allowed to run bash commands so what
this function allow us to do is run the
command through a PHP function or
through a Python function or through a
perl function so this way you're
actually not running the command
directly you're running a PHP function
and then the PHP function itself runs
the command therefore if you don't have
permission to run commands directly
you'll be able to bypass this by running
the command through a PHP function
so to see all the vectors or all the
methods that we can use to run the
command we're gonna do shell Sh
followed by - H
and as you can see the first thing you
see is the general way of using the
command so you type in shell SH and then
you type where you want the command to
be displayed this is the redirection and
we're not going to mess with that
because we want it to be displayed on
screen after that you specify the vector
so this is what we're talking about this
is the methods that you can use to run
the shell commands and you can see that
you can run it using system so this is
the default way of running the commands
you can also use a pass a PHP
pass-through function so this is the one
that we used to use when we were
executing commands using PHP remember in
the code execution vulnerabilities again
you have a number of PHP functions so if
one of the functions is disabled you can
use the other one you can also run
commands using Python through the Python
interpreter and you can run functions
using the Perl interpreter so to use
this we're gonna use the same command
shell SH followed by - V just like we
see here in the template so cell knows
first thing you type in is the command
followed by the vector and we're going
to choose a vector to use and for the
first one let's try the pearl system so
we're going to use pearl
system so this is the actual function
that will execute the command that we
specified
and you can see here in the template so
it's shell Sh followed by the vector
followed by the command that we want to
run and let's run this time we're gonna
try to run Who am I
hit enter
and as you can see this doesn't work so
we're gonna go back and we're gonna
change the vector and let's try to use
pass through and we know pass through
works because we used it before so again
we're using pass through as a vector and
we're running the command Who am I hit
enter and as you can see now the kamat
got executed on the server so again in
our particular case here this doesn't
seem very useful because we can run
commands normally just we can just type
in Who am I but in a lot of real case
scenarios you won't be able to run
commands directly like this and using
this function with the vector could be
very useful so all you have to do is
just use this shell SH and experimental
with all the available vectors until one
of them works for you
so we're still inside Weebly and in this
lecture we're gonna see how we can
upload and download files from the
target system
at the moment I'll be running some shell
commands and I'm gonna look for a file
that's interesting for me so with first
thing we're gonna do is download the
file and I'm gonna do PW at the end you
can see that I'm in VAR w w w dvwa i'm
gonna do an LS to see all the files
right here and we can see that there is
a directory called config and the config
directories are or if you see a file
called config or directory called config
then chances are it contains important
information most of the time it contains
information about connecting to the
database so I'm going to navigate to
that directory using the CD command
and then I'm gonna list to see what I
have
and you can see that we have a file
called config dot int dot PHP now we can
try to read this using the cat command
and we can try to read it using the
functions that come with we've Lee but
this is not what we're interested in in
this lecture let's see how we can
download this file so we can read it on
our local machine now remember you can't
actually browse through this file so if
we go here to the server
and if we go to dvwa
config'
and you see that there is a config file
but if we click it you'll see that you
can't actually read it because it's
written in PHP and PHP files cannot be
write remotely so even if you view the
source
you'll see that it's empty it has no
lines whatsoever
so let's go back and we're gonna use the
download so the download is called file
download and then I'm gonna put minus H
to see how to use it because I don't
know how to use it so just I want you to
see the idea of how you use all of these
functions you put the function name - H
to see how to use it and you can see
that the way to use it is you literally
just specify a file download you can
specify the vector so this is similar to
when we were doing when we were reading
the e.t.c password or executing the
shell SH executing shell commands so you
can specify the method of reason of
downloading the file because sometimes
maybe the basic download method will not
work for you so you can just do minus
vector and you specify the vector that
you want so in this example I'm just
going to use the default one I'm not
gonna specify a vector so again we're
gonna do file download our path which is
the remote path so the file on the
server that you want to download
followed by the location that you want
to download it to on your local machine
so the command is gonna be file download
the remote path is going to be config
dot inked as PHP and I want to store it
in my route so this is on my actual
local machine it's going to be stored
and rude and I'm gonna call it config
downloaded
and I'm gonna make it a txt so you can
actually put it a PHP if you want but
I'm gonna make it a txt in my case so
the command is very simple it's file
download followed by the file the full
path or the location where the file is
located and the file for me is located
in the carrot working directory and it's
called config dot Inc dot PHP and I want
to download it to my route config
downloaded dot exe so I'm gonna call it
config downloaded dot txt and if I want
it if this command didn't work for me
then I can just do either vector by
doing - vector
and specify the way that I'm gonna
download it so I can just specify
through all the methods that we have
here so we have file we have a freed
file get and base64 so I'm just gonna
use the file
that's it the file should be downloaded
so let's go to our file manager
in the road and you can see that there
is a file called config downloaded dot
txt if we double click it you'll see the
information that was saved in that file
and remember when we went on the browser
nothing was displayed when you go here
you'll see that you can see everything
because we actually downloaded the
source code for the file
now let's see how we can upload files to
the server so uploading files can be
very useful because you can use it to
literally upload anything you want so
you can upload any PHP script that you
want PHP scripts can be used to do
anything you can use it to gain a
reverse shell you can use it to execute
commands on the server you can use it to
connect to the database and browse
through the files and you can even use
it to exploit local vulnerabilities such
as buffer overflows and code execution
so the possibilities are endless really
one thing to note is that now when I
check my privileges so if I do Who am I
to check the current user you will see
that I am the www data and the current
website is running under that user so
basically I can do anything I want on
this website because I am the owner of
this website at the moment and a lot of
the cases depending on how you gained
your access to the website your
privileges might be nobody so when you
do your who am I instead of getting www
data you'll be who you'll be nobody and
when you're nobody you can't upload
anywhere you want you can only upload to
directories that has seven seven seven
permissions so two directories that
basically allow anybody to upload to
them so if you do LS Li you can see that
we have all all of our files and you can
see that all of them are owned by
www.cerritosinfiniti.com
therefore I can upload anywhere but what
we're going to do in this lecture we're
going to pretend that we can't upload
anywhere we're gonna pretend that I am
nobody and if I want to upload something
while being nobody we have to upload it
to a place where everybody is allowed to
upload files and that place which should
have a seven seven seven permissions
these are the permissions here and what
they look like is they should look like
this
so there should be no minuses in it and
it'll basically mean that everybody can
do anything they can read write and
execute so we can see from the
directories here now the directory start
with a D and the permission so we can
see that from the directories here we
have nothing with seven seven seven
permissions so we actually have to look
around
I'm sorry I clicked ctrl C there so I'm
just going to go back and connect back
to Eve Lea
so again we're gonna do PWD and we're
we're in VAR www dvwa and where I want
to go is we can see an interesting
directory here called hackable so let's
go in it and then list see what's in
there so we're going to go into hackable
using CD command and then again we're
going to do LS L
you
and again there is nothing really
interesting here so let's go back
and we're gonna navigate back again
and if we list here you'll see that we
are in the root directory and we can
navigate to different websites now and
if you notice we have a directory called
Daffy here now if this directory doesn't
belong to us it actually belongs to the
root user so it doesn't belong to
www.upalliance.org
so it has seven seven seven permissions
which looked like this so we're going to
navigate into that place
CGT dev we're gonna list to see if there
is anything already there and we can see
that there is no files whatsoever there
so we're gonna upload our file and we're
gonna use a function called file upload
we're going to do the - H like you like
usual
and you can see that the way you used
this function is you type in file upload
first you can use the - f - force /
light to overwrite the file if it exists
already you can specify the file content
and you can specify the vector and again
the vector is the method of how the file
is going to be uploaded and I'm going to
keep this the default so I'm not going
to use the - vector and then he gives
the local path so where the file is
stored on your current computer on our
Kali machine followed by the remote path
so where do you want the file to be
stored on the target server so the file
that I wanna upload is located in my
route so if we go to the file manager
you'll see that I have the file in the
root and it's just called tester TX it's
actually a shell but it's just called
test dot txt so we'll try to upload that
and so our local directory is going to
be root
test.txt
and we want to upload that to the remote
path of the current path so if you want
to specify the current place the current
working directory where you are you just
have to put adult followed by a forward
slash so this is where we want to upload
it and then we have to give it a name so
I'm gonna call it shell or test shell
uploaded
though txt just the name so we know that
the file has been uploaded correctly
so again the command is very simple is
file upload you specify where the file
is stored on your current machine and
mine is stored in root and it's called
tester txt and then you specify where
you want to upload it and I'm going to
upload it to the current working
directory that's why I have a dot
forward slash and then followed by the
name that I want to call it so I'm going
to call it test shell uploaded the txt
I'm going to hit enter
and you can see that it's given us a
true statement which means that the file
has been uploaded if we do analyze
you'll see that the file has been
uploaded to this particular directory so
now we can go to our web browser and we
upload it for the file to a directory
called of and then we called it test
shell uploaded txt
and as you can see now we can see the
file has been uploaded and this is the
actual content of the file it's an
encrypted shell so it has been uploaded
perfectly or correctly and again we
uploaded it to a directory that doesn't
belong to us but the main idea is the
directory has to have seven seven seven
permissions and that way even if you
have and nobody even if you are nobody
you can upload to that directory
if the directories have your permissions
like the www data here all these
directories we can upload to them
regardless of the permissions they have
because we are www data so what I showed
you here is just an example of how you
would upload files if you had nobody
permissions
in this lecture we'll see how we can get
a reverse connection from our weave
Lachelle so at the moment we uploaded
we've lee and we're connecting to it
directly using this URL so when we hit
enter we're actually just doing a direct
connection and it's as if we're just
interacting with a normal PHP script
uploaded on that directory so what we
want to do is maybe in some cases you
can't read your own commands like this
so right now I can run whatever command
I want whatever Linux command we also
seen how we can use the shell SH
function that comes with we've ly to try
and bypass if we can't run commands if
none of that works or if you want it
just an actual direct reverse connection
from the target webserver to our machine
then you can follow what I'm going to do
in this lecture it can be really handy
because you'll have a direct connection
and you'll be able to bypass a lot of
security measurements
so we're going to do help first to see
the options that we have and the
function that I want to use today is the
reverse where is it back to reverse TCP
and it basically just gives you a
reversed TCP shelf so it won't be
executed through a PHP it will be a
reversal reverse connection coming from
the target server towards your computer
and because of that it will bypass
firewalls because the connection is
coming out of this web server not to the
web server so the first thing we're
gonna do is as usual we're just gonna
run backdoor
reverse TCP and I'm gonna put minus H to
see the options that we can get with
this function and you can see the way to
use it is the first thing you need to
specify the name of the function
followed by the type of shell so we're
going to leave that the same you can
tell it not to auto connect but we don't
want that we actually want it to
automatically connect and then you can
specify the vector and again the vector
is very important and it specifies the
way the reverse connection will be
spawned so you can use net cut it can be
done through netcat it can be done
through Python it can be done through
Perl Ruby these are all programming
languages so if the connection doesn't
if the target server doesn't have netcat
installed or if it has certain security
or permissions that prevent you from
using netcat then you can try to get
your shell through Python if python is
not installed or if it has some sort of
measurements that prevent python from
connecting back to you then you can do
it through perl and again if perl is
configured in a way that it's not
allowed to spawn reverse connections you
can do it through Ruby and again you can
use any of these vectors until one of
them works for you and once one of them
work for you chances are you're going to
be able to bypass a lot of security
measurements definitely you'll be able
to run - commands on the target server
so if you can't run bash commands
normally and if you tried the shell as a
CH function that we seen in an earlier
video
still didn't work for you then you
should come to this try this method if
it works then you'll be able to run any
shell commands you want on the target
server so let's try it in action so
we're going to type in backdoor
reverse TCP
what are going to give it the vector
going to want to use netcat
and then we're gonna give it dependent
on this as you can see so we did that
and we gave it the vector then we need
to give it our localhost so the IP
address of our current computer followed
by the port that we want the connection
to be done through so to get the IP
address of my computer I'm just gonna
run if config
and you can see that my IP address is 10
2014 to 13 so I'm going to close this
and then we're going to give you the
port and I'm going to set the port to
so the command is very simple
five-thirty burst TCP vector which is
going to be not cut and then we put our
current IP address followed by the port
that we want the connection to be done
through I'm going to hit enter
now the connection established so now we
can run any commands we want and keep in
mind that these commands will be
executed through netcat so the
connection is coming back now from the
server to us and now we're in
communicating with it through a
completely different part it's not gonna
go through we've Li it's actually going
to go through netcat so if there was
some sort of security that didn't allow
us to run commands through we've Li then
we'll be able to bypass them now so now
we can use it we're going to do a PWD
for example and we have to add a
semicolon after it you can see that
where we are we can do a Who am I
seems like we lost our connection so I'm
just going to do it back
so again we can do Who am I
we can pretty much do any command we
want now again if this didn't really
work for you you can go ahead and try a
different vector you can try the Python
you can try the Perl after each of these
vectors try to see Who am I and see the
current permissions or the current user
that you're running as because you might
actually be running under a different
user
one thing to keep in mind here is your
IP because the connection is is a
reverse connection so it's coming back
from the target web server to your
computer therefore at the moment I'm
actually using a private IP within my
connect network but it works because the
website is on the same network if I was
doing this against a real website this
won't work because my private IP is not
accessible publicly because it's hidden
behind the router so if you want to
receive connections if you want to
receive reverse connections from an
actual web server and if you're not on
the same network as that web server then
you need to either set up your Kali
machine as a DMZ host or you need to
enable IP forwarding to enable the port
at the port that you're using here so
8080 in this case to be forwarded to
your private IP
you can do both of these things from the
control panel of your router your router
is usually located at the first IP so my
IP now is 10 2014 to 13 the router is
usually at the first IP so it will be at
the one so you can access that through
the browser look for the option called
DMZ and set the Kali machine as a DMZ
host another option is to go to port
forwarding add a rule to forward port
8080 to the IP of the Kali machine also
make sure the IP the Kali machine is
connected to your actual network and
it's not set up as a nut network like
this so make sure you have a wireless
card connected to your home network and
from there you will have an actual IP in
your network instead of a private
virtual IP like we have here
a lot of the time we'd be interested in
to more than just hacking into the
website so at the moment we can read
write download modify files on the
current web server but a lot of the time
what actually interests us is data that
is stored in the database so things like
usernames and passwords you won't see
them into files they'll actually be
stored into the database so if you want
to see these things if you want to have
access to them
you have to hack into the database
most of the programs for example dwv wif
metal day and real-world programs like
wordpress they all connect to the
database to store stuff in it and in
order to be able to connect to the
database they do that through a file
called config so there's usually it will
be called config dot PHP see if CFG dot
PHP or something similar to that so the
first thing you want to do is you want
to locate that file and read its content
so this is what we're going we're gonna
do this is gonna be our step 1 so we are
in VAR WWWF so I'm just gonna go to dvwa
so I'm gonna go back once and go to dvwa
and then I'm gonna list and you can see
that we have a directory called config
so we're going to open that directory
and we're going to list
and you can see that we have a file
called config dot ink dot PHP so you can
read that using the normal cat command
so you can literally just do cut
config dot dot PHP and you'll be able to
read the contents a lot of the times
when you do that it's not gonna work so
what you want to do is you can do you
can use a function that comes in with
we've Lee again it's called file read
and it allows you to read the file using
multiple methods so if the normal cat
method didn't work for you you can use
that function to read it and let's see
how we can use that function so we're
just gonna do file
read - H like we always do and you can
see that we have a number of vectors so
we can do one every done it we can do if
I'll get and you can get it in base64 so
again you can use you can use that
similarly to the ways that we were doing
it before so you just do - vector and
we're going to choose file and then you
select the file that you want to read
which is again it's called config dot
Inc dot PHP
and once we read this file you see that
it has information about how to connect
to the database so this file is actually
used by the web application itself to
connect to the database so you always
see these four things you'll see that
the host and you can see that it's set
to the local host here you can see the
database name is called dvwa
the user name is root and password and
in this case it's blank chances are you
won't see a root user and you won't see
a blank password so you'll probably have
like some sort of a name in here and
you'll actually have a password in here
once you have this information you can
connect to the database using an SQL
shell so if we go back to the help here
you see that we have to SQL modules one
of them is the SQL console and this one
will basically allow you to have a
normal an interactive SQL console where
you can run any SQL statement something
similar to what we got with SQL map this
will not work in this case because our
root user is not using any passwords so
it'll just not connect but in normal
cases it should work for you the second
example which is the more useful example
anyway is the SQL dump and this will
basically dump the whole database into a
file and it'll download the file to your
current computer so that you can open it
and read the data normally using a text
editor so we're going to have a look on
this example on the SQL dump so using
using these modules is very similar to
what we've been doing so far so the SQL
console is very similar to the module
anyway so
we're gonna do SQL dump
and we're going to do a - age to see how
to use it
and you can see that the way to use it
is you do SQL dump you select the
database type you don't have to do that
we're not going to do it you give it the
host so let's give it the host and this
is going to be localhost
again we're taking this information from
here from the config file after the host
you want to give it the L path and this
is where the data is going to be saved
in your local computer so let's start it
in route
and we're gonna call it dvwa data
dot txt
and then you want to select the vector
so I'm gonna leave this the way it is
and we're not going to modify that
and then were you have to select the
database again we'll take this
information from here so the database is
dvwa
then you have to give it the user so the
user is route
and my password is blank so again the
command is SQL dump giving it the host
where we want to store the data and then
the database is dvwa the user is root
password is blank hit enter and I did
something wrong here
I forgot to put - I'll pass in here
hit enter
and now it's on us that this method has
failed
so again when something fails we go we
try a different vector so let's try to
use MySQL dump eh so we're going to use
the same command but we're going to add
minus vector to it
and this is going to be MySQL dump Sh
he'll enter
and as you can see now this worked and
it's telling us that the data has been
stored to route dvwa data.txt so I'm
going to go to my file manager and I'm
already on route and you can see that we
have a file here called dvwa data the
txt double-click the file
and right here we can see information
about the whole database so it might
look like gibberish but it's not if you
just have a closer look at it you can
see that you have the table structure
you have a table here called guestbook
you can see that this table has the
following columns it has a column called
comment ID it has a column called
comment and it has a column called name
and you can see that the primary key is
the comment ID going down
you'll see that we have a table called
users you can see the columns are user
ID first name last name user password
and avatar and if you go down you'll
actually see the entries
so you can see that we have a user
called admin and this is their password
this is their working directory again
you have another user called Gordon his
second name is Brown and this is his
password now the passwords are encrypted
so you can go and try to decrypt these
passwords but again this lecture just
show you how to gain access to the
database and dump the whole database
into a local storage and then browse it
the way you want these are actual dump
files so you can actually import them
into PHP myadmin so if you have a web
application background you can go to PHP
myadmin
create a new database and import this
file into that database it will
automatically create a database with
these tables and you'll be able to
easily navigate through this and read
the data