okay so let's see how we can gain full
control and get a meterpreter session
from the target computer so again we're
gonna go on to commands and we're gonna
go on to social engineering now there's
actually a number of ways that you can
use in here to get a reverse shell now
it all depends on how you want to make
your social engineering attack what
we're going to use we're going to use a
notification bar a fake notification bar
and we're choosing Firefox because our
target is runs on Firefox or are using
Firefox so what this will do it will
basically tell the user it will display
a notification bar telling the user that
there is a new update or there is a
plug-in that you need to install once
they install the plug-in then they'll
actually install a backdoor and you'll
gain full access to their computer so
the way we're gonna do this is we're
gonna use the same backdoor that we
always created and we've been using now
I actually have it stored in my web
server so I have it stored in bar
www dot html' and I have it called
update 30 exe but it's the same backdoor
the same reverse HTTP interpreter that
we used before
so I'm gonna give the full address to it
here so it's stored in 10 2014 207
that's my actual IP and the name of the
file is updated to Exe
and then the notification the
notification is just saying there is an
additional plug-in that needs to be
installed to display some elements on
this page now you can change this and
just say critical updates for Firefox
click here to install
so I'm going to hit execute
and if we go on the target you can see
that they're getting a message telling
them that there is a new update for
Firefox and click here to download and
install so the target person will be
like oh yeah I need to install this so
they download it and now basically they
have a backdoor downloaded on their
machine once they try to run this
backdoor to install the update they
think it's an update but they'll
actually run a backdoor which will give
us full access to their computer before
I run the backdoor I need to listen on
the part exactly like we did it before
so I'm just gonna do show options here
to show you I'm not gonna go through all
the steps it's using Metasploit Multi
hunter same way we did it in the video
of listening for ports so we're using
meterpreter reverse HTTP I have my IP
and the port so I'm just gonna do
exploit
and I'm listening for the connections
now now let's run the update that we
just downloaded
you
and if we go on the target you can see
that we got full control over it using a
meterpreter session
now again this is just an example of one
way of gaining full control over the
target computer there's a number of ways
that you can do using beef and there is
a number of social engineering attacks
that you can do to gain full access on
the target computer so again I highly
recommend you go over the plugins and
experiment with them and see what
attacks you can come up with now let's
talk about how we can prevent XSS
vulnerabilities the way these
vulnerabilities happen is because
whatever a user enters something into a
text box or into a parameter that input
is displayed into the HTML so it's
treated as if it's part of the page and
therefore if there is JavaScript in it
the code is being executed so to prevent
this exploit the best thing to do is to
try and minimize the usage of untrusted
input so anytime a user input something
or anytime something's input from
parameters try to minimize that also
make sure that you always escape
whatever that's going to be displayed or
used into the HTML page because XSS can
not only be injected into places where
things are displayed on the page but it
can also be injected into parameters of
certain elements of the HTML page
so what I mean by escaping is converting
each of these characters to what they
would be represented by an HTML you can
do that using scripts and you can do
that using your own script now let me
show you how this happens now I'm here
at my vulnerable web page that we were
using and I'm gonna go to this third one
and obviously can see that every time we
click on that the XSS runs so let's
inspect this element now this element is
where we injected our alert and if we
right-click and go on inspect element it
will show us the HTML of this page or
the HTML of this particular element
right here highlighted so I'm going to
make this bigger and if we look at it
right here you'll see that we have the
name and that's xate and then the other
input which is the message it's a script
and the script where the script tells it
does alert exercise so it's exactly what
we injected into it when we did the
comment so every time we run this page
this piece of code gets is executed so
we need to do is we need to make sure
every time a user enters something and
that something will be displayed on a
page or that something will be used
somewhere in the elements so even the ID
here or even the H the ID is just for
example is a parameter of the Dib it's
not displayed you never see this ID but
this is this can be injectable it can be
injected as well so hackers can actually
try to inject stuff into the parameters
they can try to inject itself into the
image attributes for example they can do
an image and inject stuff into the
source or into the URL so this is just
an example here and every time a user's
input is going to be used anywhere on
the page so even if you don't see it if
you usually don't see it you need to
make sure that you escape that input and
make sure that it does not contain any
code and if it contains any code that
it's it's converted to its HTTP
equivalent once you escape this you'll
actually see this in the message so you
see the message as script
xs/s but it will never be executed the
this script will never actually be
executed on the target person when they
run it
and this is exactly what the high
security level implements so let me go
through the security settings and let me
close this and I'm gonna set this to
high I'm gonna submit it and we'll go
back to our reflected it's the same
measurement are taken in the reflected
and in distort and now if we try to
inject any of our codes that we were
doing before for example if we try to
inject this script so script alert XSS
and then we close the script you'll see
this script exactly the same way that
you would have seen a normal name so if
we say is 8 here you'll just see my name
and if we inject our script you'll see
it appearing as if it's a normal name it
doesn't appear you don't only see what's
between the tags and then the code
doesn't even get executed if we look at
the source you'll see that you see all
the tags so you can see the script tag
you can see the close of the script tag
and everything is being injected
properly so you think that this should
work but it doesn't work because the
website or the web page or the browser
now is that these tags are should be
treated as HTML characters and should
not be treated as part of the code and
this is all thanks to a function that's
being used here which is called the HTML
special characters so it's all thanks to
this function so whatever your input in
in the name it's being filtered through
this function now this function will
iterate over each character that you
entered and it'll tell Hastie ml or the
browser it'll change it to its
equivalent in HTML code therefore the
browser will know that this is not part
of the code and this is part of what
should be displayed on screen as text
and this way no matter what you try to
inject it will be converted to HTML code
which will just be displayed on screen
like normal text or normal characters
now as a user to prevent yourself from
being used into an XSS attack now the
URL coming to you will probably look
like a URL of a trusted website for
example let's assume that you work in a
company and there it was an XSS in your
company and you were logging into your
company and the code gets executed on
you then there isn't much you can do
yourself but you need to be careful so
with beef we saw in order to exploit the
vulnerabilities we were showing for
example a fake update so make sure when
you if you get an if you get a message
always that there is an update make sure
you actually go to the website that
provides did that application so Firefox
said that there is an update go to the
fate to the website a face of Firefox
and see if there is actually an update
and if there is download it from that
website don't download it from the
notification that you got also make sure
you're downloading it from an HTTPS
website and once you download it you can
inspect it and check it the same way
that we seen before to make sure that
there is no back doors or anything in it
it can also check the md5 sum to make
sure that the file hasn't been
manipulated while it was being
downloaded the same one we did the fake
facebook login when you are with beef so
what you can do is whenever you're told
that you got logged out and please log
back in again ignore that go to
facebook.com make sure it's going
through HTTPS and then login to Facebook
so always try to be careful with
notifications popping up telling you you
need to do stuff always be wary and
never trust them
in this lecture we're going to learn how
to bypass other authentication by
manipulating cookie values
now this doesn't always happen and it's
not always possible but it's possible
when the session management is
programmed in a way that can easily be
bypassed and I'll talk more about that
once we actually do the attack but
before we do anything we need to have a
plugin that allow us to modify our
cookies so the first thing that I'm
gonna do is go on Google
and look for cookie editor
Firefox
and I'm gonna download cookie manager
plus all they have to do is just click
on the link to Firefox and install
and it's going to ask you to restart so
I'm going to restart it
and it should be installed now now the
cookies are used to authenticate users
after they login so for example once you
go in here and log in I've already
created an account on this you can
create one by just clicking on the
register here and the account that I
created the username is 8 and the
password is 1 2 3 4 5 6
now once I log in here you'll notice
that every time I go to a different page
I don't have to log in again so every
time I just browse through this website
you'll see that I don't get presented to
log in again and everywhere I go it
knows that I'm logged in as eight now
this is possible based on cookies so
every time I go to this website or to
these pages they know that Zeta is
trying to get in here because the
cookies are stored in my browser and
every time I request something from this
website the cookies are sent to that
webpage and Stellan it that they it has
already authenticated himself and he is
just trying to display this website so
even if I close this and so I'm just
gonna close me till the day and just get
back to it again
you'll see that I'm still logged in as
eight now cookies have a date of expiry
and they'll expire after a while
sometimes the cookies are configured in
a way that they can be easily
manipulated so let's have a look on the
cookies for this website now if we go
I'm gonna click on alt to display the
menus here and then I'm gonna go on
tools cookie manager plus and I'm gonna
search for the name of this website
which is 10 2014 to 12 and that will
display all the cookies that have been
sent so you can see that the PHP SSID
and all these cookies you can see that
there is an two interesting cookies one
of them is called user name and the
other one is called user ID or UID
so this is really interesting and if we
click on edit
you'll see that we have the name of the
cookie is UID or user ID and the content
is 17 so you can try to guess that means
that this cookie is telling this page
that the user ID of the person who's
trying to visit this page is 17 so we
can guess that the user ID for Zaid for
the user that I just created is 17 so
what we can do is we can try to modify
this to a different value and see what
happens and often admin users are
created first at at every website so we
can try to go for one so I'm just going
to delete the 7 and I'm going to keep it
as 1 and then we're gonna save the
cookies like this
I'm going to close that
and then I'm just going to refresh the
page
and now you can see that I've actually
I'm logged in as admin and I can browse
the website and do anything that the
admins are allowed to do and we managed
to do this very simply by modifying our
cookies and changing our user ID to user
ID number one so this was possible
because the cookies that are used are
very simple
now cookies should be more complicated
so they should actually use what's known
as session IDs or tokens these tokens
should be very complicated and not
relate to the user ID that way I
wouldn't be able to know what the user
ID even if I know that the admin has a
user ID of one I wouldn't be able to
know what token that admin is using so
they should be dynamically generated
based on each user and they should vary
from time to time so even for the same
user every time he logs in they should
get different token randomly based on
some parameters so that it's very
difficult for anybody to know what token
each user gets otherwise it'll be very
easily for people to guess what token
the add mirror or any other user has and
just injected into their browser now
using complicated tokens and session IDs
is still one vulnerable for
man-in-the-middle attacks and we see
that in plugins like Firesheep
and in programs like ferret and hamster
where I actually explained that in my
network penetration testing course where
you could gain access to any user
account as long as the people are on the
same network as you so even if the token
is really complicated you'll be able to
capture that token and then inject it
into the browser but the main idea is
the website is not vulnerable because
you can't guess it yourself here you
have to actually capture that token from
another person and then inject it
whereas in here we were able to just
know or guess that the admin has an idea
of one injected and then login as admin
in this lecture we're going to have a
look on CSRF or cross-site request
forgery these vulnerabilities allow us
to force a user to do things that they
don't want to do for example once you
log into a website let's take facebook
you'll be able to do certain things to
your profile so you can upload pictures
you can change your password you can
change your information send messages
and post stuff to your wall now CSRF
occurs when the website doesn't validate
if the user actually wants to do the
certain task so it doesn't check if the
user actually intends to change their
profile picture or to change their
password so if the website doesn't do
that we'll be able to program an HTML
page and if the user clicks it or runs
it they'll be forced to carry out a
certain task that we program it to do
for example we can get the user to
change their password without them even
knowing let's have an example on how
this happens and it will become more
clear to you so I have my dvwa here and
I'm just going to log in with my
username and password which is admin
and I'm gonna put my password
now if we go to the CRS F tab here
you'll see that it allows us to change
our our password so this is just like a
normal control panel to a normal website
and usually when you log into your
account one of the features that you can
do is you can change your password to a
different password so from here I'm
gonna set my password to two two two two
two two and I'll set it in here as well
the same password I'm gonna hit enter
and as you can see it's telling us that
the password has been changed so this is
an example of a feature that the user
can do to their account they can change
their password if the target website
which is dvwa doesn't check if the user
actually wants to do this task then we
can create a page that is similar to
this page and once the user runs that
page they'll actually change their
password without them even knowing now
there's a number of ways to analyze the
connection and analyze the information
sent between the client and the target
to make that CSRF exploit I'm going to
show you the easiest and most reliable
way and it works regardless of the type
of form whether it's post or get so with
this particular one it's actually really
easy to exploit if you just send the URL
right here to the target user and then
if they run it their password will be
changed but in more complicated ways
sometimes you don't see that sometimes
post is used so I'll show you the most
reliable way to do this kind of attack
so the first thing to do is right-click
the form that you want to hijack you
were going to inspect the element and
we're going to look to at where the form
is so we're going to look at where is
the start of the form tag and the end of
the form tag
I'm actually going to right-click it in
here inside the form
and as you can see now we have the start
of the form is in here and it ends with
with a slash form forward slash form and
you can see it right here at the end so
this is the part of the code that were
interested in - this is the part of the
code that we want to modify and send to
the target user so that when they run it
they'll actually change their password
without them knowing
so I'm going to right click this and I'm
gonna add it as HTML and I'm gonna copy
everything inside here so I'm going to
do ctrl a ctrl C and that's copied for
me
and then I'm going to go to my leaf pad
right here and I'm gonna paste it
and I'm gonna save this and we'll call
it CSRF dot html'
and I'll put this in the desktop and
click on save and that's it save now if
we let's just run this code at the start
and see what we get so I have it right
here on my desktop
and I'm just going to double click it
and as you can see you just get a page a
normal page that asks you for a new
password and a comfort to confirm the
password so you can see the form here is
actually similar to the form that we
want to hijack
now to get that page to work we need to
modify a few things now you can see here
we have a forum right here and the
action is set to a hashtag so it
actually doesn't give a website to
submit this form to so the first thing
you want to modify is you want us to
give it to the website to submit this
form to and this is going to be the same
website that we're on at the moment so
I'm gonna ctrl copy this and I'm gonna
put it in here instead of the hashtag
now sometimes you'll actually if you're
copying a form from a different website
you might actually see a name of a file
so you'll just see a file name you want
to make sure you have the full URL to
the to the form because if you just have
a file name for example if you just have
index dot PHP it won't know whether that
index dot PHP is it now it when it's on
the website because it's already stored
on that website but when we're actually
taking the file like this and storing it
on our local machine you want to make
sure you have the full URL in here so
even if you seen something instead of
the hash tag if you seen something like
index dot PHP or whatever keep that in
there but make sure you give it the full
URL that comes before that page
so this is all good now if I save this
and if we run this we'll actually be
able to change the password using this
form now the beautiful thing about these
exploits you can actually confirm that
it works for you first and then you can
send it to the target client or the
target person so if we actually reset
our password here so I'm going to set
the password to 3 3 3 3 3 3
and confirm it in here
I'm gonna do hit enter you'll see that
we get a message telling us that the
password has been changed and we can
actually now log out and login with the
new password so this is good now we have
a form that's actually not stored on the
website but using it we can actually go
to that website and change the password
so this actually confirms that the
target website is vulnerable to CSRF
because it's not validating that the
request is coming from the website
itself so it's not validating if the
user actually wants to do that now the
webpage that we made so far is not very
good because it still asks the user to
change their username and password and
these are still pics what's username and
password they want to use so now we're
going to modify our code one more time
and with this time we're actually going
to make everything invisible and we're
going to make this code to be submitted
automatically once the user browse the
page so the first thing to make
everything hidden we're going to convert
all the inputs and we're going to add to
them type equals hidden so you can see
we have an input here and I'm gonna add
an argument saying type equals hidden
I'm also going to add to this input
right here which is the input that
confirms the password so we're going to
set that to hidden as well
and we're gonna change the last input
which submits the code as you can see
here it's called change we're gonna
change that to hidden as well so the
user won't see this input either this is
the submit button
and I'm gonna remove everything written
on the page so you can see that in here
it says confirmed password so I'm going
to remove that
and we can see that in here it also asks
for the new password so I'm going to
remove this part as well
and I'm going to remove this tag
and now I have my three inputs and I
have my form so I only have the
important part of the code so we have
our first input and it's set hidden this
is the first input that the user puts
the password in and we have the second
input right here which is the confirm
password and then we have the submit
button now we're going to remove the
types from here from the input from the
password input and instead of that we're
going to add a value so we're actually
going to set the value for the new
password
and this time we're gonna set it to six
sixes so one two three one two three and
I'm gonna do the same with the confirm
with the confirm password input so we're
gonna set its value to six six six six
six six because we've already changed
the type to hidden and I misspelled type
in here so I'm gonna save this and I'll
just open this in my browser just to see
what this website looks like now now as
you can see the page is actually empty
but if we view the source you'll see
that we still have our firms
so you can see I'm just gonna zoom on
this you can see that still submitting
the form to the right place it has the
input which is set to hidden and then it
has the new password the value is set to
six sixes we also have the confirmed
password it's also set to hidden and the
value is six sixes and we have our input
the one that changes everything and this
one is set to hidden as well so all this
good now the last thing we want to do is
we want this to be executed
automatically when the user double
clicks the file so we don't want the
user to hit anything we even made our
input the submit button we made it
hidden so we want the user as soon as
they run this file they get redirected
to the page that will change their
password to do that we're gonna you need
to use a JavaScript code that will
automatically submit this form so once
the page loads it will automatically
submit this form so the first thing we
need to do we're going to need to set an
ID for this forms so that JavaScript can
identify this form so I'm gonna give it
an ID and I'm gonna set that to let's
say form one
and I'm gonna place the JavaScript code
in here and to do that we're going to
need to put it between two JavaScript
tags so we're gonna start with the
script and we need to close that tag as
well so it's a slash script
then we're going to do document to
access the current document
dot get element by ID so we can access
the form that we just created and we
called it form one
then we're going to place the idea that
we just created and we called it form
one right here so we're gonna change
that to here so we can say form one
so the code so far will access the
current document and it's going to look
for an element that has the ID of number
one then we're going to tell it what we
want to do with that element with that
form and we're going to want it to
submit so we're going to say dot submit
so the code is very simple we just added
an ID to the current form we called it
form one and then we added a JavaScript
code starting with a script and ending
with a forward slash script and we said
the document and we want you to get the
element by ID we want you to get form
one and we want you to submit it
now once the user double clicks this
file the file will be executed
automatically without the user having to
do anything so let's see this in action
I'm gonna come now I'm gonna close this
and I'm going to close this one as well
and I'm just going to double click my
new file right here
and as you can see automatically I got a
new page and this page is telling me
that the password have been changed so
the user didn't click anything the user
didn't put any password and the page was
executed from a place that's not on the
same web server so it was executed from
the local machine but still it submitted
the information the website accepted the
information and the website changed my
password to the new password so my
password now the admin password have
been changed to 666 666 so if I log out
and try to login I'm gonna put my
username as admin and the password to
666 666 hit enter and you'll see that I
logged in with the new password instead
of my original password now it's all up
to you and how smart you you are with
her with tricking the targets with how
to get them to run your file so now it's
all down to social engineering how
you're going to send it what you're
gonna pretend that the file is going to
be one way is to send the file as it is
as HTML the other way is just to host
the file on an HTML web hosting so you
can upload it to any web host think
there's a lot of free ones and then you
can just send the URL of the file
instead of even getting the target
person to download the file which will
be much less suspicious in the previous
lecture we've seen how to create a HTML
web page that exploits a CSRF
vulnerability that will automatically
submit a form and we see in how we can
exploit it to get the target person to
change their password without them even
knowing so as soon as they double-click
the file this form will be automatically
submitted changing the password to the
password that we want one problem with
that is it's usually a bit difficult to
get people to run files even though it's
just the HTML file and you can use smart
social engineering skills to get them to
run it it's still a bit difficult and it
will be much easier if we can just send
them a link which will change their
password as soon as they click on that
link and this is actually really easy
because the file we created is a HTML
file so all we have to do is just upload
that file to a web hosting company now
there is a lot of free web hosting
online you can just upload that file
there you can use a URL shortening
service as well to make the URL shorter
and less suspicious and then you can
send it to the target person so I'm
going to show you how to do that but I'm
actually going to do it on my local
machine because everything for me here
is local but it works on the external
websites exactly the same you'll just
have to upload the HTML page on a web
hosting doesn't matter if it's real free
or paid but there is a lot of free ones
so I'm
use my local Apache server right here
and then we're going to browse it from
our target Windows machine and we'll see
how that is going to be executed and how
the password is going to be changed so
before I do anything I'm actually just
going to reopen the file and I'm gonna
set the password to seven seven seven
seven seven seven instead of 666 so we
just know that the password has been
changed to the new one and I'll change
it in here as well and now I'm going to
copy this to my local web server and
Kali first of all I'm going to copy the
file to my document root so the file is
stored in desktop now so I'm going to do
CP desktop CSRF to var www HTML and now
I'm gonna start my Apache so I'm gonna
do service I Pat you to start
now everything's working so I'm just
going to get my IP address
and my IP address is 10 2014 to 13 so
I'm just going to go to a Windows
machine
now in this machine I'm actually
pretending to be a target user so first
of all I have to be logged in to my
account so I'm just going to go to dvwa
so I'm going to log in with my username
which is admin and I'm going to log in
with my old password which is or - my
current password the one that we reset
it previously which is six sixes
now as you can see I can login normally
now I'm gonna go I'm gonna close this
now we're gonna browse to the page that
contains the forest CSRF exploit so
we're gonna pretend that I was social
engineered and someone gave me a URL to
click so at the moment we're actually
not gonna download any file we're not
gonna double-click any file all we're
gonna do is literally just browse a URL
and once we do that our password is
going to be changed so the page as I
said you can host it on free hosting
there's a lot of free hosting online at
the moment I have it hosted on my Kali
machine and its IP is 10 2014 to 13
and then I'm gonna put my the name of
the page which you are set to CSRF dot
HTML
I'm gonna hit enter
and as you can see it's telling me that
the password has been changed and all I
did again all I did is just run a URL so
it's all done to you to how you're gonna
convince your target to execute that URL
so if I just log out now and log in
again you see that my password now I
have to login with admin and I'm
actually going to type the password here
so it's seven seven seven seven seven
seven and I'm gonna copy all of this and
paste it down there just so that you
actually know that the password has been
changed to seven seven seven seven
so the vulnerable URL was 10 2014 to
thirteen forward slash CSRF anybody who
would run this URL and logged into the
target website they'll be forced to
change their password to 7 7 7 7 7 7
now you can use this method as I said
with any website that is vulnerable to a
CSRF and it'll force the user to do any
action you want all you have to do is
just adopt the same method to the form
so whether it's a payment form whether
it's a signup form whether it's a submit
article form whether it's a form that
sends a message to a friend you can just
change the website right click inspect
the form element copy the form code hide
everything did you have a script code
that submits the website or that submits
the form automatically then you can send
the web the HTML website as it is to the
target person or you can upload it to a
known online hosting and then just send
the hosting URL to the target person
once they browse that URL the web page
will be automatically executed forcing
them to change their password or to do
the action that you want them to do
now that we know how to discover and
exploit CSRF vulnerabilities let's talk
about how to protect websites from them
so if we just go back now to dvwa and
set the security to high you'll see that
they have a very simple way to protect
against it but this way actually works
and what they do is they ask you for the
current password so even if we get this
form and we do all the forging and all
the stuff that we were doing it then
send it to the target person we can't
actually hide this and get it to
automatically submit because we don't
know the current password so it asks for
the current password and then it allows
you to add a new password so this is a
really good solution for this case only
though because what if the form actually
doesn't change a password what if we're
just going to send messages pretending
to be that person
what if we're gonna post things to that
person's wall what if we're gonna post
things into that person's blog so CSRF
can be exploited to do many things as I
said in previous videos and this method
will only protect against change in the
password
you can't really ask the person for
their password every time that they want
to post something or to do something
with their profile
now newer versions of dvwa that don't
come with Metasploit able to actually
have a more secure option that will
implement the method that I'm going to
talk to you about it now it's actually
called impossible instead of hi but it
doesn't matter it's not exploitable
anyway so we don't really need to have
it installed
so let's talk about how you could
actually prevent these vulnerabilities
from happen without asking the user to
re-enter information or to early enter
the password if you think of it the way
we were able to exploit this is we were
able to just copy the form that the
website uses and send it to the target
person and get that person to run it or
automatically run on the target person's
computer
so once the request is sent to the
server the server wasn't doing any type
of validation to ensure that the user
actually wants to change their password
so the best way to prevent CSRF is to
make sure that the user is submitting
data through a page that was served to
him by the web application and not by
anyone else a good way of implementing
that is to use synchronizing tokens now
I know the name sounds complicated but
the idea is very simple
basically we want to generate a unique
and random token at the server side then
when the page is loaded when the form is
loaded we're going to embed this already
generated token into that page as a
hidden form then when the form is
submitted we're going to make sure that
the form was submitted with that token
that we sent to that specific user so
basically we give the user a token and
then we wait for him to submit the form
with the token that we gave him that way
the token that the hacker gets will only
work for him so even if he generates a
page and send it to the target and the
target runs the page the form will be
submitted while it will be refused by
the server because it did not give that
token to that user it gave that token to
the hacker say for example we have this
user here and he requests facebook.com/
password with PHP it goes to the server
the server is gonna generate a response
for that request so it's going to return
the HTML page that represents password
dot PHP in that page it's going to
include a unique token so when the page
is loaded at the client-side it's gonna
already have the form that the user is
looking for plus a unique token that was
generated by the server then when the
user submits whatever they want to
submit the server will only accept the
form and will all will own the response
to what the user is asking if the user
returns the same token now of this
implemented properly it can still be
exploited so if the token was
predictable or if the same token was
being used then the hacker can discover
what the token is embedded in the HTML
code and send it to the user so the
token needs to have certain
characteristics so that it's secure and
basically the main thing is that you
want to keep in mind is that the token
needs to be unpredictable and it cannot
be reused regardless of the way you're
going to implement this these are the
two main things that you want to keep in
mind because if it was predictable then
the hacker will be able to create their
own tokens and then embed them in the
code and run the attack same if the
token can be reused
then the hacker can just use their token
or someone else's token to target their
target so in order to make the token
unpredictable and make it so that it
can't be used then the token needs to be
a large value so that the hacker can't
do a brute-force attack and discover
what the token is the token needs to be
random so that the hacker will not be
able to create their own tokens and it
needs to be unique for each user because
if users get the same token or similar
tokens then they can pass them around
and then the token that works for the
hacker will work for other people so
that will defy the whole point you can
also increase the security of the token
by including other factors in the token
generation algorithm so you can include
for example the date and time then
combine it with a secure random
generator and then encrypt that all of
this is obviously happening at the
server side so the hacker will not be
able to know what algorithm you're using
because the code will be executed at the
server side you don't necessarily have
to do this using a secure large and
unique random number is enough but if
you want to increase the security then
you can just add other factors and
encrypt the token before you send it to
the user this is actually implemented in
Matilda so let me just show it to you in
action
so I'm just going to go to Matilda in
here
and I'm gonna go on our Stan CSRF and
add to blog
so this allows you to add a blog post so
it doesn't allow you to change your
password or anything it actually allows
anonymous people to add posts as well so
you can't really ask people for a
password I'm actually gonna go and
toggle security so that it's the highest
because it's at zero right now
so now it's the most secure and if we
right-click this and go on is inspect
element
going to scroll up
and as you can see we have the form here
and we have a hidden input with a very
long value and this is the token so this
has already been generated by the server
and the server will refuse any request
that we sent to it unless it has this
specific token and if I use this form
and send it to someone else
then again the e requests that they will
send will be refused because they'll get
a different token this token was
generated for me and for me only so let
me show you if I actually refresh right
now
I'm gonna get a different token and
again if i refresh again I'll get a
different token and if I modify this so
let's say instead of the capital I at
the end I'm going to put a small I and
if I submit this now
it's given me an error but let me not
change this so again I got a different
token now and if I just submitted the
way it is
it's going to work and now we have a
blog entry called
test so that's it it's actually very
very simple I didn't want to go into too
much details about how to create random
token and all that because that's going
to be specific depending on the
programming language that's the web
application is programmed in but I was I
just wanted to show you the concept or
the idea of how to secure web web
applications against this type of
vulnerability the whole idea is you want
to make sure that the user submits their
data through a page that you serve to
them and not by a page that was given to
them by any other person so in order to
do that we generate a token at the
server side this token needs to be long
random and unique send that token with
the page with the form and embed it as a
hidden form and then whenever a user
submits the response make sure that they
submit the same token that was given to
them
now let's assume you tried all the
attacks that we learned so far on your
target website you tried all of them on
all the websites on the same server and
none of these websites is vulnerable you
went and you try to hack into that
server using the applications installed
on the server using the server-side
attacks so you use the port scanner and
you determine the programs and the open
ports and you try to hack into the
server based on these services and again
you still didn't find any way to get in
and let's assume that you try to attack
the data center itself which contains
all the servers and again you still
didn't manage to gain access and you try
to hack the users that use the websites
all the websites on the same server as
your target website so you try to hack
the users you try to hack the admins you
try to hack the support people using
social engineering attacks and all these
attacks and again you still didn't
manage to gain your access then I'd
usually go down to brute-force attacks
now a lot of people would actually try
brute-force attacks before that but I
just don't really like brute force
attacks not because they're not useful
or because they're not effective they're
actually very effective but it's just
that I don't really feel satisfaction
when I gain access to a system using a
brute force attack
so what we mean by brute force attacks
is we're gonna go to the login screen
most websites have login screen to allow
the administer login and we're gonna try
to determine all possible combinations
of the password
so there is two flavors of brute force
attacks or I should say guessing attacks
there is brute force attacks and
dictionary attacks so brute force
attacks would try to cover all possible
combinations of the password for example
on your phone the pin can only be made
out of numbers so you can actually cover
all possibilities very easily because
the pin only has four digits and there
is only nine possibilities when this
comes to passwords especially when it
comes to web logins you have lowercase
characters uppercase characters symbols
and digits which makes the brute-force
attack really unfeasible because it will
take years to cover all possibilities
this leads us to the dictionary attack
where you actually cover all
possibilities in a list so you're going
to have a list of passwords these can be
made of common passwords or based on the
research that you did on your target in
the dictionary attack you'll only cover
the passwords that exist in the word
list so unlike the brute-force attack
it's not guaranteed because with the
brute force we're going to cover all
possible combinations in the dictionary
attack we're only going to cover the
passwords that are in our word list or
in the dictionary
so in the next few lectures we're gonna
see how you can create your own
dictionary and we're gonna see how we
can launch a brute-force attack to gain
access to a system without exploiting
any vulnerabilities all we're gonna do
is just try a large number of passwords
until one of them works and this is the
reason why I don't really like brute
force because there is no smart way
you're not actually exploiting anything
you literally just guessing the password
until it works keep in mind though just
because I don't really like it doesn't
mean that it's not effective I've
actually in many cases I spent days
trying to break into a system and at the
end one of the times I still remember
the password was 1 2 3 4 5 6 ABC which
yield probably if you had a word list of
common passwords you'll probably gain
access to that system within an hour or
two
in this lecture we're going to learn how
to create a word list this is a really
handy skill to have under your belt if
you want to be a penetration tester
because you're going to face a lot of
scenarios where a wordless attack can
become very handy so you can actually go
ahead and look for ready word lists on
the internet and there is some really
really good ones and you should probably
use a lot of them because some of them
just have the common passwords but in
many cases you might actually need to
create your own word list
so in this lecture we're going to learn
how you create your own word list using
a tool called crunch so using the tool
is very simple all you have to do is
just put the name of the tool and then
you specify the minimum number of
characters for the passwords to be
generated then we're going to specify
the maximum number of characters for the
password then you specify the characters
that you want to generate passwords from
for example you can put all lowercase
characters all uppercase you can put
numbers digits or you can just specify a
small a smaller number to make the word
list smaller you can also use the option
T which is an optional to give a pattern
so for example let's say that you are
looking at the person while they were
type in their password and you seen that
the password will start when it with an
A so you can tell crunch that the
password will start with an A and then
give me all possible combination of
passwords that start with an A and after
that we use the minus o option to
specify the file name where the
passwords are going to be stored so we
have a small little example here that
will generate a list of passwords that
contain that start from six characters
to eight characters and contain these
characters right here so it's going to
create combinations of 1 2 3 ABC and the
dollar sign and it's going to store it
in a file called
that should be a no I'll fix that in a
file called word list and these
passwords are going to start with an A
and end with the B and it will generate
passwords based on all possible
combinations between the a and the B so
all of the generated passwords will
always start with a and end with beef
so let's have an example of the tool now
the tool actually have a lot of options
other than what we've seen so far so if
you just type in man crunch
you'll see all the options that you can
set and you'll see detailed description
about all of these options so it's
actually really really good you can go
ahead and spend some time to get
familiar with the tool now I'm going to
show you the example and based on the
example you'll be able to run all of
these commands but if you want to run or
create some advanced word lists then I
highly recommend that you go over this
one of the really cool options that I
want to highlight is the minus P option
the minus P option tells crunch to
generate passwords that don't have
repeating characters for example when
you specify all lowercase characters you
specify ABCD it will start by generating
passwords made of   and then a a
then a bbbbb and all of that so when you
do this crunch will actually ignore
these type of passwords and it's a loan
to create passwords that don't have any
repeating characters and that'll reduce
the size of the word list from the
number of characters to the power of the
length to the number of characters
factorial
if you scroll down you'll actually see
more examples of commands and the type
of word lists that will be created so
again you can have a look on these and
get yourself for me familiar with once
you're done looking at the man you can
just press Q and you'll be out of it and
we're gonna run our command here so
we're gonna use crunch
and again I want to generate passwords
of minimum of six characters and maximum
of eight characters and I want them to
contain combinations of ABC and let's
say the digits 1 2 now in here you can
actually keep listing things you can
list characters you can list uppercase
characters or even symbols if you wanted
to once you're done with listing the
characters we're going to specify the
file to save it to and we're gonna save
it in a file called test
but txt so the command is very simple
its scrunch minimum length of the
password the maximum length of the
password followed by the characters that
we want to use to generate passwords
from and then Oh to the file that the
passwords are going to be stored in you
can hit enter
and as you can see now is telling us
that it generated four hundred and forty
eight thousand passwords approximately
and they're all stored in a file called
tester txt now the size of the file is
four megabytes and now I can open this
file by doing cat
test
dot txt and as you can see now we can
see all the passwords that have been
generated I'm going to control C out of
it because it's a huge file and as you
can see it actually contains all
possible combinations of ABC one two
I also want to show you an example of
using the minus T option so I'm gonna
set this to only six to six so it's only
six characters and we're going to use
the minus T option which is the pattern
option and I'm gonna tell it that I want
the password to always start with an A
and then I want you to fill all possible
combinations of characters between the a
and the B so I want passwords that start
with an A and end with the beep and in
the middle at the add sign you can fill
all possible combinations of ABC one two
can hit enter
as you can see now the number of
passwords is much less it's only 625
passwords because I've narrowed down the
possibilities of passwords again if I do
cat
test dot txt you'll see that I have all
the passwords right here
so this is it tool is really useful can
be used in many scenarios I highly
recommend that you spend some time with
it and also have have a look on some of
the existing word lists out there on the
Internet
now that we have a word list ready
whether you downloaded it from the
internet or if you created it by
yourself now we can go ahead and proceed
to gain an access to our target website
using a word list attack
so we're gonna use a tool called Hydra
and Hydra can be used to brute force any
type of service really I can't think of
any service that you can't brute force
so it's a really handy tool to know how
to use we're gonna do our example on a
web login but you can use it to gain
access to SSH FTP router is anything
that ask you for a username and a
password really
so to use the tool the first thing we're
going to do is we're gonna type in Hydra
and we got ports - help to see how to
use it
now as you can see there is a lot of
options for the tool but don't be
overwhelmed with that they're already
pretty simple to use so if you go up you
can see that the main syntax of using
the tool is you the first thing you have
to do is put in the name of the tool so
we're gonna put Hydra
and then we're gonna put the service
that we want to attack so you can see
that they have examples here of you
attacking an FTP service people attack
in an IMAP service and other type of
services so in our example we are
interested in to gaining access to our
login here to to this page and we're
gonna assume that we don't know I use
the name and a password and we're gonna
try to log in to the admin without
knowing their password
so our target service is going to be
this one
so the first thing you want to use is
its IP so the IP is 10 2014 to 12 so
we're going to put it after the name of
the tool
then looking at the syntax here you can
see that we have to specify a login and
a password so let's have a look on the
minus L and the minus P options in here
and you can see that you can use a small
L to specify one username or I capital L
to specify a list of usernames so in our
example we're only trying to gain access
to the admin so we're not going to use a
list of usernames we're only going to
try to gain access to the admin password
so what we're going to do is we're gonna
do - L small and then we're going to
tell it that the username is admin
and then the next thing we need to
specify is the password or a password
list so similar to the other option you
can use a small P to give one password
or you can use a capital P to specify a
file or a word list or a dictionary of
passwords so I'm actually going to
modify the password file that we created
in the previous video
I'm just gonna open it in my text editor
so this one it's right here it's called
tester txt and I'm just gonna add the
password for the admin I know the
password for the admin is called admin
pass and I'll just add it somewhere in
the middle here
okay so I'm going to save it and quit it
and now our word our word list contains
the password so we're gonna do minus P
capital P and then we're gonna give it
where the password list is stored and
it's stored in root test dot txt
so everything is good until now and
there is only one more thing to do
we still haven't specified what type of
service that we are attacking so we gave
it the IP we gave it the username and we
gave it the list of passwords to try but
Hydra still doesn't know what type of
service that we're going to attack and
that is the most important option and
the options that you need to pay the
most attention to because this is where
it gets a bit tricky and this is where
things can go wrong
so before I start talking about that I'm
actually going to copy our commands so
far and I'm just gonna paste it in our
notepad
so all we have to do now is tell Hydra
what type of service and how to use the
service to brute force the username and
password for me and you can see here in
the help it's telling us that these are
all the type of the supported services
so as I said I can't actually think of a
service that's not supported so you can
have a look on all of these and try them
what we're interested in too is the HTTP
and you can see that there's going to be
a - and it's going to be either get or
post dependent on our target and after
that it's also going to be a forum
because it's sent through HTML and I'll
tell you why it's going to be like this
now let's go down
so I'm going to right-click in here and
I'm going to go to inspect element
and I'm gonna click I'm gonna look for
something called form and you can see
that there is a form there has to be a
form in the HTML pages and look for the
method I'm going to zoom this in for you
and note that and here it says that the
method is going to be post and that way
we know that it's a post and if you look
at the URL here you'll see that the URL
is a HTTP it's not a HTTP so therefore
our module that we're going to use here
or the service is going to be HTTP POST
form so it's right here you can see it
all the type of services like I said
so it's HTTP followed by a - followed by
post and followed by form and to see how
we can use this and to see an example of
how you can use this service I'm
actually going to control see this and
I'm gonna say Hydra - you and I'm gonna
give it the name of the forum or the
name of the service that I want to use
which is going to be HTTP
post
form
as you can see now again it's giving you
a long description about how you can use
this service and at the bottom it gives
you examples and the examples are
amazing the examples are really good
because you can just copy and paste them
and adapt them to your target
so the format of this service is you
give it the location where the brute
force where you want to brute force
deform from your gonna give it the user
parameter so whether it's you well it's
whatever this parameter is called and
then you're gonna give me the password
parameter and then you're gonna give it
the incorrect message so when there's a
failed login what happens to the web
page so I'm going to copy this the way
it is
and we're gonna modify to adapt to our
target so the first thing you we want to
put is the page that the login happens
from which is this page
so we're going to put all of this
instead of login dot PHP here
so that's all good now the next thing
that we need to modify is the user and
the pass so these are the names of the
parameters that are sent to the web
application and we don't know what these
are called and for this we're gonna use
burp suit now I'm not going to show you
how to configure this because we've done
that before so I'm just gonna turn my
Interceptor on and I'm gonna log in with
our wrong username and password so I
just want to see what gets sent to the
target web application so I'm just gonna
log in with the username admin and just
any password so I'm just gonna put
random characters hit enter
and I'm gonna go on the headers
and this is what's being sent so you can
see that the username parameter is just
called username so I'm going to copy
that and put it here instead of user
and we can also see the password
parameter again it's called password
instead of pass
and you can see that we also have an
extra parameter here which is an login
submit' button equals login so you need
to add that as well and in your case if
you had other things that's being sent
you need to add them as well to your
request so we're going to add that after
the pass here
exactly the way it is we're not going to
modify anything so it's just going to be
and login.php submit button equals login
the last thing that we need to modify is
this part and this part is the way that
Hydra is going to know whether the login
is successful or unsuccessful so the way
this is going to work is you either give
it a capital f equals to the
unsuccessful so it equals to the failed
attempts or you can give it a capital S
and you tell it what happens when a
successful login happens so in my case
I'm gonna give it a capital F to tell it
what happens when a failed login happens
and I'm just going to turn off the
Interceptor now and we can see that we
have a failed login and in a failed
login you can either use this or in my
experimentation it was easier to just
use this so if you just use the message
right here that says not logged in so
we're going to say F equals
so this is the most part the most
important part and the most tricky part
I'd say of the whole attack so I'm going
to go over it again
we can see that the whole request is
separated by three columns
the start of it is the location where we
want where the page that we're going to
brute force is so we took that from here
the second part is the parameters that
we're going to be dealing with and that
we're going to be sending to the server
and we took that from burp suit
and the third part is the way that
pursuit is going to know whether this
login is successful or in successful and
we gave it capital F to tell it that
this is what happens when the password
is wrong and we told it that you'll see
a message called not logged in
so we're going to combine this with the
command that we already had so the
command that we already had was Hydra
the IP
followed by the username that we're
going to use which is admin followed by
the password list and we're going to put
all of this after it and that's it
that's our command done I'm going to
copy this
paste it in here and execute
and I forgot to tell it the type of the
service that we're going to be attacking
so I only gave it the I only gave it
what it should send but I didn't tell it
what type of service were going attack
so like I said before it's going to be
HTTP POST form so it's the same service
that we were inquiring about when we
used you option so again copy this
paste it here
her enter
now you can use the minus V option so
that Hydra would actually display every
request it sends to the server I didn't
use that right now so all you see is
literally just a blank screen but we're
going to wait for it until it finds the
password for us Hydra also supports
pause and resume so if you just control
C out of this the next time you're on it
all you have to do is just put in minus
R and that'll actually allow you to
continue from where we were you left the
last time
and as you can see now we managed to
find a valid username and password and
you can see that the username is admin
and the password is admin pass and this
works against any web login so it
literally this web login doesn't read
doesn't need to have any SQL injections
or JavaScript or XSS or anything so now
I can login with the username admin
and password admin pass
and as you can see now I'm logged in as
admin