in this lecture and the next few
lectures were going to be talking about
a popular type of vulnerability is
called SQL injections before we start
talking about how this occurs and how to
exploit it let's first learn what SQL is
now for if you're given a pen test on a
certain website chances are this website
is a little bit bigger than smaller
websites so it'll it's probably using a
database most websites other than very
simple websites use databases and the
databases are used to store data so
there are either store usernames
passwords news articles blog posts
pictures anything that anything that
happens on the website literally is
stored on a database and the web
application queries the database and
then displays the data to you or to the
users on screen when the users do
something it's later update delete or
modify the data that exists in the
database this interaction between the
web application and the database happens
using a language called SQL so let me
show you what I mean by a database this
is just an example I'm not hacking
anything I'm literally just going to log
in to the database that is installed on
our Metasploit able machine and then
we're just gonna see what's being stored
on it so I'm not doing any hacking there
is nothing here the nothing fancy just
logging into MySQL and then I'm putting
in the username is root and my the MIT
exploitable doesn't use a password for
the root which is really bad but
obviously it's a vulnerable system so
I'm just going to log in and I'm not
hacking anything I'm not doing any SQL
injections this is just the terminal for
MySQL which the web application would
use to interact with the database so I'm
just trying to show you what I mean by
databases and what's saved in there so
the first thing I'm going to do is I'm
just going to type in show databases
and that will show us the databases that
exist on our target server and we can
see that we have the information schema
this is a default database that holds
default information information about
all the other databases so this one gets
gets installed by default when you
install MySQL the rest have been
installed for each web application so we
can see we have one for Tiki Wicki we
have one for OS 10 and that's for this
one metal day
you
we also have one called mysql' we have
one called Metasploit and one for dvwa
which is the one that we've been using
the web application so you can see for
each web application we actually have a
database and this database holds the
information that is used by that web
application let me show you what's in
there so I'm gonna use the OS 10
database
so this is the one that is again this is
the one for Mattel day for this web
application and we can see the table so
each database has a table tables and in
the tables there is information so I'm
going to say
tables to see the tables that we have
and you can see we have a table for
accounts so you can assume that this
table has information about the
usernames passwords and information
about the users we have a table for
blogs so probably has the blog inputs
the posts and the comments in there you
can see captured data a credit cards so
there's a table that contains credit
cards now this is huge for shopping
websites they actually would have credit
cards table and the information for the
credit cards would be start there
basically the database will store
everything ever all the data that is
used on the website because they don't
get stored on files it's not efficient
so let's have a look on the accounts and
if I just say select so this is exactly
how the web application would be
retrieving information from the database
it will be selecting stuff updating or
deleting
so I'm doing a select statement here
again this is not hacking I'm not doing
anything just selecting stuff and I'm
gonna select star which means everything
from accounts
ah strophe and as we can see we can get
we have the account ID the username the
password and then the signature for the
person and if that person is an admin
now these columns depend on the table so
it's actually the person who designs the
database designs the tables the columns
as well and then the data gets inserted
by the web application so you can see
that we have a user called admin and
their password is admin pass we can see
we have a user called Adrian and their
password is some password so this is
just to show you what databases look
like and just to get a feel on it
because in the future videos we're gonna
try to exploit these databases and have
access similar to this so this I just
logged in with the username and a
password now usually you wouldn't have
access like this only the web admin
would have that access in the future
videos we're gonna try to run some
attacks in order to gain access similar
to this so that we'll have full control
over the database so that we can read
stuff and see if we can write or modify
things so I just want to highlight why
as SQL injections are so important and
so dangerous the reason behind that is
they are found you can find them
everywhere any play a lot of places a
lot of big websites have these kind of
exploits and like things like Yahoo
Google had them it's they're very hard
to protect against and it's very easy to
make a mistake to make these exploits
available for exploitation the other
reason that they're very dangerous is
that they give you access to the
database in many scenarios if you find
an SQL injection you really don't need
to upload a PHP shell or get a reverse
connection there is really no point of
uploads itself and then increasing the
danger of being caught because if you
have access to the database as we seen
here you pretty much have everything you
need you have usernames passwords you
can login with normal username and a
password that's a normal user or you can
if you're looking for a sensitive data
we can see that we've had access to
credit cards you pretty much can do and
thing you want so there is really no
point of trying to further exploit the
system if you found an SQL injection
bingo like that's that's all you need
really in many scenarios we actually use
a PHP shell to gain access to the
database and see if we can read it like
say for example if you managed to upload
a PHP shell on the server on this server
the Metasploit able but then you
couldn't access the database you there
isn't much that you can see you can't
see credit cards you can't see user name
and passwords
you really can't ya you have control
over the server but you can't read stuff
so sometimes when you upload the PHP
shell the next step is I need to gain
access to the database another thing is
the they can be used to do many things
so if you find if you manage to find an
SQL injection in a website that is not
your targets so it's not the one that
you're targeting but it's in the same
server then you can use it to read files
outside the WWE root so similar to file
inclusion vulnerabilities you can use it
you can use the admin the username and
password for the admin and see if you
can upload stuff usually the admin can
upload a lot of things instead of just
images and then you can upload a PHP
shell or a backdoor from there and then
from there navigate to your target
computer or to the target website sorry
or you can actually in some cases you
can use it to upload a PHP shell you can
use this an SQL injection to upload a
PHP shell so basically SQL injections
can be used as file inclusion
vulnerabilities they can be used as file
upload vulnerabilities and also they'll
give you access to the whole database
that's why they are very very dangerous
and very useful if you manage to find
one
now to try and discover SQL injections
you need to browse through your target
and try to break each page so whenever
you see a text box or a parameter on
this form for example page dot PHP then
something is equal to something try to
inject stuff here so try to use a single
quote try to use an ant or the order by
statement to break the page and make it
look different so I'm going to show you
here an example and I'm gonna go into
the login page first right here and it's
asking me to login now I've actually
registered with my own name so you can
just go in here and your register I have
a user name called Zeta and a password
with one two three four five six so
first let's just I'm gonna log in just
to show you so why is there name is Zaid
and my password is one two three four
five six and now I'm logged in as a then
my signature was is just nothing really
just like as a test
so I'm going to log out and we're back
at the login page
right here we have the page so you can
try to inject in that but we'll get into
that later so at the moment we're having
an example of injecting into text boxes
so you can try to inject into the name
and into the password so I'm gonna put
my name as 8 and I'm gonna put a single
quote so I'm putting this sign into my
password so let's see if we can break it
and as you can see now there is an error
being displayed to us and it doesn't
look like a normal error it looks like
it's a database error and usually you'd
be very lucky if you get an error like
this now usually the error won't be as
informative as this sometimes you'll
just see that the page is not acting as
it's expected as you expected sometimes
it'll just be a page that is not does
not look as it should for example if
it's a news page maybe it'll have the
article missing or if it's a blog it'll
have one of the posts missing or
different kind of posts so you need to
keep an eye on what's changing in this
example we were actually getting a
really nice error some of us which file
it has and it's telling us that there's
an error in this statement and the error
near the quotation mark that we added
and it also tells us the statement
that's been executed this is really good
for learning because now we can see
what's the statement that the system is
trying to run and the system is trying
to do a select star so I was trying to
select everything from accounts where
the username is equal to Z and the
password is equal to a single quote and
note that the the system their web
application is already adding quotes
around the name so when I said they had
added Zeta between two quotes and added
the single quote that I added between
another two quotes so that's why we have
three quotes right here so from this
weekend it's like 70 percent of the
target website has an SQL injection
we're still not sure if it can execute
what we wanted to do so can I actually
inject code and get it to be executed
let's see if we can do that so the user
name is going to be saved again
and what I'm gonna do with the password
I'm going to put my password so I'm
gonna put one two three four five six
and then I'm closing it so I'll tell you
why I'm closing it because the current
statement in the system is is select
start from
to Zaid
is equal to and it's gonna open a single
quote by itself
so let's call this s password so we're
treating this as a variable and it takes
in whatever I put in here whatever I'm
gonna put in this box and it's gonna
insert it
instead of the S password which is a
variable so I'm just I'm giving you an
idea so you need to be able to imagine
this happening so it's taking whatever I
put in there and it's gonna put it
between two single quotes and it's gonna
be inserted in there and executed on the
system so what I'm doing is I'm gonna
put one two three four five six and I'm
gonna add the quote myself so what I'm
gonna do right now
the code is gonna be like this so it's
gonna select this and password is equal
to that and I have two quotes right now
okay and then what I'm going to do is
I'm gonna say and
1 is equal to 1 so 1 is equal to 1 and
I'm just trying to see if it's going to
execute what I wanted to do so my
statement right now is it's gonna be
select star from accounts where username
is equal to Z and password is equal to 1
2 3 4 5 6 and now I'm gonna be inserting
this myself and 1 is equal to 1 one
problem that the system is gonna
complain about is that we have an extra
quote here because I'm going to be
inserting this myself in the text box so
it's going to be complaining about this
it's gonna say this this is an open code
and never be has been closed so what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna add a comment and
when you add a comment basically
everything that comes in after the
comment will not be executed I'm gonna
use the hash as the comment so anything
that comes in after the hash the system
is gonna ignore so I'm gonna eject now
is going to be this + 1 is equal to 1
and this so as I said usually what you
have here
you have slush doll or password or
depending on what the programmer called
it but we're just imagining this and I'm
going to be inserting this inside so
when you do that and you insert it
inside this is what the code is going to
look like so it's gonna look like the
right username the right password and
one is equal to one which is true and
then it's not gonna it's gonna ignore
this quote right here so if we paste
this we should be able to log in it
should allow me to log in and perfect we
were able to login and user name is
eight so far we haven't done anything
but this kind of shows us that is it
running our code let's try a different
thing now let's try to add a false
statement so we did we did one equal one
and that was correct and it executed
what we wanted let's try one equals two
and this is false so I have the right
password and I have the right username
but I either do and one is equal to two
and this should be wrong because it's
false one is not equal to two and I'm
using an aunt so everything has to be
true
so it should give me an error even
though I'm gonna play the right username
and I'm gonna put the right password so
I'm puttin 1 2 3 4 5 6 and 1 is equal to
2 so it's gonna be like oh this is wrong
and as you can see it's given me an
authentication error bad username or
password even though I'm given the right
you the right password and the right
username so this confirms that this
website is actually injecting anything
we want
ind password so we can use the password
field to inject SQL code and it's always
gonna be on this form so we're gonna put
a password and you're going to put your
code here so I'm just going to put it in
capital code here because we're gonna
put any password close the quote and
then put the code that we want to
execute on the system right here and
it's going to be executed on the target
system
okay so now we know that we can put any
code we want in here and it's going to
be executed on the system so let's have
another look now in the statement so the
statement says select star from accounts
where username is equal to the username
that we put here and password is equal
to the password that we put there let's
see if we can use that to log in without
using a password without even now in the
password and I'm going to be doing that
with the admin so the admin or God the
username is going to be admin
and I don't know what the password is
for the admin so what I'm going to do
I'm just gonna put anything
so nothing really any any random
password and in decode what I should run
here we were doing and 1 is equal to 1
and or stuff so what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna do or instead of ant and I'm gonna
say 1 is equal to 1 so what's our code
is going to be once I run this once I
inject this this is going to go in here
like we were doing before so our code is
going to look like this so it's going to
be select star from accounts who our
username is equal to admin and password
is equal to AAA now this is wrong or 1
is equal to 1 which is right so anytime
you have an or if the or condition is
right everything is right that's the way
our statement works so select star from
a counter username is equal to admin ok
username is equal to admin and password
is equal to ie a that's wrong or 1 is
equal to 1 okay I'll accept that and
then it's actually going to execute it
and let us login to the admin without
even knowing the password for the admin
so let's try to inject this now
and as you can see I was able to login
as admin and monkey is the signature for
the admin now bypassing logins can be
done in so many ways depending on the
code that's written on the page and
dependent on the way you want to do it
and how you're imagining the code and a
lot of the cases when you put the single
quote here you won't see this message
sometimes you do see it which makes your
job so much easier if you don't then you
kind of need to guess what it looks like
so I'm going to show you another example
of bypassing and instead of injecting
the code like this the admin parameter
is actually injectable as well as you
seen when I put the single quote the
admin parameter is injectable exactly
the same way as the password so we can
inject code in the username as well and
what I'm going to do now so let's have a
look on this and I'm just going to reset
it to the way it would usually look like
so you'd have
and the username and the password are
the fields that you whatever you put in
here are going to be substituted in the
username and the password so let's try
to inject something in the username and
what I'm going to say is I'm gonna say
username is equal to admin and then I'm
gonna close the quote myself and then
I'm gonna add a comment so my statement
when I run this statement it's going to
look like this and I'm actually just
gonna copy it here and when I inject
when I put this code in here and then my
name it's going to inject that in there
so this is what the code is gonna look
like it's gonna select star from
accounts where username is equal to
admin I close the quote myself here
using this right there and then I'm
adding a comment so basically all of
this is not even gonna be executed so
the code is gonna be this it's gonna be
select star from accounts where username
is equal to admin and it's gonna let me
log in without even entering anything in
the password so let's do this I'm gonna
put my username as admin and I close the
quote and add a comment and then you can
put any password you want really I'm
just gonna put number one and I'm gonna
login and as you can see I managed to
login as admin so again in this is black
box testing so you don't really see the
code in many cases you want to be
playing around with it and see how it
works with you but the main thing is you
want to test if the ice QL injection
exists and you'd use that using the
method we showed you in the previous
video so try single quote try the aunt
statement try F true on statement so
once you go to one and then a false on
statement so one is equal to zero or two
is equal to zero and if they work as
expected then your target has an SQL
injection and you can start playing
around with
let's see if we can do the same when we
increase the security level so as you
can see here the security level is set
to zero so it's the least secure right
now so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
click on toggle security and that will
increase our security level to number
one which will basically make the
website more secure so that the attacks
will not work the same way that it used
to be so again we're still at the same
page or at the login page and we're
gonna try to bypass the login using the
exact same way that we did in the
previous lecture so I'm gonna put admin
followed by a comment and then we can
put any password we want right here
I'm gonna hit enter and as you can see
we get an error message saying that some
illegal characters got detected
so let's try the other exploited exploit
that we found which was we put the
username normally and then we put the
password as anything we close the quote
and we use or one is equal to one which
is correct so again I'm gonna just keep
the username as admin normally and then
I'll paste this exploit right here
hit enter and again we get the same
error saying that some illegal
characters got detected now this
filtering could be happening at the
client-side or could be happening at the
server-side what I mean is if it's
happening on the at the client-side it's
the stuff is being filtered before it
gets sent to the server the other way at
the server-side means these characters
are being detected and filtered at the
server-side after they get sent to the
server now if it's happening on the
client side then it's very easy to
bypass using burp proxy
burp can also help us identify whether
this is happening at our site at the
client side or if it's happening at the
server side
so as usual we're going to go to the
proxy and I'm gonna set up the proxy
settings again for Firefox just like we
did with in previous videos so that it
uses burp so we're gonna go on advanced
settings and we're gonna use manual
configuration and set to port 8080 so
that's all good now everything we do as
we seen before should go through burp so
if we go to home you'll see that packets
are coming here if we forward them they
go to the server so again when I go to
the login the packets come here we
forward them from burp and then they go
here now watch this now I'm gonna try to
put in the username as admin and I'm
gonna put this exploitation right here
and when I paste it notice that the
packet will not be sent so I'm gonna
click on login and see that nothing was
sent to burp so this request was stopped
before it even reaches the internet
before it even reached the server so it
was stopped by some code loaded on the
browser or in this web page itself so if
the filtering is happening on the client
side on our side
before it even goes to the website and
still not that some dangerous characters
were detected so let's go back to our
diagram here so we have our HTML website
with client-side filtering so when it
detects special characters the
client-side code will remove these
characters or it will display an error
so what we're doing is we're gonna write
a username and a password without any
special dangerous characters we're just
gonna write it normally send the request
which will bypass the filtering that's
happening on the same page on the client
side it's going to go to BER proxy then
right here when it comes to here we're
gonna modify it and add our dangerous
special characters that will allow us to
bypass authentication or run code on the
target website once we do that we're
gonna send it to the server the server
will execute and send it to us so using
burp we're going to be able to bypass
client-side filter
so let's go back and see how we're gonna
do this
so we're gonna use a normal user name as
admin and I'm gonna I'm gonna put a
random password so it doesn't have to be
right I'm just gonna put a aaaa
doesn't really matter and I'm gonna
click on login now this is a valid
request so it will be sent to the
internet it's once we stopped by the
filter which works on the client-side so
I'm gonna click on login and as you can
see the request has came here and the
request and here we can see that the
user name is area is admin and the
password is a aaaa so what we're gonna
do now we're going to actually modify
the user name and the password values
right here instead of modifying them at
the web browser because at this stage
we've bypassed the filter so the
username and the password were valid at
the client-side they got sent to the
internet before they got into the
Internet we captured them by birth proxy
and we're going to modify this password
exactly the same way that we wrote our
exploitation in the previous video so
this is going to be
AAA or 1 is equal to 1 and then we close
it with the comment here
okay so I'm just gonna repeat this so
the filtering is happening at the client
side by JavaScript code which gets
executed on the page itself so the
request is being stopped before it even
reaches the server when we run burp we
actually have used a good username and
password that are not considered to be
dangerous they pass through the filter
and before they go to the internet we
have birth proxy working which captured
that we're gonna modify it in here
because we've already bypassed the
filter and when I click on forward
you'll see that I managed to login as
the admin
okay so let's increase the security
level to the high security which is
fairly secure so sometimes it can be
bypassed sometimes it can't be bypassed
and in this lecture I'm actually just
gonna highlight something for you
so let's try and use the same exploit
that we were using before so if we copy
this and we're gonna turn on our
Interceptor and just I'm gonna put a
normal user name and password for this
now
and then we're gonna intercept it here
and modify it like we did in the
previous video
okay now we're going to forward it
and as you can see it's telling us there
is a bad user name and password so
obviously this is more secure and
actually in this particular case in this
page this it is not injectable anymore
with this security level it doesn't
implement the best security practice but
for this specific case it's secure
enough so I'm gonna have a we're gonna
have a quick look at it
but it's not the best way to secure your
website so we're gonna talk about the
security part at the end of the section
and we're gonna talk about the best way
to secure yourself against SQL
injections but for now this is what
noteworthy to see because it's a quick
implementation and if you know what
you're doing you can fix your problem
quickly say for example if you had a
problem and you don't have enough time
to change the implementation to the most
secure way which we're gonna talk about
later then you can just do it this way
quickly just so that you can you are
secure enough until you can implement it
and change the code to be more secure so
what they're doing in this page now this
doesn't always secure you 100% again but
it is in this particular case it is
secure so this is the code for the login
and right here we have the case one
which is the arrogant or the security
level one and here we have the code for
security level five so you can compare
the two codes the main the main
difference is this select statement so
I'm going to delete everything and I'm
just gonna keep these two select
statements so we can compare them
okay so you can see here in the not very
secure statement we it select star from
accounts where the username is dollar
username and the password is dollar
password so basically whatever your
input in the textbox is for the username
and the password is being directly used
in here now there was client-side filter
ation and we were able to bypass that
using the proxy so whatever we input in
the proxy was being substituted in here
so we could have we could modify the
code by setting the username is equal to
or one is equal to one and then we added
a comment so basically what happened in
this statement right here instead of the
username that was substituted so
whatever the whatever we put in here was
substituted and this value was injected
so this was changed to a quotation and
then or one equals one comment and all
of this was basically ignored everything
that comes after this was ignored which
made our statement work so as you can
see here we closed the quote that was
already inserted and then we added r1 is
equal to one which is a true statement
we put the username is admin actually
that's what we did
so
this would be admin as well here so
basically it's selecting anything where
username is equal to admin and it
doesn't care about the password which
was giving us access to the admin
account now we could have injected also
in the password saying r1 is equal to 1
again it gives us a true statement and
this was getting executed
in this particular case here in the
secure one what they're doing is they're
doing a function which is called the
real escape string and what this does it
basically removes characters such as the
newline character the break character
and the quotation so a single quote or a
double code
so at scans it scans the input that we
put right here and it removes any
quotations that we put so if we put the
single coat right here or when we were
put in the double code it was removing
it so when it removes it it basically
renders everything inside it as a
strength
another problem with this now I said
this is only secured in this particular
case because they're also adding a
quotation right here before and after
the input so if there was no quotation
then our inject injection what we need
to inject will not need to have contain
a quotation and that way we'll be able
to bypass this function but because
they're using they're actually
hard-coded in quotations in here
right here and right there at the end at
the start and at the end of the input
and then they're also escaping any
quotations of the input contains any
quotations they're removing it then
whatever we inject whatever text you put
in there will be considered as as a
string so it will only be considered as
normal text and it will never be
considered as code therefore it will
never be executed on the server only in
this case so let's just have examples so
we have our admin here so this is the
injection that we're always using so if
we're gonna put this
so this is our username here so
basically what's happening is this is
coming up to the code and then the code
is gonna scan this and it will notice
that there is a quotation right here and
because there's a quotation it's going
to remove it this particular function
will remove it so after the function is
applied the this will disappear and also
the function will disappear so this is
what's going to look like to the code to
the computer this is what's gonna see
and it will basically just see a normal
string which is contained within two
quotes as well so we need to remove the
dots here
and notice that they already hard-coded
these two quotes so because of that our
injection will never work now if they
didn't include these codes if they
didn't hard-code them here if they
didn't exist
even though they use the function this
injection will work
but because they use the quotes whatever
that's gonna come in inside the codes
will be considered as strengths and
because they're checking that our input
should not contain quotes on the server
side then whatever we put will be
stripped out from the quotes and it will
never be considered as code again this
isn't the best way to secure your
website I'll explain the best way at the
last lecture of this section but this is
a good way to temporarily secure your
website if you didn't have time to
implement the proper procedure
okay now I'd like to show you an SQL
injection and in a different file in a
different page and I'll show you a few
different things that you can do to
exploit the vulnerability so the first
thing I'm going to go to the login page
which is here user info so the first
time we went to the login page from
there this time we went to the user info
page so this this page will show you the
information about the user provided you
give the user name and password so I'm
gonna do Zaid and I'm gonna put my
password one two three four five six and
it'll show my details username and
password and my signature is aaaa so the
statement that's been executed here is
similar to what was being executed when
you log in so it's selecting star from
accounts where username is what you put
in the user field and password is what
you put in the password field so what
we're going to do now is we're going to
see a different way of exploiting this
kind of vulnerability in the previous
video we were doing it using a post text
textbox so whatever you put in the
textbox was being posted using a post
method to the web application now these
vulnerabilities can't exist and to get
and what I mean by get is when you do I
get when something is sent as yet you
will see it here in the URL so if you
look at the URL here you see it's being
sent as the user names ade and password
one two three four five six so let me
just copy this URL here and we'll start
playing with it from the URL and instead
of doing it on the web page I just want
to show you a different example cuz in
many places there might not even be text
boxes for example it could be something
like in news and news dot PHP so we can
see here for example in this example
it's index dot PHP and in your
pentesting you might see something like
a news dot PHP and for example ID is
equal to two and then you can try to
inject stuff in there so we're having an
example here where we're going to be
injecting things
into the username field which is this
field and we're going to be injecting
stuff in here so anytime when you're
doing your pen test anytime you see
parameters like this you should try to
inject them anytime you see something
dot PHP and then you have a parameter
equals something then always try to
inject stuff in there and see if it
works for you
so we also seen a way of discovering the
injection and that was using the
quotation mark and using the aunt so we
do a false and and a true aunt and one
is equal to 1 and then and 1 is equal to
2 and if the server is executed what we
want then we're gonna know that there's
an SQL injection I'm going to show you
another way of discovering these
exploits and it's using the order by as
the name suggests the order by statement
is used to order the results that we get
on the screen based on a specific column
so our injection is going to be like
this so I'm gonna do or thereby
one so this if if the objection exists
this should work because in each select
statement there should be at least one
column is being selected therefore when
we say order by one we're saying I want
to order the results based on the first
column therefore this should always be
acceptable by the database and return a
true or something that we expect we also
need to add the commented here and
execute this code so it's exactly like
before so when we're doing this
basically
this is our URL and what's going to
happen on the database so this is the
code that's been executed on the
database it's going to look like this
so it's going to be select star from I
can swear username is equal to Zeta and
note how this is closing the quote and
we're gonna do an order by one and there
should be this code here for the end and
this this comment comment will tell the
SQL interpreter that to ignore anything
that comes in after it so all this is
going to be ignored
I'm helping this
so you can actually paste this injection
for Zaid order by one into the name
right here and that's gonna work but
again I just want to show you a
different way of doing it by injecting
it through the browser another thing
that I want you to note is when you're
injecting stuff into the browser the
browser the code should be encoded so
for example this sign usually when you
put it on the URL it should be written
as percentage 23 spaces for example get
converted to percentage 20 and
percentage 23 is the comment that we're
using so I'm gonna copy that and replace
my common sign with it
now you can Google HTTP encoder and
you'll see online there's online tools
that will just compare this for you for
me now I know that the hash tag can be
converted to percentage 23 so that's why
I'm using it there and I'm gonna hit
enter and as you can see now we're
seeing something that's acceptable
nothing wrong and then it's shown me the
information about Zaid one two three
four five six and show me the signature
so it is ignoring the password so the
injection worked and it's ordering by
one so it's not showing me anything
wrong let's try to make this number one
a very large number so I'm put in 10,000
or 100,000 now so what we're saying
right now is I want you to order the
results that will be returned by the
current select statement based on column
100,000 now chances are there aren't
100,000 columns used in this select
statement and therefore this should
return an error so when I execute this
you'll see that there is an error and
the error is in the order close and
stillness that there is an unknown
column for a hundred thousand and this
is great because now we know that the
database is executed in what we want so
when we told it to order the results
based on the first column it showed us
results so it followed what we told it
and then when we told it to order the
results based on a column that does not
exist it gave us an error so it's
obviously vulnerable to SQL injections
okay so now let's try and determine how
many columns are being selected into
this page so how much information are
being selected and displayed on this
page so to do that we're going to use
the order by command so we did order by
one and that returned something that was
acceptable and order by a hundred
thousand gave us an error so let's try
and do order by ten and we still get an
error so I'm gonna do an order by five
and that works so let's try to do an
order by six and that gives an error so
by doing this we know that there is five
columns or are being selected from a
certain table and it's the accounts
table and displayed on this page so
let's try and build our own Select
statement and get it to be executed on
the target computer so let's come here
and try to build it there so at the
moment the statement is select star from
accounts where your username is equal
to Zaid and we're doing an order by one
so let's see if we can fix that and get
it to select something that we like
so the normal way to select stuff is
using this format but because we are
trying to do multiple selects and we're
trying to do it from the URL we're gonna
have to use a union first and then we're
gonna say select
then we need to imagine what's happening
on this application so in this web
application we know that there are five
records being selected so there are five
columns that are being selected so we're
doing one two three four five and we got
that from the order by command so let's
run this and see what happens
you
and I spelled Union wrong
and as you can see now the selection was
right and we got the first selection so
the first selection that this line does
has been done and then it did the Union
so it's it combined that selection with
another selection and it shows us
something else and as you can see here
we're only seeing two three and four and
what that means is whatever value you
put in number two or three or four
whatever you want to select if you put
it in there it's going to be displayed
in this page in this particular location
and you can see that here you have
results for two so whatever you put in
two will also be shown in here
so let's try to see our database so
instead of number two I'm gonna say
database
and instead of number three I'm gonna
say user name or user and instead of
number four I'm gonna do version and
this will select the current database
the current the user privileges that we
have and the version of the database so
let's see if this gets executed and then
we'll talk about it
okay cool so the username is showing up
as OS 10 and that's that was number two
so that is the database that we're
looking for so the database is our stem
the current user that were logged in as
is root at localhost so were the root
user and in the signature this so these
stuff actually don't mean anything we're
only concerned about this and what we
injected and we injected the version and
we can see this is the version of MySQL
so it's five point zero point five one
so at the moment we know that our
database that were connected to is a
wasp then usually in most real-life
scenarios each database is assigned to a
certain user so usually you're only able
to select stuff tables columns data that
is located in this current database at
the moment who are logged in as root so
this web application has been connected
to the database as root so therefore we
can actually access other databases but
this doesn't really happen in real life
scenarios usually each user has their
own path their own database so when they
connect a web application to a database
they connected to one database and
therefore you won't be able to access
other databases so we're going to
consider that we're going to assume that
we only have access to our stem which is
our current database for this current
website and that the user name is root
at localhost and the next videos we'll
see how we can further exploit this and
do more powerful select statements okay
so now we now our target database is
called OS 10 let's try and discover the
tables that exist in that database so
this is our select statement it's a
union select one and we have these
things so I'm going to leave this or
change these to no because I'd only want
to select one thing now and I'm gonna
set this to null as well and any number
two we're going to select
table name
from now we're going to select this from
a database called information schema now
I said this in the first video of SQL
that information schema is a default
database created by MySQL and it
contains information about all other
databases so what we're doing now we're
selecting the table name from
information
schema dot
you put the table
so basically we're selecting a table
called tables from a database called
information schema and the column that
were selecting is called table name so a
selection table name from the database
that's called information schema from
the table tables let's execute this and
see if we can get all the tables that
exist in our Stan database
so we can see we got 237 records and you
can see all the tables that we have so
these are all the tables that we have
access to so again I said we are logged
in as root therefore we can actually see
tables from other web applications such
as the Tiki Wicki but in real life
scenarios you'll only see tables related
to your current database which is
Matilda
so I'm going to do is I'm going to use a
where clause and I'm gonna say where the
table
schema is equal to hours
10 so our Stan was what we got when we
executed when we selected the database
so we got our stem which is our current
database that Matilda is working on so
we were using the same statement we're
selecting the table name from
information schema tables where the
table schema is a wasp 10 so I'm going
to copy that
and execute here
and as you can see now we have so many
so much less tables and we only have the
ones that were interested in so we have
the accounts the blog's capture data
credit cards hit log and the pen test
tools now if you remember in the first
or the second video in the SQL injection
videos we I showed you what's the
content of the OWASA table was and it
was these tables of the OS database now
let's see if we can select and get and
have a look on all the accounts that
exist within this table so let's see if
we can query the database and read the
information stored in the accounts table
to do that we're going to first need to
know the column names of the columns
that exist within this table because if
you look at the way we're using our
statement we're doing Union select
column name from a table so we still
don't know what columns exist in
accounts now we can try and guess that
there is a username and a password but
sometimes they could be different names
so I'm going to show you how you can
select the columns for a certain table
the command is going to be very similar
to the tables command
and the only difference is instead of
table name we're gonna say column name
and instead of selecting it from the
information schema tables we're going to
select it from information schema those
columns
and we're gonna say where the table name
is equal to accounts because we're
interested in to the accounts table if
you wanted to get columns for another
table then you just substitute this with
the table or with the column that with
the table that you want so our command
is going to be Union select one column
name from the information schema dot
columns where the table name is the
table that we're interested in which is
the accounts and this should show us all
the columns that exist within the
accounts table so let's run this command
you
and perfect same columns that we seen
before and it's CID username/password
my signature and is admin
now let's take this one step further and
select the usernames and passwords from
the account table so again the the
command is going to be very similar to
what we're running at the moment we're
going to be selecting and we're gonna
select username and I'm gonna select the
password for number two
and for number three you were going to
select the is admin
now remember I can't select anything
instead of number one and number five
because they don't they're not they're
never displayed for me on screen the
only thing that I see he was number two
three and four which were displayed here
two three and four so therefore I'm only
substituting values for two three and
four and we're gonna select that from
accounts
and we're not gonna need the word so I'm
gonna delete the word so very simple
statement we're selecting username
password is admin from the accounts and
this should return all the usernames and
passwords that exist within the current
table that exist in the accounts table
you
and I have an extra quote here that I'm
going to delete
and as you can see we got all the
usernames and passwords we have the
admin and their password is admin pass
we have other users and we have their
passwords and it's also telling us
whether they are admins or not this is
very useful because in most websites
when you log in as admin you have so
much more privileges than a normal
person and then you'd be able to upload
PHP shelves or back doors viruses
whatever you want to do really
and then further exploit the system so
at the moment I can actually log in with
a username admin
and the password admin cars and it's
gonna accept that because it's correct
so no matter how complicated the
password was were just gonna be able to
read it because we're reading it
straight from the database
in this lecture I'd like to show you an
example of how to discover and exploit
and a blind SQL injection now a blind
SQL injection is one that doesn't
display any errors to you so we've seen
in our previous examples let me just go
to SQL injection and if I just put a
single quote here
you see that it actually displays on air
for me which tells me that this page is
vulnerable and I can exploit this page
with an SQL injection and I blind SQL
injection however it will not show any
errors for us so right here in the blind
SQL if I put a quote and execute it you
see that it's not gonna show me any
errors at all this doesn't mean that the
web page isn't vulnerable it just means
that the website might not be displaying
errors and this page might have a blind
SQL injection and real life scenarios I
always approach the pages and try to
discover it exploits in them as blind
SQL injection so I never actually look
for errors and I never depend on just
input in a single quote the way I test
for the existence of SQL injections is
that I try to inject a true and a false
statement and then see if the bay if the
page behaves according to the statements
that I'm given so if I give it a true
statement it should give me a valid page
if I give a false statement it will give
me an invalid page what I mean by an
invalid page is a page that doesn't look
like what I expect so it doesn't have to
show on error this will come more clear
now in the example I'm just going to put
one now to see a valid page so literally
I'm just putting a normal user ID and we
can see that it's given us a valid page
so it's given us the first name and the
surname and this is what the default
what a valid page look like in this web
application so the first thing I'm going
to try to do is I'm going to try to give
it a true statement a statement that
returns a true and this is going to be
and
one is equal to one so this is obviously
true and when I inject this if the page
is vulnerable it should still show me
the valid page
so I'm gonna inject it here and one is
equal to one I forgot to put my comment
here I just gonna put the comment
percentage 23 and now as you can see the
page is showing me a valid page again
showing the first name and the surname
so it's executing what I'm telling it I
told it 1 is equal to 1 1 is equal to 1
is a true statement it's not going to
affect the execution of the page now
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna try to
inject a false statement so I'm gonna
try to break the page even though I'm
giving 1 which is a valid ID so my false
statement is going to be + 1 is equal to
0 so that's going to be false
and I'm gonna go in and inject it now
and as you can see the page doesn't show
the default valid page even though I'm
given number one so you don't see any
errors like we see in with the normal
SQL injections but you can see that the
page isn't valid it's not discipline
what it should display even though we're
giving the ID equals one so when we give
a true statement it's it's given a valid
page when we give a false statement it's
given an invalid page we can also verify
this using the order by so I'm gonna put
one and then I'm gonna ask it to order
by one so order by only one column which
basically is a true statement it's
always true so
this is going to be my true statement
and I'm going to execute it here
and as you can see now it's displaying
the valid page that we've seen with the
Antoine's equal to one so we can also
change this to a false statement to give
us an invalid page and we're going to
ask it to order by a very large number
so I'm just going to put one zero zero
zero zero
so this is going to be my fourth
statement and if the page is injectable
then it should show me an invalid page
or a page that I don't really expect
and again we see a page that we don't
expect which means that this website is
vulnerable even though it doesn't
actually show us any error pages about
the SQL
now that we are sure that this page is
vulnerable we can actually exploit this
vulnerability exactly the same way that
we exploit normal SQL injections so I
can just do Union select one two and as
you can see I can display stuff in one
and two and I'm gonna select table name
from
information schema tables
actually misspelled schema here
so the exploitation part is exactly the
same whether it's a blind or normal SQL
injection the only difference is the way
you discover it and I recommend that you
always approach your websites and try to
discover blind SQL injections so never
rely on only using a quote always try to
use the and one is equal to 1 1 is equal
to 0 and also use the order by to try
and discover this type of
vulnerabilities because if you rely on
the quotes you'll be missing a lot of
blind SQL injections that are just as
useful as normal SQL injections
now we've seen how to extract data using
an SQL injection you can increase the
security to level 1 but you can exploit
this exactly the same way that you
exploited level 0 and if you increase
the security level to 5 it's actually
very secure it's going to be as secure
as the web login that we see in in the
login bypass so it uses the MySQL escape
real escape string combined with single
quotes and double quotes so it's pretty
much an injectable what I want to show
you in this lecture is a trickier SQL
injection and I'm going to show you that
in dvwa instead of Mattel day so I'm
going to close this and we're here at
dvwa and I'm just gonna go down to the
security level and I'll make sure that
that's set to low now I'm actually
interested in to the medium level but
I'm going to show you how to exploit
this in the low level just so that the
information flows properly so I'm going
to go to the SQL injection and I'm just
gonna put number 1 in here
now as you can see we get a valid valid
page giving us the first name and the
surname of the user ID that we given now
I can inject this in the post and the
box or here in the URL and I'm going to
inject it into the URL and I'm going to
put a single quote here and as you can
see we get an error telling us that
there's an error in this statement which
means that there is an SQL injection
here we can verify it
by adding a true statement saying + 1 is
equal to 1 which should give me I
actually forgot to add my comment here
so I just gonna add the comment so the
true statement should actually give me a
valid web page like we see here so it's
given us the first name and the second
name properly now if I say 1 is equal to
0 which is an invalid should give me an
invalid page and here we go we're
getting an invalid page width which
means that the ID parameter here is
injectable and the page is doing what
we're asking to do we can also verify
this using the order by 1 and then we
can say order by a very large number and
should give us an invalid page and here
we go that's that means that this
webpage is definitely vulnerable to SQL
injections now I'm going to try to
determine the number of columns I'm
going to put 3 and this is telling us on
an unknown column let's try to put 2
and the page is valid so that means we
have two columns in this page so we can
build our Union select statement now you
can see I'm actually actually have them
built already and I am able to select
everything but I just want to show it to
you again
so I'm just going to build the Union
Select statement with you actually here
so I'm just gonna say Union select one
two
and we can see that we can display stuff
in one and into so I'm gonna select the
database in one
and we can see that my database name is
dvwa so I can go ahead and try to select
all the tables using my information
scheme at our tables so the query is
going to be very similar to the query we
run here with dvwa
and the only difference is that the
table schema is going to be set to DV WI
instead of Austin
so I'm gonna paste that here and as you
can see I can get my tables which is
guestbook and users
now we can go ahead and try to select
and find the columns for each of these
tables using the same statement that we
used in the previous lecture I'm not
going to run it now because I've already
run it and if the if the table statement
runs and the columns tables gonna run
so I've already found that there is a
user username and password column in the
users table and I'm just gonna run this
statement to select the username and the
password just to show you what's going
to happen
and as you can see we can select the
usernames and the passwords for all the
users that we have in the users table
now I'm actually not interested into any
of this because we've done all of that
before with Matilda what I want to show
you is how to run these statements with
the medium security level so I just
wanted to do this to show you how it
works on the low and now I'm going to go
ahead and change the security level to
medium
and now can go to SQL injection okay and
we're going to try to discover it the
same way that we did before so I'm gonna
put number one first to see a valid page
and this is about its page now I'm going
to try to put a single quote after the
one and as you can see now we're getting
an error but this error is different
it's actually complaining about the
existence of the single quote so let's
try to put an ant we're gonna put and
one is equal to one like we did before
and close it with our comment
and this should actually show us valid
page but as you can see now it's not
showing us a valid page it's actually
still giving us an invalid page even
though we said one is equal to one which
it shouldn't affect our statement or our
query so let's try to put the HTTP code
for the quote instead of using a quote
so I'm gonna put percentage 27 and see
if that will bypass any security maybe
they're using and again I'm still
getting the same error same problem
still complaining about the quote so
let's try and play more with this now as
I said exploiting SQL injections can
vary from website to website depending
on the way it's implemented so there is
a lot of trial and error in this so
let's try and remove the quote and see
if that will actually fix our problem
and make it injectable
great now this is given us a valid phage
now let's try to change it and say 1 is
equal to 2 and see what happens and yep
this has given us an invalid page so the
website is responding to what we're
saying the only difference now is that
we're not using the quote who were just
injecting it straight away after the ID
after the number
okay so let's go ahead and try to build
our union select so I'm going to type in
Union select one two
and yep that looks like we can write
stuff in number one and in number two so
let's try to select table name
from information schema tables like we
always do just to get all the tables
that we need
and here we go we're getting all the
tables just like we got them before