all the JavaScript injections that we've
done so far we used to inject them like
this that we used to actually inject
them in the HTML code and we used to
have to put the script alert exercise
script or put anything in here depending
on the cheat sheet that I shared with
you
now I've said earlier with SQL
injections the payload or the exploit
can vary from website to website depend
on on the way the website is programmed
or the page is programmed and XSS is the
same so you always you need to approach
the websites and think about it in a
general idea and try to exploit it
depending on the page itself and don't
always just copy and paste the exploits
or the payloads and to do that I'm just
going to show you another example today
and we're gonna do it in Matilda and
we're gonna go to the injection and I'm
going to go to the JavaScript injection
and to the password generator
now what this page does basically you
click on the generate and it just
generates a random password so there are
a lot of websites on the internet that
just do that for you
looking at this at the website itself us
that this password is for anonymous and
looking at the URL we can see that it's
given a username and the username is
given in the URL in the username
parameter and it's given as anonymous so
we can just change that name to any name
we want so for example if we change that
to Zaid
it's telling us that this password is
being generated for Zaid and if we
generate it's going to be generated now
note that whatever you write in here is
being displayed here and this should
instantly tell you that maybe this could
be vulnerable to an XSS vulnerability
because whatever you're typing is being
displayed so let's try and use the same
exploit that we always use and try to
get it injected in the code and the page
now as you can see the exploit didn't
run so we didn't actually get a pop-up
box telling us that there is an XSS in
the page but something went wrong as you
can see now some of the code is being
thrown at the page
this shouldn't be shown in here you seen
in the basic case when you just put a
normal name you don't actually see this
code so that means something is
happening something is going wrong in
this page so let's try to inspect the
element
and I'm just going to make this bigger
now what I want to focus on is the part
of the code that's being thrown in here
on the screen so I'm going to
right-click it and again inspect the
element just so that we get navigated
automatically to where that is in the
code and I'm going to go down
and you can see that this part of the
code is being broken we usually add the
script tags ourselves when we when we
try to inject like you like you see in
here but what's happening in this page
it's automatically trying to put what we
input our user input inside to script
tags this one and this one so first of
all we know that we don't need these
because they're already there
also note that our code is being
injected here so this is my code script
alert XSS this is what I entered for the
username and you can see that this is
being placed inside a single quotation
so in order to exit this quotation mark
I'm gonna add one in my exploit okay so
that's gonna close this for me and then
I remove the script so it's going to
become alert XSS which looks really good
and then we have the end of the script
here
so let's have a look again on the code
so you have the first line it's same
document that get don't get element by
ID now I actually don't know how to
program in JavaScript so you don't need
to be a JavaScript programmer but you
just need to have like a general idea on
how this is going to work so we can see
that this is the first line of the code
and it's saying this inner HTML is equal
to this password is and whatever we
input between the two quotes so what we
did we close this and then the next line
is going to become our alert XSS so in
JavaScript to end one line you actually
have to add a semicolon so we're going
to close and add the semicolon in here
and our exploit
and what this will does it will close
the quote here and it will execute this
as another line as the next line and
I'll add the semicolon here at the end
just in case and I'm gonna copy this I'm
gonna inject it and I'll show you what
the code looks like after we injected it
will become even clearer so I'm going to
inject it here
now as you can see there is nothing but
if we click on the generate now looks
like there is something still wrong so
we still didn't really inject it
properly let's have a look on the code
again so again right click inspect
element
and we're going to go down to where the
code for the user right here
and this is what our code looks like now
so it's saying try document again get
element by ID and this is telling this
is equal to this password is four we
close that so that's really good we
added a semicolon perfect and then we
said alert XSS very good semicolon
perfect but then we have this single
quote and this semicolon and these are
coming from the original code so these
are used to close this statement
originally so they're actually being
hard-coded or inserted by the code in
the web page so all we have to do is do
like what we used to do with the SQL
injections and just add a comment here
to comment everything that comes after
this so that it doesn't break our code
so again I'm going to copy this
paste it in here
and as you can see now our code runs and
we managed to run javascript code on the
target website now you can share this
link with any JavaScript code you want
and that will be executed on the target
person on the person that runs this link
so you can go ahead and look up any
types of codes for JavaScript or you can
use beef like I'm going to show you in
the next lectures
so the take-home message from this
lecture is the way you exploit
vulnerability is not only job not only
XSS or SQL injections any vulnerability
is going to vary from website to website
so you have to always think about it
maybe you look at the source code look
at how the data is being transmitted
between the websites and try to adapt
your exploit to that specific webpage
okay now let's have a look on a start
exercise example now start exercise is
very similar to a reflected one it
allows you to inject JavaScript code
into the browser the code is executed on
the people that visit the page the only
difference is with this with the
reflected you have to send the URL to
your target so the target had to
actually click on a URL for the exploit
to run or for the code to run and the
start XSS the code will actually be
stored into the database or into the
page so every time any person runs that
page they will see your code and your
code will be executed so you won't need
to interact with any users or send them
anything therefore this could be much
more dangerous than reflected XSS so
let's have a look on this now I'm I
clicked on the XSS stored here on the
left and you have this page and this
page just allows you to add a message to
the system so I'm going to put my name
as ade we're just going to do a normal
test first and we're gonna put a message
body for example and then I'm gonna sign
the guestbook and you can see that Zaid
added a message called message body so
if you would go to here into another
machine so this is a different machine
into a different place and if we go into
XSS store we can see that there is two
entries so the entries are being loaded
from the database and that they contain
the entries in that database so if we
managed to inject code in here then any
person who runs this page the code will
run on it without even having to send
that person anything so let's try to
inject stuff here so let's put my name
as a and I'm gonna try to put my code in
here so I'm going to try to inject into
the message I'm gonna put it as script
I'm gonna use the exact same test code
that we used in the previous video just
a message saying XSS again very basic
code but it serves for the purposes of
this video and we're going to say alert
xs/s and i'm gonna try to sign the
guestbook and as you can see now I got
the XSS here but the real magic happens
when a normal person so let's just go
home first and let's assume this is just
a normal website and people just are
coming and browsing it and once they're
gonna go to the guestbook javascript
code will be executed on their system
from that website so the code is coming
from that website and it's going to be
executed on every person that visits
this page again we're just showing a
proof of concept here in future videos
will show how to further exploit this
kind of vulnerability
okay now let's go ahead and have a look
on the medium security level and see if
we can exploit this third cross-site
scripting vulnerability now before you
do anything because this page will
automatically contain code that will run
every time the page works you can go to
set up and reset database this will
basically reset reset everything and
when you go back to this third XSS
nothing is going to work because all the
records will be deleted now I'm also
going to go to the security and I'm
gonna set the security to medium submit
it and go back to our store now in the
medium security level the message text
box is not injectable and we'll talk
about that in the next video
for now I'm Olga I'm going to try to
inject in the name so first of all we're
gonna try our code that we always use so
it's just not the normal code with
capitalizing some of the letters
and you can see that we can't really
write much in the name because it's
limited to ten characters this can be
easily bypassed by right click inspect
element to see the code and then we're
gonna change the max length here to 100
then we can put 100 characters in here
so again I'm just gonna paste my code
and I'm gonna put anything here sign the
guestbook
now as you can see we managed to bypass
it just like that what I also want to
show you is how to run one of these
discovery payloads without using a quote
so some websites would use filtering on
single quotes or even double quotes and
they'd be removing them so what you
could do is you can try to use this
function shrank from chart code and
instead of putting a string in here
exactly the same way that we did with
SQL when we used hex in this case we're
gonna convert the string or the text to
char code so you can do that from Google
if you just Google char code calculator
and I'm gonna put this link in the
description we're gonna use the first
one and I'm just gonna put I'm gonna
call this one
XS 2 so we don't get a mixed up with the
first one
and I'm gonna get its code so this is
its code
we're gonna copy that and we're gonna
substitute it in here and then we're
gonna run this so this is gonna be
normal and I'm also just I made one of
the peas small in here and I made one of
the she's small just so that we can
bypass any filters if they're checking
for a script and then we're using
instead of putting the text in here
between these two brackets we're
actually saying string.fromcharcode so
basically decode this char code and then
run it as a string so let's go ahead and
run this and see if it works now we're
gonna add it again we're gonna have to
change the name to 100 in here
and then I'm gonna inject it put
anything in here sign it this is the
first XSS the first entry and as you can
see our second entry is being executed
and we managed to execute this second
entry without putting any quotes in the
payload
so far we've seen how to discover XSS
vulnerabilities we had a look on
reflected stored and Dom based and we
also seen a few ways on how to bypass
security and how to edit our payload so
that it works on different situations we
still haven't seen any good way of
exploiting these vulnerabilities though
all we did was run a code saying alert
XSS or alert any message that we want so
in this lecture and the next few
lectures we're actually going to see how
we can exploit machines that visit these
vulnerable web pages and we're gonna do
that using a framework called leaf
framework what p f-- does it allows us
to run a large number of commands to
hook browsers and to hook a browser to B
if a javascript code has to be executed
on that browser and because beef uses
JavaScript it's very easy for us to
inject that code into XSS vulnerable web
pages and that code will be executed
every time a person runs that page so
all this is going to become more clear
let us just run beef and get it set up
and get someone hooked to it in this
video and in the next videos we'll be
running our commands and you'll see it
will become much more clear on how to
use beef so I'm gonna go to my Kali
Linux and the first thing I'm gonna do
is just run beef here from its icon
give it some time and it will start it
will automatically start the browser for
you
so now to login the username is beef
password disbelief as well
so this is the main screen of beef you
can see here on the left you have online
browsers and this will basically list
all the browsers that are hooked to be
at the moment you can see that we have
nothing hooked to it and on the right
once you click on a hooked browser
you'll be able to run your commands in
here again in this lecture and future
lectures we'll be running some commands
so it will become more clear to you so
right now let's go ahead and try to go
and get some people hooked to beef now
there's a number of methods that you can
do to hook people to be if what we're
interested in is how to hook them
through XSS vulnerabilities so the main
thing that we're going to be using is
the code given to us by beef itself so
it's actually telling us what code to
use and as you can see now this is a
JavaScript code similar to the alert
code that we were using so the first
thing I'm going to do is copy this
and we're gonna paste that in a leaf pad
just so that I can show you how to
modify it
so all you have to do is just inject
this code into the vulnerable pages one
thing that you have to modify is that
you have to add your IP in here so to
get your own IP all you have to do is
run if config so I'm just going to get a
terminal and I'm going to run if config
and as you can see now my IP is this so
it's 10 2014 208
and that's it now the code is ready to
be executed so I'm gonna close this and
let's go to one of our vulnerable web
pages that we were using before so we
used to go and let's go to DB WI
so first let's just go and set the
security to low we seen how to bypass
the security so I don't want to make
this video too complicated
and let's have a look on an example on a
reflected one so if we go on a reflected
XSS and remember when we used to put the
name here and the name gets displayed so
we used to just put our script instead
of the name and that gets executed as
well so instead of doing an alert we're
actually gonna run it like this so this
was our code
and we used to do this to get our code
to be executed so let's just have an
example on it as well
and as you can see you get access s so
we're using exactly the same code or
exactly the same concept except were
changing the payload instead of saying
in alert we're actually going to put
this code we're going to ask for this
code to be executed so we're just going
to modify that and put it in here
so this URL is ready now and you can
send it to any person and once they
execute this URL they will be hooked to
beef and then you'll be able to run all
the commands that beef allow you to run
now you can go ahead and change this URL
using a URL shortening service just to
make it look less suspicious so let's
just have an example I'm actually going
to execute this code and mice in the
same browser which I shouldn't I should
probably do it on a different machine
but we'll do it just here just to show
you the proof of concept so we run this
here and if we go to beef now
now I've actually mistyped with my IP
here it's it's 10 2014 not 10 14 twenty
so this is my IP I'm just gonna fix that
paste it here
and if we go to beef you'll see that we
have an online browser and a person is
hooked now we can click on this and run
the commands but I'm going to leave that
for a different lecture
now I want to show you an example of
this third because in my opinion this
third is much more dangerous in this
case the reason being is you don't have
to send anything the code will actually
be executed in this third page now these
are just old codes that I have injected
the code will be executed will be stored
in this page so that every person that
just visits this page you don't have to
actually send anything to any person
whenever someone visits this page the
code will be executed another thing is
that you won't have this suspicious code
in the URL so again you can you can just
go ahead and send this URL if you really
wanted to someone to visit it but your L
is just gonna look as a normal URL and
keep in mind if you find this
vulnerability in a famous website or in
a trusted website then people will visit
it without even thinking twice about it
so they'll just click on it no problem
at all
so we're gonna inject it again the same
way that we were injecting in our video
about the stored so I'm just going to
set the name to beef
and then we're gonna put our code in
here so we're gonna put our exploit in
here I'm just gonna copy it again from
here
this field actually doesn't let you
write more than 10 characters I think in
it or 100 so we're just going to
right-click and inspect element and
we're going to set the max length to 500
like so and that allow us to write more
characters so just go back and paste it
in here
and we're ready to go I'm gonna sign the
guestbook
okay and that should be running so now
you can just go ahead and send this URL
instead of this suspicious one that we
were seen in the reflected case so you
can literally just send this URL to
anybody that you want your code to run
on their computer and once they click it
you'll get them hooked to beef or you
can just wait for people to visit that
URL normally as if they're browsing that
website or whatever once they click on
that URL
they'll be hooked to your beef and again
like I said before if the website is
famous if the website has a lot of
visitors they will be clicking on that
another plus is the web admin probably
going to be visiting his websites web
pages every now and then so again you'll
get you'll get him hooked and you'll be
able to hack him and then maybe gain
full access to the server or to the web
site through this XSS so I'm going to go
to my Windows machine
and I'm gonna run my browser
you
and I'm gonna go to the DV WI and I'm
just gonna pretend I'm a normal user so
and we're gonna go to dvwa login
so I'm just gonna go on the security and
I'm gonna set it to low because on high
and nothing's gonna work
and note this now I'm gonna just click
on the xs/s third so I'm just pretending
to be a normal person browsing through a
web page web pages and I'm gonna just
come across a web page that is
vulnerable to I start XSS I could be the
web admin as well just clicking on my
own page and we can see these are just
the old exploits the old XSS is and now
this browser should be hooked without
even clicking on anything suspicious
again you can see this is normal they
didn't really receive anything or
anybody asking them to click on anything
but if we go to our beef here you'll see
that we have a Windows machine so this
is my Linux machine here and you can see
that we have a Windows machine here now
the windows icon we can see the IP
address of the Windows machine
and this machine is hooked now so if we
click on it it's online and we can run
all the commands that leaf allows us to
do
so and here on the right we'll be
spending most of our time now in the
next lectures to run commands on the
target computer so once you click on an
IP address from the left here you'll be
using or interacting with that hooked
browser from here from the right so you
can get various information here about
that web browser or about that person
you can see the version the browser
version it detected it as a Mozilla and
it's using Apple WebKit
it's used in English es USD language
it's win32 architecture this is
important when you come to create back
doors for that computer if you wanted to
gain full access to it you can also see
the plugins installed on that browser
again useful to try maybe spoof them and
ask the person to upload that plug-in
and we'll see that Analects lecture or
you can see and try to hike him through
a vulnerability within these plugins
you can also see the comedy components
that's enabled on that browser so you
can see it uses flash it doesn't use
vbscript again these things can come in
handy when you're trying to gain full
access to that computer scrolling down
you'll see more information about that
website or about that person you can see
the page that we managed to get them
hooked through and it's this page so
it's the dvwa page you can see where
they came from and they came from the
security dot php' again
you can see the IP where the page is
hosted and the cookies again here you
get more information you have the IP of
the target person we have the operating
system so it's used in Windows again the
architecture now you can see that the
architecture here is different than
what's saying on the top on the top sign
and windows 32 and in here it's in it's
64 now on the top is actually the
architecture of the browser so the
browser is a Windows 32 bits but the
actual CPU on the computer is detected
here which is 64 bits again this comes
in handy when you create in backdoors
for that computer
going on the going on the logs you'll
just see the logs or the events that
happened so far so you can see that the
browser window was focused it lost focus
you can see here when they just joined
and we just got hooked the commands
we'll be spending a lot of the time here
these are all the commands that you can
run on the target computer and we'll be
having a more in-depth look on them in
the next lectures
the writer will allow you to see and
create HTTP requests the XSS race will
allow you to discover XSS
vulnerabilities in the current page
the eye pack is just a beefed terminal
that you can use beef commands and
interact with beef through it the
network will give you an overview of the
current network so you can see that we
have our hooked browser here it is used
on this machine right here the Windows
machine and it's hooked to us there is a
firewall and it's hooked to us to here
that's us now if you had multiple
devices then you'll be able to see them
in here so that it will help you imagine
or have a visualization of what's
happening the web RTC basically allows
you to create a network of all the
browsers that you gained access to and
try to hide yourself by using this
peer-to-peer network
now this is just a basic overview of
beef and the next lectures we'll see how
to interact with with the hooked
browsers how to run commands and even
gain full access to the connected
computers once you're done you can just
log out of beef by clicking on the
logout button and that's it you're out
so now that we have our browser or
Target hooked we can go on the commands
and start executing commands on that
target you can use the search to filter
you're looking for a certain command if
you know what you're looking for or you
can use the categories and look for
commands suitable to what you want to do
on the target computer some of these
commands are information gathering
commands some of them are social
engineering some of them will even give
you full control over the target
computer there is a lot of commands so I
won't be able to go over all of them but
I'll be showing you some of the most
important commands and examples of
simple ones as well so you know how to
experiment and run the other commands so
we're starting if you go to the browser
you'll see commands related to stuff
that you can do inside the browser so
you can see things that will allow you
to for example get a screen shot and
you'll be able to try and gain and turn
on the webcam and see if it works
and basically open the webcam on the
target you can gather information and if
you go here on the exploits you'll see a
number of exploits that you can run
again depending on what's running on the
chrome target computer you can run them
all you have to do is just click on the
module that you want to run and click on
execute sometimes some modules need to
send some options to be set up and we'll
have examples of that as well and the
social engineering again there is some
really cool stuff that you can do and
you can show fake updates fake
notification bars and stuff like that so
let's have an example of a very simple
command so again we're going to do just
an alert to show an alert box so I'm
just using the search to filter and you
can see here this will just create an
alert dialog and it's gonna say beef
alert dialog you can modify this and
type in anything you want for example
I'm gonna type in test and then when you
hit execute go on to target and you'll
see that the target got a message saying
test so this has been injected into the
target browser
another cool thing that you can do is
the raw JavaScript
and this will allow you to execute any
JavaScript you want so again you can
look for Google for a useful JavaScript
code for example a keylogger or whatever
you want to do or you can write your own
if you know JavaScript and basically
whatever you write here will be executed
on the target again we're only saying
and alert and this is gonna say beef raw
JavaScript I'm gonna execute and here we
go again we got a dialog saying beef
draw JavaScript
let's see if we can get a screenshot of
the target computer and we're gonna use
a plugin called spy spy there I I think
yes spider eye so again click on it hit
execute give it a second then we're
gonna click on the command here looks
like this time didn't work properly
let's just do it again
you
and here we go as you can see we got a
screenshot of what the target person is
looking at another really good plugin is
a plugin it's redirect plugin
and it'll basically allow you to
redirect the browser to any web page you
want this could be very useful because
you can use it to redirect the target
person and tell them that they're gonna
they need to download an update and
instead of giving them an update give
them a backdoor you can redirect them to
a fake login page for example for
Facebook you can really do anything you
want with this so you can set the
website that you want the target to be
redirected to and we're going to
redirect them to beef project in this
example and once you hit execute as you
can see here they redirected to beef
project these are some of the basic
modules that are that you can use again
you can experiment with these go over
them and see what would be useful in
your particular situation
okay now let's have a look on a social
engineering plugin that will allow us to
steal usernames and passwords for
accounts so basically the way this works
is it will dim the screen and it will
turtle the person that you go logged out
of your session so please log in to your
account again so you can get
authenticated so this will allow us to
bypass HTTPS HSTs all all the security
that's used by the target account page
for example if you're trying to get
username and password for Facebook then
you'll be able to bypass all the
security that Facebook uses because
you're what you're doing is you're
actually just showing a fake Facebook
page so the user will never actually get
in contact with Facebook so let's just
click on this and you'll see that you
can click from here you can click what
account that you want to hijack
so let's say we're going with Facebook
and you can select what the back light
will be so we're just leaving that as
gray and we're gonna execute this and we
go when we go to our target you'll see
that they're being told that they got
locked out of their session so please
login with your username and password so
I'm gonna put my username as 8
then I'm gonna put my password as one
two three four five six
and enter and if we go back here
you'll see that we got our username was
8 and the password was 1 2 3 4 5 6 so
you can use this to hijack a number of
accounts for example and let's just have
another example if we go with YouTube
again you give it an execute come back
you see the YouTube logo and you can try
to login put a username password sign in
and that'll be captured so again this is
a really good way of gaining access to
accounts because even if the user is not
planning on logging into the account
that you're trying to steal then you'll
kind of force them to enter their
username and password to get to be
logged back in into their account and
then you'll be able to capture the
username and the password
in this lecture we're going to learn how
to generate an undetectable backdoor AB
actor is just a file that's one executed
on the target computer it'll give us
full access to that computer so it'll
basically allow us to hack it and do
anything that we want on that computer
there is a number of ways to generate
backdoors and what we're interested in
is to generate a backdoor that is not
detectable by antivirus programs now
this is not very hard to achieve as
you'll see and we're gonna do this using
a tool called veil framework now I
already have wills project page open in
here I'm going to include its link in
the resources of this lecture on the top
left now if you're not familiar with git
this is a version control system that
allows programmers to host share and
update their programs so to download
something from github all you have to do
is click on the green button in here
copy this link and then go to terminal
navigate to the location where you want
to download this project and in this
example I want to go to opt this is the
directory where you should be installing
optional software and if I do LS you
will see I only have one directory in
here called teeth so to download will in
here all you have to do is first of all
write the git command which is good and
what we want to do is we want to clone a
repository and the link for this
repository is the link that we copied in
here from the green button so I'm just
gonna paste it here
so a very very simple command we're
using it to download a repository from
get we're saying that I want to clone
this repository and the link of the
repository that I want to clone is this
one so if I hit enter now you'll see
it's going to download it for me
and once it's done if we do LS you'll
see we have a new directory called Ville
and we can navigate to this directory by
doing CD evil
and in here if I list you'll see we have
a number of files but the main file for
the program is this one well dot py but
we can't run this file right now because
we still didn't install this tool now
available eyes on a large number of
libraries and third-party programs so
you're gonna have to install all of
these first before you can use it now
luckily you don't have to do this
manually because we'll comes with an
installation script now this script is
placed in the config directory so we
have to navigate in this directory first
so we'll do CD config
and if we list here you'll see we have a
file called set up dot sh now as the
name suggests if you're on this file it
will install all the needed libraries
and third-party applications that we'll
uses so to run an SH or a bash file from
the terminal all you have to do is type
dot forward slash followed by the file
name and in our case it's called setup
dot Sh
now you can run the setup as is like
this but I want to add two arguments to
this the first argument that I want to
add is the - - silent this argument will
run the Installer as an unattended
installer so basically it will install
everything with its default settings and
it won't ask us to configure anything
the next argument that I want to add is
the - - force so that in case you're
running this a second time if you
already installed well and something
went wrong and you're installing it
again
the first argument will overwrite any
existing installations now I didn't just
figure out these arguments myself if you
actually read the description here on
the project page you'll learn exactly
how to install it and what each of these
arguments do so I'm gonna hit enter now
and as you can see now it's going to
automatically gather information about
my current operating system it's going
to install the needed libraries and the
needed applications this might take some
time because it's going to download a
lot of packages so please be patient and
give it its time now I'm going to pause
the video because this is gonna take
some time and I'll continue recording
once it's done so right now as you can
see the installation is finished and
it's telling me that everything is done
so I can run the tool now but what I'm
actually gonna do is I'm gonna first
close this terminal window and open a
new window just to show you how you
would start it by default because
usually when you open terminal you'll
actually be in the root directory so if
I do PWD right now you'll see I am in
root so in order to run ville we have to
first navigate to the location where you
downloaded it and we downloaded it to
the opt directory so we're gonna do CD
opt well
now if we do LS you'll see we have the
file that I told you that's the file for
the program and we have the config
directory where we were and where we run
the installer now we've already
installed everything so we don't need to
run the installer and to run Ville all
we have to do is type dot forward slash
followed by the program name which is
well dot py I'm going to hit enter and
as you can see the program is working
with no issues at all now in the next
lectures I'm going to show you how to
use this program to generate
undetectable backdoors that can be used
to hack Windows computers ok now that we
have well loaded you can see it show us
the main commands that you can use with
well so the first command is you can do
exit to exit you can do info to get
information about a specific tool you
can do lists to list the available tools
you can do update to update valve and
this is very very important because you
always want to be up-to-date when it
comes to bypassing antivirus programs
and then you can do use to use a tool
now let's start using relevation and as
we do it it's going to become so easy
and you'll be able to understand it more
now ville has two main tools and if we
do a list you'll be able to see them so
we have the first one which is the one
that we're interested in which is called
evasion and that's the one that
generates undetectable backdoors for us
and then there is the second one which
is called ordinance and this tool
generates the payloads that's used by
evasion so you can look at this as a
helper or a secondary tool now what I
mean by a payload is a payload is the
part of the code of the back door that
does the stuff that we want that does
the evil stuff if you want to say so
it's the part of the code that gives us
a reverse connection it's the part of
the code that download and execute
something on the target computer it's
the part of the code that allow us to
achieve what we want by executing that
file and this is going to become more
clear as we start using Ville now for
now we're interested in to using evasion
so we're going to do use
one because that's the first tool that's
number one
and as you can see we have will evasion
loaded now and as I said before this
used to be a standalone tool that you
just downloaded on its own but now they
have it all combined together now as you
can see the first thing that we get when
we load will evasion is the commands
that you can run on this tool so the
first thing that we want to do is we
want to list to see all the available
payloads
and as you can see we have 41 different
payloads and all of these payloads
follow a certain naming pattern and you
can see for example let's take this
example right here because that's the
payload that I'm going to be using you
can see the payload is divided into
three parts
the first parts right here refers to the
programming language that's the payload
is going to be wrapped in so we have the
evil code and then the evil code is
going to be wrapped into a certain
programming language that the target
computer understands and right here you
can see that this payload uses go
programming language we can see this one
uses C we can see these ones UCS we have
Python we have powershell and we have
Ruby if we scroll down
the second part of the payload is really
important this is the type of the
payload the type of the code that's
going to be executed on the target
computer
in this example were using meterpreter
which is a payload designed by
Metasploit Metasploit is a huge
framework for hacking and it allows you
to do a lot of things but in this
lecture were focusing on creating a
payload called meterpreter and what's
really cool about meterpreter is it runs
empty memory and it allow us to migrate
between system processes so we can have
the payload or the backdoor running from
a normal process like explorer for
example and this payload will allow us
to gain full control over the target
computer so we'll be able to navigate
through the filesystem download upload
files turn on the mic turn on the webcam
even use that computer to hack other
computers install a key logger you can
literally do anything you can think of
and all of this will be running from the
memory from a normal process on the
system so it's very hard to detect and
it doesn't leave a lot of footprints
that's why it's a really really cool
payload and we'll be using it a lot
the third part of the name is the method
that's going to be used to establish the
connection so in here you can see that
this is called Reb HTTPS so Rev
stands for reverse and HTTP is the
protocol that's going to be used to
establish the connection so we can see
that this payload will create a reverse
HTTPS connection you can see this one
right here for example it creates a
reverse HTTP connection and we have this
one in here that creates a reverse TCP
connection now what I mean by reverse is
the connection is going to come from the
target computer to my own computer so I
won't be connecting to the computer that
I want to hack what's going to happen is
once the person DoubleClick's the back
door the back door will connect back to
me from the target computer
what's cool about this is I'll be able
to bypass antivirus programs because the
connection is not going to the target
computer is coming back to my computer
so it's literally as if the target
person is just connecting to a normal
website I'm going to use a port that
websites use which is 80 or 8080
so again if the person analyzes the
connection it'll look as if they're
literally just connecting to a normal
website also if the target computer is
hidden behind a router or behind a
network again this is going to work
because the connection is coming from
the target computer to me instead of me
connecting to the target computer so
using a reverse connection is really
really handy and I think this is really
the only practical way of gaining access
to a computer because there is a lot of
things that can stop you from connecting
to a certain computer now this is the
general naming pattern you'll see some
payloads like this one right here which
doesn't follow that general naming
pattern and basically what these
payloads do for example you can see this
one is called shellcode inject so what's
going to do is it's going to create a
payload that injects your other payload
so it's going to create a normal payload
and that normal payload injects a
meterpreter payload for example now it
does this to try to bypass more security
but usually they won't bypass more
things than the normal payloads would
bypass so that's why I usually just used
one of the normal payloads in here so
this is it this is all about the
payloads sorry I took a bit of time but
I wanted to make sure that you guys
understand the naming pattern I wanted
you to understand what a payload is and
the difference between a reverse and a
bind and a TCP payload this way you the
rest of the course will become more
clear to you and I can just use the
payload that I want without explaining
what it is now in the next lecture we're
going to be generating a payload and
we'll be testing it against antivirus
programs
okay so in this video we're going to be
using veil to create a backdoor so the
first thing I'm going to do is I'm going
to do list to list the available tools
and I'm going to use number one because
we want to use evasion and then I'm
going to list my payloads
and like I said in the previous lecture
I want to use go meterpreter reverse
HTTPS so that's number 15 so I'm going
to use 15
and that's gonna list the first of all
is going to show me information about
this particular payload and then it'll
show me the options that I can set for
this payload so the main option that you
wanna set and the most important one is
the IP address so this is the IP address
which you're going to be receiving the
connections on as we said we're going to
have a reverse connection and we need to
set the IP address which the payload or
the backdoor will try to connect back to
and in our case we want to receive the
connection back to this cally machine so
we're going to set the IP el host to the
IP address of the current cally machine
now to get the IP of my cally machine I
have to run if config so I'm going to
split the screen by doing right click
and click on split horizontally
and I'm just gonna bring this down a bit
and we're gonna run if config
now you can see the IP address in here
is 10 2014 to 13 this is the IP of my
Kali machine this is the IP of the
machine that I'm using as the attacking
machine so this is where I want the
connection to come back to so I can hack
the target computer once the backdoor is
executed so I'm gonna set
Elle hosts
- 10 2014 - 13
so you can set any of these options
using the set command so all you have to
do is write set followed by the option
that you want to change so in this case
we want to change the L host and we want
to change that to 10 2014 to 13
now the airport is set to 80 which is
really good because that's the port
that's used by web servers so as I said
the connection will look as if the
target person is connecting to a website
and it's not going to be suspicious but
I don't want to use that port because
I'll have a web server running on this
and we'll talk about that later
so I'm gonna change that to 80 80 80 80
is another port that used by web servers
so it's still not suspicious and it
should still bypass firewalls so I'm
just gonna do set same way that we did
it before with the alehouse we're going
to do el port
to the value that we want to set this
option to and we're going to set it to
now if I do options again
to list all the options
see that the alehouse changed to 10 2014
to 13 and the Alport changed to 8080
now if you generate the back door like
this you will bypass all antivirus
programs except AVG I've already tried
this that's how I know this and that's
not good enough because we want to
bypass everything now the way antivirus
programs work is they have a very large
database of signatures these signatures
correspond to files that contain harmful
code so what they do is they compare the
signature of your file of your backdoor
to all the files in this huge database
if your file matches any of these files
then they'll flag it as a virus or as
malware if it doesn't then they'll think
that it's a normal file and it's not
malware
so the main point in here is we're going
to try to modify the file our back door
as much as possible to make it more
unique so that it bypasses the signature
database and we'll be able to bypass
antivirus programs now as I said Ville
is already doing that for us it's an
encrypted the backdoor it's obfuscating
it it's injecting it in the memory so
that it doesn't get detected and it's
doing a good job at it it's bypassing
pretty much everything except for only
one antivirus program
so just to bypass this last antivirus
program I'm gonna set some optional
options that really won't do much of a
difference they'll just make the
backdoor look a bit different so the
first thing that I'm going to modify is
processors and that's the minimum number
of processors to be used by the backdoor
I'm not gonna set a huge number because
that'll just make my backdoor not work
I'm just gonna set it to one which is
pretty much nothing really but I'm just
gonna set this option to make the code
look a bit different so I'm gonna do set
again the same way that we are setting
the L part and the L host
we're just going to put the option name
which is processors
and we're going to set that to number
one
I'm also gonna set another option which
is the sleep option and that basically
lets the backdoor sleep for a number of
seconds that you set before it executes
the evil code that you have in there
before it executes the payload so I'm
gonna set this to six again no real
reason for this I'm only doing this to
make the backdoor look a bit different
so I'm gonna do set sleep
two-six so I'm going to hit enter and
I'm gonna do options again to make sure
that all the options are set the way I
want them to be so I have my IP address
set properly I have my L port I have my
processors and I have my sleep so I'm
going to generate the back door
and now it's asking me to name this back
door or something so I'm gonna name this
back door Rev
HTTP 8080 just so that we can remember
which payload and which port to use for
this back door in the future
now the backdoor is generated and you
can see it's telling us the module
that's used and it's telling us where
the backdoor is stored so the backdoor
is stored in this path right here so I'm
going to copy that
let's go ahead and check to see if the
backdoor is detected by any antivirus
programs now you can use the built-in
feature by will using the check VT
command but this feature only uses the
signature of the file and it's not 100%
accurate sometimes it tells you that the
file will bypass all anti viruses but
it'll actually be detected you can also
use virustotal but I don't recommend
that and please don't do that
because if you do that your backdoor
will become less effective because
virustotal
share the results of their scans with
antivirus programs what we're going to
do is we're going to use a website
called know distribute so we're going to
go to it now
so I'm just going to Google for know
distribute
and what this is gonna do it similar to
virustotal
the only difference is it's not going to
share these kind results with antivirus
programs so what effect your backdoor so
I'm gonna click on browse to navigate to
my file and I'm just gonna copy where
the file is stored so Ville is telling
me now it's stored in this location and
users share will output compiled so I'm
gonna copy this
and I'm gonna come here I'm gonna click
on the pen and I'm gonna paste the
location
I'm going to click on open
and scan the file
now as you can see I've already scanned
this file and it's telling me that this
file has been scanned before so I'm just
gonna click on view previous results and
as you can see the file is actually
scanned on the same day as today which
is the 29th of March 2017 and as you can
see the file is bypassing all antivirus
programs
so we can use this back door against any
device and we'll be sure that the device
or the computer will not be able to
detect this file as a virus now there is
a few things to keep in mind antivirus
programs always update their database
and will always update their code as
well so you want to always make well
up-to-date also sometimes with the same
exact backdoor
it might get detected and it might not
get detected because depending on the
way the backdoor is getting encrypted
and it's getting generated
I've actually generated this backdoor
before with sleep or with no sleep and
as I said it got got detectives by one
antivirus program I generated with 10
seconds and it still got detected and
then with 6 it was able to bypass it so
you want to keep playing around with the
options you want to keep playing around
with the payloads until you managed to
achieve the best results so that you can
bypass as much antivirus programs as
possible
now the backdoor that we created uses a
reverse payload so like I said before it
does not open a port in the target
computer it actually connects from the
target computer to our computer and by
doing that it will bypass firewalls and
it will look less suspicious so for this
to work we need to open a port in our
computer so that the backdoor can
connect from the target computer to us
on that port so if you remember when I
created the backdoor I set the port to
8080 so I need to open that part in my
Kali machine so that when the target
person executes the backdoor the back
there can connect back to me on port
8080 so I'm just going to write the name
of the payload that we used because
that's very important when you're
listening for incoming connections so we
used a payload that's written and go and
that was ammeter Peter Rev HTTP which is
a reverse HTTP payload now this is not a
command I'm just going to write it in
here so just that you keep this in mind
and we used port 8080
for the reverse connection so these are
the most important things to keep in
mind when listening for incoming
connections so I'm going to split the
screen
I'm gonna listen for incoming
connections in here and to do that I'm
going to use the Metasploit framework
now to run Metasploit all you have to do
is just run MSF console
now Metasploit framework is a huge
framework for penetration testing
so the meterpreter back door or the
meterpreter payload that will created
for us is actually programmed by the
people who made meters ployed that's why
we're using Metasploit to listen for
incoming connections so veil evasion
actually uses Metasploit to generate the
backdoor that we chose in the previous
video so to listen for incoming
connections were gonna use a module in
Metasploit now Metasploit as I said is a
huge framework and it has a lot of
modules so the module that were
interested in is a module that allow us
to listen for incoming connections from
a meteor Piotr payload to use that
module we're gonna do use
to use a module and then we're gonna
specify the module name and the module
name is exploit multi handler okay so
the command were using is used to
specify the module that we want to use
and we're using a module called exploit
multi handler that allow us to listen
for incoming connections I'm going to
hit enter
and I was already in that module so you
can see that nothing changed for me but
for you you should navigate to that
module and I'm gonna do show options
to see the options that I can set for
this module
and you can see that you can specify
different options for it
the most important thing that you want
to specify is the payload so you can see
in here for me it's set to Windows
meterpreter reversed TCP and if you
remember what we used we used a meter
Peter reverse HTTP not TCP so you want
to change this the first part is fine
because our target is going to be
Windows but you want to change the
reverse TCP to reverse HTTPS and you can
change that exactly the same way that we
did with veil evasion so you type in set
you put the option name that you want to
change and we want to change the option
for the payload so we're going to say
payload
and we're gonna set that to windows
meterpreter reverse HTTP this time
okay so we're doing set to set an option
were setting the payload to Windows
meterpreter reverse HTTP now this
payload should correspond to the payload
that you chose in the back door so in
the back door we used meterpreter
reverse HTTP that's why in here we use
in reverse HTTPS as well if you chose
reverse HTTP then set this to reverse
HTTP if you use reverse TCP then set
this to reverse TCP and so on so I'm
gonna head enter for this and that's
gonna do it for me and if I do show
options now
you'll see the payload changed to
Windows meterpreter reverse HTTP now the
same concept applies for all the other
options so you want to set the alehouse
to our IP address and you can see that
this is already set to the right one so
if it was wrong for you all you have to
do is just do set L host
and put your IP address so you can get
the IP address using if config like I
showed you in the previous lecture so
for me it's 10 2014 to 13 and again this
is the same IP that I used when I
created my backdoor and same goes for
the port you want to set the same port
so we're going to do set L port
to 8080 because that's the part that we
used when we generated the back door so
again the main idea with this is you
want to set the payload the L host and
the port to exactly the same options
that you chose when you created the back
door once done with that we're going to
do show options one more time
and you'll see that I have my payload
set properly windows meterpreter reverse
https I have my L host and I have my
Alpert and all of that is done properly
so all we have to do now we just do
exploit
and now Metasploit is waiting for
connections as you can see on port 8080
and on my IP address which is 10 2014
213 so now if anybody opens the back
door that we created in the previous
lecture because the server's back door
the back door will try to connect to the
IPS that we set when we created the back
door which was 10 2014 213 and it'll try
to connect on port 8080
it's going to come to this computer and
this computer is already waiting for
that connection from this multi handler
module so the connection will be
established and then I'll be able to
control the target computer and I'll
basically hack it and have full control
over it now in the next lecture I'll
show you a very basic way to deliver the
backdoor to the target computer and how
to test the backdoor and make sure that
it works properly
now we are ready to receive connections
from our back door so we created the
back door we set a payload and we're
listening for incoming connections here
from any connection that comes in from
the same back door on the same pair a
port on the same IP so now if a person
runs that back door will receive the
connection back in here on this computer
what we're gonna do now is we're gonna
test the back door to make sure that it
works and to do that we're going to use
a very basic delivery method later on in
the course we're going to talk about
smart delivery methods that will trick
the person and to open the file that
we're sending to them for now we're just
doing a very basic example just to test
our very basic back door so to do that
we're just gonna put the back door on
our web server and then download it from
the target computer so there's nothing
smart about this and you probably can't
use this way to deliver the back door to
a real person so we're only doing this
for testing to make sure our back door
works so Kali comes in with a webserver
and what that means basically you can
use