now let's talk about how you can secure
your website from file upload
vulnerabilities
the main thing to keep in mind is that
never allow people to upload executables
there shouldn't be a need for you to
allow people to upload executables
really so stuff like PHP bash scripts
executables like exe comm all these
files you should never allow people to
upload them because there is a high
possibility that these files could harm
your server
the second thing is you need to check
that the file type is what the what you
want is what you're expecting and check
the extension at the same time so when
we seen when we were checking with our
tests and the previous videos at the low
security level obviously there was no
checks at the medium security level
there was checking for only the file
type and at the high security level they
were checking for the extension only so
what you want to do really is never
allow executables make sure the uploaded
file is what you're expecting so if
you're uploading an image make sure that
the file type is an image and the and
the extension is an image extension so
it's a JPEG or a PNG or any other image
type only and once you do these two
checks so that and that make sure that
you recreate the uploaded file so you
check that the file is an image and you
check that the extension is an image
extension then analyze the file using
some sort of a library so depending on
the programming language you're using on
your server make sure that you analyze
you pass this file to a library and
analyze its content and you recreate the
file to suit your website now this is
actually a good step anyway because
since you're displaying this on your
website you want to make sure that the
images aren't too big and that they are
optimized for web applications so it's a
good thing for your website to run
faster and it's also a good thing to
make sure that this image is actually an
image and it's not harm a harmful file
so let's just have a look on the source
code now I know I always say we're doing
black box testing but we're talking
about the security now so you actually
have to see the source code to see how
you can secure it so I'm just going to
set the security level to medium because
the load just doesn't really check
anything so we're just gonna go with the
medium for now and we're gonna go on the
upload
and I'm going to view the source so as
you can see now in the medium it's only
checking if the uploaded file type is an
image now I don't want to get into too
much details about coding because this
isn't a coding course we're only talking
about how you secure yourself and about
penetration testing so I have to cover
the security part so we're going to talk
about the concepts but not the actual
code that you need to use because you
could be using a different programming
language so in here they're using PHP
and what they're doing is they have just
a simple if statement and they're
checking if the if the image if the
uploaded file type is an image so we
seen how we can bypass this easily by
uploading an image and then changing the
extension to by renaming our shelf to
the jpg which will upload it which will
be accepted as an image and then we'll
just rename it as it's been uploaded to
PHP file now if we set this to high
security level
and you go back to the upload and have a
look at the source code you can see that
what they're doing here they're checking
that the extension is a jpg or a jpg and
then you can upload the picture so
they're not checking for the file type
this time so as I said you need to check
for both now in the new versions of dvwa
it actually has an extra security
setting called
impossible and what that is it basically
just shows you the right implementation
of each one of these pages so it's it
actually can't be hacked it's the right
way to do it
the dvwa version that comes in with
Metasploit Apple doesn't have that
security setting but we don't really
need to use it anyway we just need to
see the code so I have it here on github
and the way the right way to implement
this is if we look at this is the same
if statement and basically what they're
checking is they check the extension is
is an image extension such a JPEG or jpg
or PNG so that's all good so it has to
be one of these things and it has to be
of an image type so it has to be of type
image JPEG or image PNG and it doesn't
stop at that actually checks the sizes
but that's okay
what it also does which I was speaking
about which is recreating the image
itself
so what they're doing is they're
stripping the metadata of the image and
they're using a library actually they're
not using that library but you should be
using that library which is called PHP a
magic or whatever there is that they're
similar libraries for Python and Ruby
and all of that - basically what they do
is they recreate another image from the
uploaded image
once they do that they actually delete
and destroy the old image and use the
new image with a new name so they create
a new image from the old image they
rename it and then you they use that
image so these are three things you need
to check for the extension check for the
file type recreate the image itself that
way even if a person tries to upload a
bad file or a malicious file then you'll
be able to protect your web application
and your server from that file so even
if they managed to upload the file then
the file would be destroyed because of
the recreation process
code execution vulnerabilities these
type of vulnerabilities allow us to
execute operating system code on the
target server so if the target server
uses Windows will be able to execute
Windows commands if it uses Linux then
we'll be able to use to use the next
command clearly this is a really
critical problem that would allow us to
do anything we want with the target
really we can upload a PHP shell using W
get command or upload a payload a virus
anything we want using the W K W get
Linux command you just need to make sure
that you're uploading it to a file or to
a directory which you're allowed to
write stuff to another way of exploiting
this vulnerability is to just run OS
commands and get a reverse shell based
on these commands so because we can run
operating system commands we can use the
programming languages supported by that
operating system to try and get a
reverse connection or on our computer so
first of all let's just assume that
we're browsing here and we managed we're
going around and then we got to a tab in
the website where it allows you to for
example do a ping now what you should do
is you should always try to experiment
with any input box you see try to see
what that input box does and what can
you inject into it what can you do to
get stuff running so for example this
input box is telling you it's going to
do a ping and if you put an IV for
example I'm gonna put 10 2014 203 which
is my own IP just to see it to use it as
a normal person and I'm gonna do a
submit and it's gonna go ahead and ping
it for me and give me the pink results
so what looks like here it's actually
executing the ping command and Linux
systems now let's see if we can exploit
that if it's actually executing the ping
command so what it's doing is it's going
and it's doing so we're sending 10 2014
2 o3 as the pink and then it's going to
the to the web server and the web server
is do
thing 10 2014 2 or 3
so let's see if we can exploit this how
would we exploit it if it's taken what
we're importing right here and then it's
doing pink that now in Linux and UNIX
based commands you can use the this sign
to execute multiple commands on one line
so if you do this if for example in your
own terminal so I'm just going to go to
my terminal here and I'm just going to
do LS which is the list command and then
PWD is what lists what shows your
working directory so if I do an LS
followed by this sign and then do PWD it
will execute both commands so it will do
this and then it will show where the
working directory is so we can do the
same thing with this and see if it works
for us so we're gonna put an IV a write
IP and then I'm just gonna do PWD and
see if it will execute the PWD for me if
it does then this is a code execution
vulnerability and I can execute anything
I want on the server so let's see what's
going to happen I pasted this and I'm
gonna hit submit now as we can see we
got big results but at the end we got
our current working directory so it's
very www DV w ie vulnerability is an
exit so it executed the PWD that I
inserted and that means I can insert any
commands I want in there and they'll be
executed so I've inserted a resources
file that will that you can use to get
reverse connection from the target
computer now there's a number of ways a
number of commands that would give you a
reverse connection all these commands
depend on the programming language so
for example we have commands at PHP we
have commands Ruby you have Perl
commands and we have the 1 for bash bash
is the linux shell command language so
all UNIX operating systems will be able
to execute bash commands so that's a
very very good way of doing it so most
UNIX system this command should work
on most UNIX based systems so this would
be a really good way of doing it again
most of them would have Python so Python
would be a good way netcat most of them
do have net cat as well so net cat is a
good way of doing that and we're
actually going to use net cat in this
video so what I'm going to do is first
I'm gonna listen for connections just
like we used to do with Metasploit when
we used to do multi handler you can
actually use a multi handler for this
and listen for connections but I'm just
gonna keep it simpler and show you a new
way and I'm gonna use that cat so net
cat
netiquette is just a tool that allows
you to listen and connect computers
together so I'm gonna listen on port
8080 so netcat is the program Vivi is
just to see verbose output so we can see
a lot of output anything goes wrong we
can see it and we're telling it to
listen using the l option on port 8080
so I'm gonna hit enter and that's saying
it's just listening on port 8080 that's
all it's going to do the next command
we're going to do is we're going to try
to connect from the web server back to
my computer using netcat as well so
we're assuming the web server has netcat
we'll go try it and see if that works so
the command is very simple it's netcat
and we're telling it to use brain bash
and we're giving it the IP of my device
my attacker device which is 10 2014
and then the port which is 80 80 which
is we're listening on right here so I'm
gonna copy that and I'm just gonna
execute it the same way we used to
execute the PW the PWD command
so the last thing we did was 10:20
14 203
and then we did PWD so what I'm gonna do
now I'm gonna remove the PWD and paste
the code that we just created which will
try to connect from the web server back
to the callee machine to the attacker
machine and I'm gonna come here and as
you can see we got a connection back
from two to us from 10 2014 204
so that's the target computer and if we
do a PWD you'll see that we have a
reversal if we do an LS if we do an ID
you'll see that word every W data and if
we do a you name a just to confirm that
I'm in the meet exploitable and you can
see the momentum is exploitable and I'm
able to run any command that I want on
the target computer so basically I have
full access to the target computer
okay now that we managed to execute
commands on the server using the low
security settings let's see if we can
set it up to medium and if we can do the
same after increasing the security so we
covered the basic case and now I'm going
to go to security and I'm gonna send set
the security level to medium I'm gonna
submit this then we're gonna go back to
our command execution and I'm gonna
input my IP now I just want to know that
my IP is different now
if you notice that the IP of the server
right now is 209 and my machine IP is 2i
if I do with conflict
you can see that the IP of my caddy
machine is 208 so again I'm gonna try to
think the Cali machine let's just first
see if we can think something so we're
assuming that we don't know this website
and again this is going from a black box
point of view so we're not going to look
at the source code so we're just gonna
run and this website is telling us is
gonna pink stuff for us so I'm just
gonna put the IP of the Kali and see if
the pink works so we're just going to
put 10
and as you can see now the pink command
is working now let's see and try to do
what we did before so we used to do we
put the IP and then we use the semicolon
to say that run this command and this
command and in the low security settings
this used to work for us so we're gonna
submit this and at the bottom it should
show us our current working directory
because we have the PWD here so I'm
submitting this
and as you can see nothing got executed
so not even the ping command got
executed so again looking from a
blackbox point of view we're gonna think
oh maybe they're using some sort of
filtering on the semicolon so they're
checking if the command contains a
semicolon then they're gonna ignore that
command and not run it so we're just
going to try to use another trick
something similar to the semicolon so
what we used to do before we had an
example of doing LS so that's the NIST
command and or and the PWD is what shows
the working directory and we can combine
these two by doing LS semicolon and then
we do the PWD
and that will do both it will do the
Allies and the PWD so that way you used
to work for us doesn't work anymore
because they're probably filtering based
on this specific character so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna use something
else available for us in the UNIX
commands which is the pipe so piping is
really useful when it comes to UNIX
you'll use it a lot what it basically
does it means run the first command and
once you run that command send the
output or pipe the output to this
command and run the second command on it
so essentially it will run two commands
in our case now you can use pipe for a
lot of things and it's used in two regex
and things like that for us all we want
to do is we're interested into getting
the second command to run so let's have
an example of this so we're gonna do LS
which is going to be similar to our ping
and then we're gonna put the pipe
character which is the vertical bar and
then we're gonna put the second command
that the LS output should be passed to
now PWD that doesn't expect any input to
be passed to it so at the moment when we
run this it'll basically run both but it
won't show you the result of running LS
it will feed it to the PWD and show you
the result of PWD so when I hit enter
you'll see that PWD got executed so in
our example what's happen is we have a
ping then we're inputting our IP so
we're going to put our IP
and then we're going to use the bar
character and we're going to put the
second command that we want to run which
will be the command that will give us
shell on the server but for for the
testing we're just going to do a PWD and
again as you can see we don't see the
results of the pink we only see the
result of the PWD because again for the
third time this command it will run this
and feed the output to PWD
so let's try this in here so we're gonna
do we're gonna put our IP again like we
did before and we used to put PWD like
that but I'm just gonna put my bar
character
and enter
and as you can see the second command
got executed and we got our current
working directory now we can modify this
to get a shell on our computer so again
we're gonna use the bar and we're gonna
get it to you we're gonna use the exact
same method that we use last time so
we're going to do an C minus E and put
my IP
[Music]
and then I'm going to put the port which
is 8080 now before I execute this I'm
going to listen on port 8080 for
connection here and we're going to use
the same command like before using
netcat so and see V V LP 88
this is listening and we're gonna
connect back from here to the Cali hit
submit and sure enough we get a
connection here that allow us to run any
command we want on the server so we can
do PWD now we can list the files we can
get our ID or do anything we want on the
current server so we basically managed
to gain access to that website
let's talk about how we can prevent
these vulnerabilities now and these
exploits we were able to run any code we
wanted on the target computer again this
functionality should be avoided you
should avoid allowing users to run any
sort of code on your server try to avoid
all these functions such as the eval
pass-through and all these functions
that allow a user to run operating
system code on the server if you
absolutely had to use something like it
then make sure you analyze the input
before you execute for example in the
example we seen where the code was doing
a ping and it will think anything we put
in the textbox so I'm put in here slash
there our text box just to show that
this is the input that we put in the
text box this is what the program
actually looks like if it looks
complicated forget about it we're just
talking about the concept here so we're
going to be talking about this year
so say for example you put what we did
is we put a normal IP
and then we put the semicolon and then
we put a command that we wanted to do so
we did for example LS la the problem
with this is the web application used to
take this the way it is copy it and run
it in here which will when you when you
execute this command it will do the pink
first and then it will do the LS la
which is the command that we wanted what
you need to do is for example if you had
to do it what I advise is you just don't
use these functions if you had to use a
function a function like this then what
you should do is check that the input is
what you're expecting for example you're
expecting an IP address and nothing else
so you can use reg X to make sure now
I'm not going to talk about reg X or
what logics is reg X is basically a rule
that will make sure that the input looks
on the following format so it takes a
digit digit digit digit digit digit dot
digit digit which if I put anything else
then the web application should refuse
it and this is exactly what the high
security level does for the code so now
we're talking about black box testing
and everything but I want to show you
what a secure code should look like so
if we go to the security settings and
I'm gonna set this to high this is
actually called impossible and the new
versions of dvwa
but we're using the one that comes with
meet exploitable and it's just called hi
so the reason why they call it
impossible because it's very secure so
if we go to the command execution again
and I'm just gonna have you the source
to show you what they're doing so
they're implementing a way very similar
to using reg X I think user reg X could
be a bit nicer for in terms of like the
look of the code but they're using the
same concept so basically what they have
is they have the target right here so
this is what you input this is what we
put in here so whatever you type in here
is gonna come up as this variable right
here these last dollar target so the
first thing that they're doing is there
are stripping the slashes from it
after they do that they're dividing the
IP using this function so what this
function does it divides the IP based on
the dot so we have number number dot
number number dot number number dot
number number so they're dividing this
dot into an array so for example if you
have an IP let's say
so when we on put our IP which is 10
2014 208
what this function does what the explode
function does right here it'll divide
this into four and two an array of four
elements so the array is going to be
something like this it will be 10 2014
to white
okay and each one of these elements can
be accessed based on its number right
here so what they do is they check if
each one of these elements is a number
so it checks if it's numeric for the
update for the zero for the one 42 and
43 and that checks for this element this
element this element and this element so
they're making sure that we have a
number number number number so when we
try to inject our code right here
regardless of what characters we use our
words what tricks we use as long as
we're going to input characters in here
for example PWD the characters are gonna
go into here as well into the last
element and when this last element gets
checked in using this function using the
is numeric sum function it will give an
error because obviously this is not
number 208 semicolon PWD is not a number
and that'll give us an error saying that
we have entered an invalid IP so the
best way to do this again is to make
sure what the user inputted is what
you're expecting in this case we're
expecting a number number number number
dot number number number dot number
number number dot number number number
so dividing this into four elements and
make sure each one of these elements is
a number will help us to protect this
input and validate the input that it is
correct and it won't be odd hackers want
to be able to use it to hack into our
server
local file inclusion vulnerabilities
these exploits or vulnerabilities allow
you to read any file that is within the
same server so even if the file exists
outside the VAR www you'll be able to
read it and read info with it now why
this vulnerability is critical because
you can read any files so if the users
are storing some sort of important files
or password files then you'll be able to
read them and then from there you can
further exploit your target also if
there is a number of websites on the
same server and you managed to find this
on a website that you're not targeting
then you might be able to access files
related to you to the website that
you're targeting and then further
exploit your website from there so let's
have a look on this and we'll also the
way we're going to be exploiting this
vulnerability is through the URL so
usually in our code execution example we
were writing the code in here now
sometimes you might find the code burned
a vulnerability and the URL so it will
be something like CMD and then you put
the command or for example in this case
it would be IP equals to the IP for
example 10 2014 2 O 3 and then you do
you put the sign and then you put your
PWD after it for example so because our
example was just in the text box same is
gonna happen here and our file inclusion
vulnerability so we can see that when
you're in here in this URL it's saying
that this file is gonna take a page and
it's loading something called include
PHP so it looks like it's actually
loading another page like this current
page is loading another page called
include dot PHP so again you'd be
browsing the web server and trying to
get a feel of it and you see something
like this or you see something called IP
equals the IP and then you know the
the pink for example for the previous
video so for this that we know that our
targets trying to open a file and the
file is called include dot PHP let's see
if there is actually a file called
include dot PHP so I'm just going to
remove everything here and try to access
include dot PHP directly and as we can
see we actually do have a file called
include dot PHP it's not running
properly but it exists and it's in the
same working directory so let's try and
see if we can read a file that is stored
in the computer and we're going to use a
file called ITC password so that's the
file which contains all the users and
their path is on the current web server
so let's have a look on this
so etc' this file contains all the users
for the current operating system so if I
just go on my caddy right here and if I
run it here if I just do cut if you see
password you'll see all the users that I
have on the current computer and their
default path on the current operating
system so we're going to try to read
this file and to do that let's go back
and see our current location so our
current location is in the FIA file and
the FI directory so we need to go back
one two three four five times and then
go to e.t.c password so going back would
be done using the dot dot and let's try
and do that so at the moment were
accessing this current file and just to
make it easier for you actually let's
just put the full path right here
so in the page it's trying to access
this page so what we need we actually
want a place called ATC password so we
need to go back five times for these
directories so this one is going to be
let's start them from here
so we're going back back back back and
back and then we're going to go to e.t.c
password and as you can see now we have
the output of the e.t.c password file we
can copy that
and start here and then you'll be able
to read it and just get more information
about the websites that you're targeting
right now again you can use this to try
to access different files sensitive
files or files of other websites on the
same server
now let's go to the security settings
and I'm gonna set this to medium because
I just want to show you that the medium
setting is in this is actually it can be
exploited exactly the same way as the
low-level so the security set to medium
I'm gonna go back to file inclusion and
we're gonna use the exploit the exact
same way that we did it before
and as you can see we managed to get the
contents of etc' password
so local file inclusion is really good
because it allow us to read files in the
server and we might be able to read
files with passwords or sensitive
information
what will be really great is if we can
actually gain full access or full
control over the target server using
local file inclusion vulnerabilities so
in this lecture we'll see how we can get
a reverse shell by exploiting the local
file inclusion vulnerability that we
seen in the previous lecture so because
they allow us to read files on the
server so if we manage to write anything
on that server then we can write some
malicious code and then browse it and
get that code to be executed so this is
exactly what we're gonna try to do there
is a number of methods to achieve that
so usually it's done using the log files
because the log files usually register
or write stuff that happens on the
server so you can try to log in with a
username but instead of putting a
username you put a PHP code or you can
try to send an email and then instead of
the email put a PHP code and then try to
browse these log files and the PHP code
will be executed the first method that
we're gonna have a look on though it's
gonna exploit the environment variable
so this is basically a file that
contains an array of information about
the current environment so let's just
have an example of this quickly so right
here I am on my Kali machine I'm not
talking anything I'm not on any server
and I'm just gonna see what's the
content of that file so this file exists
in all Linux operating systems so I'm
just going to open that file right now
using the cat command
and as you can see you'll see a number
of environment variables that are
related to the current environment so
what we're gonna do now is we're gonna
try to open this file here in my browser
instead of the e.t.c password
so it's going to be in Prague self and
Byron
okay gonna hit enter
and as you can see again we can see an
array of variables about the current
environment what's interesting here is
this variable so we can see that the
user agent is being sent and it's being
displayed right here now the user agent
basically is the current browser used by
the by the person by the user so you can
see that because I'm using Firefox at
the web site thinks that I'm using
Firefox which is correct and that's
because Firefox every time you open a
web site it actually tells that website
what browser it is so this happens on
our website so we can see that Firefox
is telling the website or the web
browser that I'm Firefox 5 and it's
running on Linux whatever so this is
actually sent from the client so we can
actually modify this value and what
we're gonna try to do is we're gonna
modify the user agent value and we're
gonna place code that will give us
reverse shell before we do that let's
make sure that the code will be executed
on the server so we're gonna send just a
normal PHP code that will display PHP
information so I'm going to turn on my
interceptor now I showed you how to set
up BRR proxy so if you don't know how to
do that go back to that lecture and see
how you can set up your proxy so I just
turned on the Interceptor and I'm gonna
browse the exact same URL
and right here if we go on the headers
you'll see that Firefox is sending the
user agent right here and it sent them
it as Mozilla 5 and then Linux whatever
so what we're going to do is we're gonna
modify this value and we're gonna put
PHP code and the code I'm gonna put is
very simple it will basically just
display the PHP information so it's a
function called PHP info
and then I'm gonna forward this packet
and as you can see the PHP code got
executed on the on the website on the
target website this means if we send
malicious code to this website will
actually be able to gain full access or
we can get our code to be executed now
you can literally send any PHP code you
want you can send code to list files you
can send code to upload the file or you
can send one of the codes that we used
before to gain a reverse connection so
that's what I'm gonna do I'm gonna use
the exact same code that we used before
in the previous lectures to gain full
control over the target computer so I'm
actually just gonna type it down here in
terminal and then I'm gonna copy it
so we're going to be using pass-through
and we're using netcat
and then when I'm gonna put my IP
address
and I'm going to use the port which is
I'm going to in this in this attack I'm
going to use eight eight eight eight and
then we put this semicolon so it's the
same it's just a PHP function and we use
that in the code execution lecture so
I'm literally just going to copy this
and I'm going to inject it as the user
agent now before I do that I'm going to
listen on port 8080 eight eight four
connections so we're going to use the
same code that we used before again with
netcat
and now we're listening for connections
we have our interceptor on I'm gonna
browse the website I'm gonna hit enter
and I'm gonna modify the user agent
again don't forget to put the question
marks here because I only put the code
there so we have the opening and in the
closing for PHP and then we put our code
which is the pass-through code and C e
been SH our IP followed by the port that
were listening on I'm gonna hit enter
and I'm gonna forward
and as you can see we got a connection
back using the local file inclusion
vulnerability now I can browse files I
can do PWD I can do LS I can do ID and I
can pretty much do anything I want on
the server now that I have full shell
access so we were able to convert a
local file inclusion vulnerability that
can only show you files or can only
allow you to read files on the server we
were able to convert that and exploit it
to get full access to the target server
all is that possible because we were
able to write to the proc self and viren
variable which displays our user agent
and by changing the user agent to our
PHP code we were able to run any PHP
code that we want
and this lecture we're going to see
another method of exploiting local file
inclusion vulnerabilities and gain full
shell or full control over the target
server so in the previous video we seen
how to do it using the environ variable
or environment variables and in this
lecture we're going to see how to do it
based on the logs these servers have a
lot of log files and basically at the
moment we can read any file on the
server as long as we have permissions to
read it so if we can manage to write
anything to any of these files then we
can pretty much execute code and gain
control over our target e so what you
need to do is you need to try and read
any of the log files and see or think of
a way to interact with these log files
so that you can write stuff on it for
example if the log files that you're
reading or interacting with our mail log
files then maybe you can send an email
with a code and then it will show up in
the log file in our example we're going
to be using the VAR log auth dot log and
this file contains all the login
attempts to the target server so let's
do it and you'll have a better
understanding at the moment now I just
have the basic is exploit and I'm trying
to show etc' password so this is the
file that we used in our basic exploit
I'm just going to remove that and I'm
going to look for var
log
off that log
now as you can see the file is readable
and we can read login attempts to the
target server so what we're going to do
we're going to think now this file
displays all login attempts so why not
try to log in and see if the attempt
will be displayed here so I'm going to
do here I'm just going to try to SSH
into the server so I'm going to use SSH
SSH is just a lot of remote login
service that is used by web servers
pretty much every web server has it
installed so we're gonna try to SSH into
it so we're gonna do SSH and then we're
gonna put the username and I'm just
gonna put a random username that
probably doesn't even exist I just want
to see if this request will be recorded
in the log file so I'm just SS I'm gonna
SSH and I'm just going to put a username
as random
and then I'm gonna do ad and we're gonna
put the IP address which is 10 2014 to
and I'm going to hit enter
now it's asking me for a password
obviously this username doesn't exist
anyway so I'm just going to put a random
password as well
and I'm not really trying to hack use an
SSH I'm literally just attempting to
login I'm gonna ctrl C now and I want to
see if this will be logged in this file
so I'm gonna send another request
and I'm gonna look for my username so
the username was called random and I'll
see if that was logged
and you can see here it's telling us in
the log file so it was recorded in the
server that someone tried to login with
the username random and it actually has
my IP address so it's actually recorded
my IP address as well so now we can read
that file and we can also write to the
file by logging in with a non-existing
account so what I'm gonna do now is I'm
actually gonna try to log in again
and instead of put in a user name
instead of putting it the user name as
random I'm actually gonna put the PHP
code that we always used to give me a
reverse shell or reverse connection on
this server now again you can use any
PHP code you want in my example I'm
gonna use code that will give me reverse
shell on the target computer so before I
run the code I'm gonna listen on the
port and I'm gonna do that using netcat
like we always did so it's going to be
net cat
VV LP
and I'm gonna put my my part which is
eight eight eight eight
and now we're listening for connections
and I'm going to try to log in again to
the target and in this case I'm actually
gonna put my PHP code so same code that
we used before so my username is going
to be I'm gonna put two quotes and then
I'm gonna put my PHP code
so we're using pass-through
and then we're gonna pass the command
the PHP command that we want to run and
that command is going to be I'm going to
use single quotes here and then my
command is going to be netcat e
Ben Sh
I put my IP address which is 10 2014 208
then I'm gonna put the port that I'm
listening on which is 8 8 8 8 now
with this method you're only gonna get
one shot with this code because if you
put the code correct incorrectly the
whole thing is going to break and the
file is not going to be displayed any
more because you have an error in your
code so what I suggest is I'm going to
keep the pass through as it is because
that's a safe function and I'm sure that
this is gonna run correctly I just need
I forgot to put a semicolon here so I'm
gonna put that there
so I'm sure that this code is gonna run
correctly but I have a lot of minuses in
here I have a lot of spaces and I have a
lot of forward slashes which always have
problems when you're trying to pass them
between the next commands you can try to
skip through these characters but what I
suggest is you actually encrypt this
using base 64 and then decrypt it at the
other end so I'll show you how to do
that first off I'm gonna copy this
command so this is the Dashell command
that we want the pass through function
to run i'm copied it i'm gonna go to my
burps ooh
and I'm gonna go to my decoder here we
never had a look on the decoder so this
tab allows you to encode and decode text
to different types of encoding so I'm
gonna paste what I copied and I'm gonna
encode it as base64
so this text the netcat been sh my IP
port is converted to this encrypted code
I'm going to copy this code
and I'm gonna substitute it here into my
command so instead of running it like
this instead of putting the text I'm
gonna put the base64 code to make sure
that there is no special characters that
would interfere with the command with
the bash
so I have that copied now if I run this
this way so I have my pass-through which
is a PHP function and I'm telling it to
execute this shell command now if
obviously if you copy this text and run
it it's not going to run anything
because it's just gibberish so I need to
tell it that this is base64 code and I'm
gonna do that using the PHP function
called base64 decode so I'm going to
tell it to decode this sister this piece
of text and then once you decode it run
the pass-through on it so I'm just going
to type it in here so it's going to be
very 64
decode and that's just another function
a PHP function and then I'm going to put
the brackets
so I'm just gonna make this a little bit
bigger so we can talk about it more and
I'm just actually gonna copy it and run
it again just so that we will talk about
it a little bit more
okay so first off we're actually using
the username as our code as the code
that we want to inject cus because as we
seen the username is being displayed on
the lock page so anything we put in the
username will be executed as PHP code so
we have that between two quotes here
between this and this quote now we have
our PHP code that we always used and we
also always used the pass-through
function to run Unix commands on the
target server so we're keeping that the
exact same and we're telling it to run
this text but before you run this text I
want you to decode it based on base64 so
we have passed through decode the
following code and this is the code so
this is the command the netcat command
that we always use we're decoding it
based on base64 and then we're telling
it to run it using the pass-through
function to execute it as a bash command
so I'm gonna hit enter now and that'll
ask me for a password because it thinks
that this is actually a username so
we're injecting the whole thing as a
username so I'm just gonna put any
password anything random hit enter now
this should be stored now in the logs so
this code should have been injected into
the auth dot log so we're going to go
back now to our browser and you can see
that I'm already listening here so I'm
just gonna hit enter here on the browser
and as you can see we got a connection
back from our target website and if we
do ID you'll see that arm into the
target website with www data user name
or user group and I can run commands or
do whatever I want on the target server
this is just some another method of
exploiting local file inclusion
vulnerabilities to get a shell on the
target computer now again this is just
an idea and you can try these ideas with
different types of log files so you can
try it with the auth dot log you can try
it with any other type of log files but
you need to think about it you need to
think how you could inject code into
that log file so for example as I said
if it's a mail servers and then try to
send it an email if it's the auth dot
log like we have in this current example
then try to log in using SSH and see if
you can inject code and if that code
will be executed on the target computer
remote file inclusion is a special case
of file inclusion vulnerabilities we
seen in the previous video how we were
able to include any file in the server
and have access to it through local file
inclusion vulnerabilities in today's
video if the server is configured to
allow a certain function called allow
URL and allow URL F open then we will be
able to include any file from any
computer into the target web site so
will literally be able to inject any PHP
file into the target computer what this
would lead to is basically it will we
can run payloads we can run reverse
shells and we can run even system
commands and get access to the targets
or full control to the target server so
first of all let's just go here and
we'll be using the same file inclusion
vulnerability that we were using in the
previous video so it's in the page
parameter right here the only difference
is you need to enable the function that
makes this that converts the local file
inclusion to a remote file inclusion so
hence the name local allows you to
access local files remote would allow
you to access and inject remote files so
to enable that I'm gonna go to my
Metasploit able machine I'm just going
to show you how to enable it so you can
test this vulnerability yourself so
we're coming here to our Metasploit
table and i'm gonna go into the PHP
settings so the PHP settings are stored
in a file and to access that we're gonna
use nano which is a text editor and then
I'm gonna put the file location which is
an et Cie PHP 5tg I and PHP dot ini' so
that's the location where the PHP
configuration is stored I'm going to
open it using a file editor called nano
and I'm just going to exit this I'm
going to open it as pseudo as the route
actually in Cali we never needed to use
sudo because we log in as root but with
MIT exploitable you need to use sudo
when you want to do root actions so you
say sudo and then you put the command
that you want to run okay so these are
the configurations for the PHP that's
installed on the web server on the
target and we're looking for a function
called allow your LF open so I'm gonna
type in ctrl + W at the same time and
that will allow me to search and I'm
gonna search for
hello URL
and we can see here that I have allow
you our LFO print is on and allow URL
include is on as well so these two
functions if they're enabled then the
local file inclusion vulnerability that
we have can be used as a remote file
inclusion
so to exit this control an egg's and
it's gonna ask you if you want to save
just type in Y and enter for me I didn't
change anything so I didn't need to do
that once you do that you need to
restart your web server so you're gonna
do e TC and add dot d
Apache to restart and you'll need to do
this as sudo actually and this is done
now so everything should be ready for
you
just like we did before in the last
video we put five times back and then we
put a TC password to access the password
file what we're going to do today is
we're going to try to access a file
located on a different server so if
you're doing this pen test on an actual
web server then you need to store the
file that you want to access needs to be
stored on a place with a real IP address
or with a domain name I'm doing this on
my local server so I'm gonna store this
on the on the web server on the callee
machine on the 10 2014 203 this is 10
2014 2 O 4 and I'm gonna store my file
on 10 2014 2 or 3 so that file as I said
can be anything it could be a web shell
it could be a payload well what I'm
going to do is I'm going to create a
very simple PHP file so this is just the
PHP start and end of the file and what
I'm gonna put in the file I'm gonna use
a a function called pass-through and in
that function basically what this
function does it executes operating
system commands so it executes Windows
Linux or depending on the web server
it's going to execute commands related
to that so you put the command here
between the two quotation marks and I'm
going to use the same command we used
with the code execution vulnerability
which was the netcat command which
allowed us to get a connection a reverse
connection from our target so I'm gonna
paste that here so let's just first have
a look at this so PHP and the end these
are just the start and the end of the
file of the PHP file pass-through is a
function that I'm going to use which
executes any command that's inserted
between the quotations and I'm using the
same command that we used in the command
execution vulnerability which will just
do a reverse connection to my computer
so this is all good now the next step is
the most important step and it's storing
this file so as I said if your target
was a remote web server then you should
be storing this file in a place with a
real IP where you
can access it from the remote web server
now I'm gonna be axe trying to access
this from my Metasploit able machine
which is able to access files stored on
the county machine because they're both
on the same network and I'm gonna be
calling this I'm going to be starting it
in my VAR www HTML so it's starting is
being stored on the callee not on the
Metasploit able and I'm gonna call it
reverse and I'm gonna save it as txt not
PHP and I'm doing this if I started as a
PHP it's going to be executed on the
callee machine so it's gonna create a
reverse connection from the callee
machine and I don't want that I don't
want to have to Cali machine I actually
already have access to the Cali machine
the one that I wanna hack is the
Metasploit able machine and that one is
stored remotely so in order to be able
to include the a PHP code and execute it
on the remote machine we're gonna use it
as txt and get it executed on the
Metasploit able machine instead of
executed on my Cali
so I'm stalling it as a txt and I'm
gonna say save it and now let's just see
here so if I go to my local host and if
I say reverse the txt we'll see our file
right here so again this is on my local
host which is not the MIT exploitable
machine it's 10 2014 2 O 3 and the
Missis ploy devil is on 204
so how are we gonna run this first let
me just listen for connections like we
did before so it's just going to be
netcat the v LP 8080 and then right here
and setup including a file on the same
server I'm gonna include a remote file
and the command is going to be HTTP so
it's just going to be the link to this
file so it can access the file here as
txt I'm gonna copy it and paste it here
and also in some cases you might need to
add a question mark to the end to get
this file to be executed as PHP so I'm
just going to go over this again for one
more time including a remote file which
is on a remote server
make sure the remote server is
accessible by your target and also make
sure you stir it as txt because if you
keep it as PHP this file the reverse
file would be executed on the remote
server so it will be executed on the 203
and instead of being executed on the 204
and I'm keeping it as txt this way it
will be get it's gonna be executed on
the 204 and it's gonna give me a remote
connection to this computer to the
Metasploit able computer so if I come
back here as you can see we have a
remote connection if we do a you name a
you'll see that this is the Metasploit
able machine not the Cali machine so we
basically have full access to the
Metasploit able machine through and a
remote file inclusion vulnerability now
if we do an LS we can do a PWD to see
where we are and we can literally run
and in the next command we want now on
the machine and do anything we want
basically we have full access to that
machine
right so now that we managed to get a
remote shell from our target computer
let's see if we can do the same and use
the same exploit with medium security so
I'm gonna cancel this
and I'm going to go to the security
level
and I'm gonna set that to medium
submitted and we're gonna go back to our
file inclusion vulnerability I'm gonna
listen on the same part exactly like we
did in the last video and I'm gonna use
the exact same way to get back the shell
so we're just gonna put the txt file
that contains the code for the reverse
connection
so that's our file and we run it and as
you can see we get nothing here and we
get an error message so what's happened
here is it could be that the exploit is
patched or maybe they're using some sort
of filtering
you can try and play around with the
code now obviously they can't really
filter based on your name because you
know you can have any name in here they
can't really filter on dots because
again you can have dots and file names
like the file that they had originally
is the original file is called include
those PHP so again they can't really
have filter on the dots so the things
that would should raise flags for you is
the forward slash which is highly
unlikely because again forward slashes
are used a lot and the HTTP because
usually you wouldn't have HTTP in your
url after the first HTTP so what I'm
gonna use is I'm just gonna try and put
instead of normal T's I'm gonna put
capital T's
so instead of hates maltese malti I have
HTTP but the two T's in there are
capital and if I hit enter now you'll
see that I got my connection right here
and again I have full access to the
server where I can do whatever I want
now obviously this is happening because
the way that they're securing this is
not right and we'll never talk about
security in an in a future lecture so I
just want to show you the code now
though just a quick look I usually don't
show the code and as you can see here
they're actually looking for HTTP and
HTTPS and they're replacing that with
nothing so that's why when we use
capital T's we were able to bypass this
filter so always using filters is never
a good idea because filters can always
be Piper bypassed
the third type of vulnerability that we
looked at was the file inclusion and we
looked at two types the local file
inclusion which allowed us to include
any file on the system and then read
files which will cause a file disclosure
vulnerability and then you'd be able to
read any file on the server and then we
looked at the remote file inclusion
which is very dangerous which allowed us
to include any file from any web server
so we were able to include PHP shells
and then get connection from the target
computer to prevent this first of all
make sure you prevent the remote file
inclusion so just in case anything goes
wrong people can't include files from
outside your server and you can do that
the same way we enabled it using the PHP
on e by disabling the allow your LF open
and allow URL include and if we go here
to our MIT exploitable I'll just show
you very quick so if we do sudo nano
which is the text editor ATC PHP CGI PHP
that I need the same file that we used
this is the file for the PHP settings if
you open that file and now I'm going to
do ctrl W and look for allow URL
and you want to make sure that the allow
URL F open is set to OFF and allow your
l included is set to off as well
control X Y and enter and that'll save
it for you
the other way to prevent these exploits
is to use static file inclusion so
instead of using dynamic file inclusion
which we see in you can hard code the
files that you want to include in the
code and not get them using get or post
for example what's happening in the
examples we see in the vulnerable
examples is we have a page called page
or index dot PHP and then this index dot
PHP takes a parameter called page and
then it takes another page for example
News dot PHP and it includes this News
PHP in the code so what's the code look
like in the PHP code you'll see
something like include
so what this will do basically and that
looks like this I believe what this do
it includes whatever comes after the
page parameter so the code will
dynamically takes whatever that comes in
after the page parameter and includes it
in the current page so this will be in
the index dot PHP page okay this is very
bad because even if it's not yet
sometimes people use post and in post
you won't see this so it will be posted
but you can use a proxy such as burp
proxy and this would look like that and
then you can modify it and get it to
include anything you want and then it's
displayed on the page what we really
want to do is we want the user not to be
able to manipulate with what's going to
be included so if you wanted to include
a page called news dot PHP just include
it inside this without giving the user
the ability to change it I know you're
gonna program your code to just have it
looking like this but the users we know
we see how users can play with this and
just get it to include anything they
want so the best way to do it is just to
get it to include page dot PHP so your
code is not using any variables it's
it's hard-coded it might make your code
log longer but it's much more secure
and this is exactly what the
high-security option does so let's go
back to the file inclusion first and
we're at the low and if I viewed the
source now you'll see that basically
file is what you pass to it so file is
what we pass to it in here and the after
the page parameter and you can see that
it tries to display anything that we
send it so when we send it a TC password
it shows us the e TC password now I'm
actually going to keep this open and I'm
gonna go to the security level to the
security and I'm gonna set it to high
now the medium is the is similar to the
know so you can actually use the same
you can exploit it the same way that we
exploited the low so we're going to the
high straightaway and we're going to
view the source
and I'm just going to minimize this
because they have the two sources now so
we can compare them
so as you can see here and the low and
medium security level you can see that
anything we passed the file by a
variable it will be displayed to us
whereas in here at the high security
level you can see that it is hard-coded
that it is only allowed to show us the
include dot PHP file so you can you can
modify this if statement if you had a
number of files that you wish to include
then you can allow them in here or you
can have them in a list but basically
the concept is you only allow the files
that the user is allowed to see so you
can just have them in a list here you
can use an or statement or you can just
have a list and say if the file is in
this list then display it otherwise give
an error saying the file is not found so
avoid this go with the hard-coded method
yes it doesn't look as pretty as this
but it's much more secure
you