in this video we'll see how we can get
comprehensive DNS information about the
target website so just to give you a
quick refresh on what DNS is so when you
type in facebook.com a DNS server will
convert that name to an IP address now
the process is a bit more complicated so
the DNS server contains actually a
number of records each point into a
different domain or a to be out or to a
different IP sometimes to the same IP so
but in in general you request a domain
name it gets converted to an IP address
and depending on that these information
need to be stored somewhere so we're
going to query this DNS server and see
what information we can get through it
so we're gonna be using a website called
dropped XCOM and i'm just typed in here
i security org so I'm gonna click on go
and I'm gonna select the first result
and we'll have a look now you can see
here we have a nice little index that
will help you navigate through the
information because this report contains
a lot of information now a lot of these
information is a little bit advanced so
I'll be skipping through a lot of it
because I want to keep this as basic as
possible as I said web penetration
testing can't get there like you can do
a full course on that so we're gonna
keep this a little bit basic and we'll
see what information we can see in here
so first of all you can get information
about the website about how well it's
doing here on Alex our ranking and all
that you can see the DNS records so we
can see the name servers here that's
being used we can see some related
websites here you can see a summary and
description of the website we can see
the mail servers here name servers
and the IP address here the records that
I was talking about and the DNS server
here you can see all of these records so
you can see usually the I record is the
one that converts a domain name to an IP
address and if you remember when we were
doing the NS proofing we used to add an
a record in our DNS Kampf in ether Kampf
so we say I security dot org a and then
we directed to our own local machine so
the I record is actually what's used in
the DNS servers to link I security to
this IP address but again there is other
type of records for example we have the
NS record that links the domain the name
server you can also see the MX record
here which links it to the mail server
and we can see the website uses a Google
mail server so it's using Gmail probably
to provide mail services and here we
have a graph of how all of these
services interact with each other how
the services use the records and how
they are translated into IP addresses
and here in the share tab you'll see if
any of these resources are being shared
for example you can see that I security
has two IP addresses this one and this
one you can also see it's using three
name servers we can see the mail servers
here and you can also see here very
important thing is you have a number of
websites pointing to the same ip address
or a number of domain names I should say
pointing to the same IP address so you
can see there's a website called bug
bounty there's a website called Wi-Fi
high security org so these websites are
stored on the same web server now again
there is more information about the name
servers websites that are used in the
same mail server doesn't mean the
these websites are on the same server
but what the most important thing is
here you have the websites pointing to
the same IP which means that these
websites exist on the same server so you
literally if you gain access to this
website it will be very easy to gain
access to our security dot-org now
scrolling down you'll see a map with all
the servers that are being used by IEEE
security so for example here let me zoom
out so for example here click on this
you'll see that an s-1 dimming of calm
which is one of the name servers is in
America another one here and we have the
mail servers in here there's also more
information about contact information
here so you have the DNS for a cloud
fair and for a dim know for you can
contact the admins of these services and
you can also get a who's lookup from
here but the database has been exhausted
for this website here but you can
usually get whose lookup through Rob
takes calm so again this website gives
you more in-depth look at the DNS
records and the DNS configuration and
how domains how this website is related
to other domains on the Internet in this
lecture I'd like to highlight a very
important note when it comes to website
penetration testing websites are
installed on web servers on normal
computers like we said before these
normal computers have IP addresses and
using the IP address we can access our
target website now in many scenarios
your target website will or your target
server will contain a large number of
websites so it will have the website
that you're looking for that you're
targeting but it will also contain other
websites on the same server so on the
same file system what this means is if
you for example could not find any
vulnerable
and your target website you can try to
hack into any other website that is
installed on the same server if you
could do that then you'll be able to
gain access to the server gaining access
to the server basically means you have
access to all the other websites because
the server is just a computer and you
can literally just navigate to the
website that you want to hike and gain
access to that website so if you're
trying to hack into a website and you
couldn't find any exploits then the next
step will be trying to like any other
website that exists on the same server
so when what I mean by exist on the same
server is they have the same ip address
so let me show you here an example I'm
gonna be showing an example of Zaid
comms on my blog because there is a lot
of websites on the same server and if we
look here on Rob text calm and I came
down here to names pointing to the same
IP address you can see all of these
websites exist on the same server as
Zaid com so if you could manage to hack
into any of these websites you'll be
able to navigate from out of that
website and then into z.com
and then gain full access to my website
so let me just show you here if I copy
any of these domain names for example we
have this one rebadow at me and I'm just
gonna go onto my terminal
now I've already if I do a ping
z.com you'll see that this is my IP
address of my website and if I do a ping
on one of the websites that exists and
it's for an hour using Reba dot me so if
I go pink Reba that mean you see that
both websites have the same ip address
this means that both websites are
installed on the same computer and if we
could hack into one of them we can
literally just navigate from that
website into the other from our
meterpreter shell or from our PHP shell
or any type of shell that were using
another way of finding websites on the
same domain is using Bing and it's a
really simple way so if you just go on
being
and I'm just gonna put IP and then I'll
put the IP of my target website again
you'll see all the other websites that
exist on the same server as your target
website so you can literally hack into
any of these websites and from there
hack into my website and gain access to
it this is very important because in
many cases your target could be very
well secured but the server itself is
not secure so you can manage to hack one
of the other websites and then navigate
through the server to your target
in today's lecture we're going to talk
about sub domains subdomains we've seen
them everywhere for example they can win
as subdomain dot target com
so for example you'd have beta dot
facebook.com you'd have mobile dot
facebook.com or you might have user dot
facebook.com so for example in Google
you have mail.google.com which basically
just takes you to Gmail why subdomains
are important is a lot of the cases some
websites have sub sub domains for their
own users for example for the employees
or for certain customers so they're not
advertised unless you're some sort of a
VIP customer or if you are an employee
you will not see these subdomains on
search engines and you'll just never see
a link leading to them so they might
contain foreign abilities or exploits
that will help you gain access to the
whole website but you just never knew
about them because they're not
advertised another thing is a lot of the
big websites when they're trying to
install a new update or add a new
feature to the website they install it
in a subdomain so you'd have beta that
facebook.com actually contains a beta
version of Facebook which contains still
experimental features now experimental
features are great because they're still
under development and there is a really
high chance of finding exploits in them
and this is actually true not so long
ago someone was able to brute-force the
restore password key for any Facebook
user and was able to gain access to any
Facebook user and this was only possible
through the beta dot facebook.com
because facebook.com used to check for a
number of attempts or wrong attempts and
they just didn't implement that security
feature in the beta because they just
didn't think anyone's gonna go there or
for any reason like the beta usually
contains more problems than the normal
website so it would be very useful to
try and hack into it
so in today's lecture we will see how we
can find any sub domains that have not
been advertised or even the advertised
ones so we'll be able to get sub domains
of our target we're going to use a tool
called knock the tool is very simple you
don't really need to install it all you
have to do is download it using git
command so the command is going to be
get clone and then you put the URL of
the tool and that's it it's downloaded
now so I'm going to navigate to it using
the CD command and we'll see that we
have the PI file here and I'm going to
run it using the command Python
knocked out py and then I'll put the IP
at our the website that I want to get
the subdomains off and it's going to be
I security water
and this will show you some information
about the website first and then it'll
do a brute force and a Google based
subdomain search for I security so it
will show me any subdomain that I
security might have so that I could try
and test the security of that subdomain
and see what's installed on it maybe
I'll be able to gain access to the
website through that subdomain okay so
the scan is complete now and as you can
see we managed to find seven subdomains
that were not advertised so one of them
is FTP the high security org I security
dot all of you already know about this
this is just the local subdomain we can
see that the mail server has its own sub
domain as well and we can see a very
interesting one here news that I secured
if the org this was this actually did
contain a beta version of a script that
we were working on and you see crypt and
at the moment now if you go to it it's
actually converted and it'll just take
you to the actual web site because the
scripts is out of development but now if
you go and use that I security org if
you'll just tell you that this has been
moved to the main website and then if
you click here you'll go to the main
website with the script installed so if
someone was trying to hack into our
website and did this they'll actually
see that there is a script under
development and there's a high chance
that they would have been able to find a
vulnerability in it and gain access to
the whole website so this just shows you
how important information gathering gaze
again which can be used to really gain
access to websites or if you don't do it
you'd be missing a lot of things for
example you might be missing a whole
script with a whole number of
vulnerabilities or you could be missing
an admin login page or an employee login
page which is used for admins or
employees to login
so far we learned how to find any
subdomains that exist within our target
web site and that have not been listed
in today's lecture we're going to see
how we can find files and directories
that are stored on our target computer
or our target web site again this could
be useful because these files could
contain passwords they could contain
config information or they could contain
information about this actual server
which will help us further exploit our
target let me just first show you what I
mean by files and directories just to
show you the structure of directories on
a web server so here I have my
exploitable machine and as we know
usually the web server stuff is stored
in var www and if I do an LS you'll see
or I'll do I never sell a just so that
it's nicer you'll see that we have a
number of files and directories and we
can see that we have a directory there
called Matilda Matilda is a web is a web
application that is designed to be
hacked
just like net exploitable it is designed
so that it has a number of exploits so
that we can learn how to hack based on
it so we can see that that's installed
in a directory called Matilda now if I
go here to my IP address now this is the
IP address of the Metasploit Abel
machine so if I do and if configure
you'll see that it's 10 2014 204 so I'm
in there
and you can see that they have an easy
access for me for Mattel a day if I
click it look at the URL here
so it's forward slash Mozilla day that
means I'm inside the metal add a
directory so every time you see a
forward slash that usually means you're
inside a directory so let's go back here
do an LS and if I do CD Mattila day I'm
gonna do an LS and you'll see that I
have a large number of files a large
number of files here so let's say for
example I wanted to open one of these
files and we have index dot PHP if I do
index dot PHP
then this is our current file it's
called index dot PHP so what we learned
from this is Nutella Day is just a
directory inside my web root so at the
moment in the Metasploit abel device i
mean let me just write it here for you
salmon var www
Mattila day
and then the file that I'm accessing is
index dot PHP
okay so I hope this is clear now so I'm
in this directory and this directory and
I'm accessing a file called index dot
PHP so if I just do a PWD here you'll
see that I'm in bar www masala date
the IP address kind of hides where your
www route is so it hides the VAR www and
then any everything after that will be
displayed here after the IP address so
what we're looking to find today is all
the directories and the files that we
cannot see so throughout these links we
will be able to access different types
in different pages this is the same with
any other website but there is always
files and directories hidden that you
just never see so we'll see how we can
get URLs for these files and access them
and read the information in it to do
that we're going to use a tool called
Deb and to see how to use that tool
we're gonna do man there to see all the
options associated with that tool so you
can see that to use the tool you just
type in Derb the URL of your target and
then you put a word list so the way this
works is it works based on a brute force
attack and it just uses a word list of
names and it sends requests with these
names and any time it actually finds
something it tells us that oh I finally
I found a file with this name so to only
be able to find names and directories
based on the word list that you provide
now you can create a word list using
crunch or you can use word lists that
come in within them the options here
allow you to configure how the tool is
going to work so you can change things
around the way you want it for example
you can disable the recursive nests of
the tool so it just runs on one
directory instead of trying and abroad
directories
you can get it to ask you a few if you
wanted to access the directory or not
instead of with automatically accessing
directories and trying to find files
within these directories because this
could be exhaustive if your target is a
big website there might be a lot of
directories and then the tool will be
trying to access all of them and find
files within all of them so you can see
how how big the tree could go you can
also set it to use a username and a
password
if the target websites use this some
sort of authentication and we can use
Vivi for verbose output and you can also
use O to output the results to a file so
let me show you a very simple example of
it I'm just gonna run there
on our target which is 10 2014 204 and
that should be HTTP
because remember we're targeting a
website not an IP address
then I'm gonna put the directory that I
want to be that I want to find files and
directories within I don't want it to be
accessing anything within other because
we can see here there is a number of
scripts installed on this web server so
we have this script and we also have PHP
myadmin
and we have Tiki Wicki so we don't want
it to be accessed in all of them we only
want it to be working on Mattila day on
this example so that's why I'm only
using this URL and then it's gonna start
finding URLs and files within this
particular web application so I'm gonna
hit enter and we're gonna let it to work
so this is going to use a word list file
and it's using a default small word list
file that is stored in here so it's in
user shared their word lists common dot
txt you can have a look at this
directory and see if there is any other
word list that you'd like to use and you
can use them only by placing the full
path to the word list after the command
so instead of the way I wrote the
command you'd write it like this and
then you'd state where your word list is
for example let's say if it's in route
you stated as root word list dot txt or
whatever but at the moment its uses the
default one which is stored in this
directory and users shared their word
lists and so using the one that's called
common txt so we can see here from the
result it was able to find a number of
files some of them we already know of
now the favicon is just an icon footer
and header these are probably only style
files index is the index that we see
usually so it's alright
login we can see that we discovered a
page that allows people to log in now in
many scenarios I was able to find user
name and password of a target exploiting
a really complex exploit and then ended
up not being able to login because I
couldn't find where to login so tools
like this could be very useful and here
we can see that we have a login page
that we can use to log in page not phone
never is not very useful you can see the
PHP info file now this file is usually
very very useful because it displays a
lot of information about the PHP
interpreter running on the web server
and as you can see this file contains a
lot of information a lot of them are
useful now you can see you get to know
some of the directories you know that
it's running php5 the configuration is
stored in this file any files is usually
the config files for PHP so you can see
all the places where they're stored I'm
going down you'll see all the
permissions they installed we can see
here it has MySQL so it's using MySQL
and you can see the directories where
different types of configurations are
stored you can also see all the modules
and extensions that are being used with
PHP so this file is usually very very
useful
see we managed to find where the PHP my
admin login is and that's basically the
login that's used to log into the
database
another very useful file is the
robots.txt and that is the file that
tells search engines such as Google how
to deal with the website so it usually
contains files that we don't want the
website or Google to see or to read so
if we can read that file then we'll be
able to see what what the web admin is
trying to hide
so going in here we can see that the web
admin doesn't want Google to see a
directory called passwords okay
and it also doesn't want it to see a
file called config in
and all it also doesn't wanted to see
these other files so let's have a look
on the passwords and the config dot ink
as examples so I'm just going to open a
new tab and we're going to put our
address like so
so it's the current directory and then
we just put passwords after in that we
can see that there's a file called I can
still txt and going here we can see that
we got some usernames and passwords so
we can see there is admin admin pass we
can see that we have a password as
Adrian and some password
so we managed to find user names and
passwords now we're still not sure what
these usernames and passwords for but
we're sure that we were able to find
very useful stuff another useful file is
the config dot Inc so let's see what's
in that and from here we can see that we
have information that allow us to
connect to the database because these
are saying DB hellos DB user DB path and
name so we can see that the username is
root and the password is blank so we can
go ahead and try to connect to the
database based on these commands and
then we should be able to get access to
that database also using these passwords
we're still not sure what we can use
them for but we can add them to a list
try to login to the admin or just start
them in a list so that we can use it if
we're going to do any brute force attack
so then again this is another video that
just shows how important and powerful
information gathering can be in this
lecture we're gonna have a look on a
tool called multi go multigo is a
program that allow us to gather
information about pretty much everything
you can gather information about people
using their name their phone their email
you can gather information about
websites servers anything really we're
gonna focus on gathering information
about websites but as I said you can use
it to gather information about anything
so we're going to go to cadie and we're
gonna go to all programs here and I'm
going to type in multi go and that's
right here now the first time you run
the program it's actually gonna ask you
to create a new username and password
for the program I've already done that
so you can just do it good click next
next next create a new username and a
password and then just log in so once
you do that you'll see this and this is
the main screen of the program now right
here on the right you'll see some
plugins or additions that you can add to
the
these additions allow you to gather
different types of information so if you
wanted to install any of these additions
for example let's say we wanted to
install the passive total tool then all
we have to do is just click on the
install click yes and that will install
it for you now I'm just doing this just
to show you but let's go ahead and
create a new blank page and we'll see
how we can use it use this to gather
information so this is the main view of
multigo and here in the middle you have
your graph where you can put your
entities and track how you gather the
information on the Left we have the
palette where you can add entities and
gather information about them and you
can see that we can add any type of
entity for example we can add a person
using their name their email address or
their phone number you can also add
people based on social networks for
example you can add a Facebook account a
Twitter account and start gathering
information from there but what we are
interested in too is a website so we're
going to start by adding a domain name
from here so I'm gonna click and drag
that to my main view right here and when
you add that in here you can see that on
the right right here you can modify the
attributes of this entity and on the
left you can run transformers so I'll
get back to transform transformers in a
second for now let's first modify the
domain name and I'm gonna use a domain
that I actually have permission to test
its security and its eye security
dot-org
so now I can run transformers that allow
me to gather information about this
domain from the left from here by
clicking on the play button or I can
right-click it and run a transformer so
I'm just going to go to the home screen
right here and what I'm gonna do is
right here you can see that we have the
Transformers categorized into different
categories and you can click the play
button right here so you can see that
there is actually a double play button
here and that will run all the
Transformers inside this specific
category if you click on the category
itself you'll see the specific
Transformers that you can run so for
example I have a DNS or a domain right
here and I want to see the websites
associated with that domain so I'm going
to run the transformer to a website
based on search engine and that will
show me the websites associated with
this domain name and right here you can
see that we have three websites we have
www-why security dot org and we have eye
security org now these two websites are
the same so I'm going to delete one of
them I'm just going to click it and
delete it so that our graph looks better
now let's see what other information we
can get from this so I'm going to right
click it again and let's see and try to
get all the subdomains that exist within
this domain so we're gonna track it to
name schema and again I'm going to click
on the play button right here and now we
have more websites we have news that I
security org we have eye security Ozark
which is a shame essentially the same as
this so I'm going to delete this one
and we have after FTP dot I security dot
org and mail that I security dot org so
now if we have FTP information we know
we can connect to it based or through
this web this subdomain
now again all these websites are
associated or stored on the same server
so we can go ahead and try to hack into
one of these and gain access to our main
website or you can use them to gain
access to our main server basically
all of these transformers you can run
them the same way so I'm not gonna go
over all of them let's just have a look
on one more which is the MX record and
what this will do it will see the mail
servers that the target website uses and
we can see that they're using Google to
handle their mail so again this is very
important because for example if there
was a certain vulnerability in Google or
in the mail server that they're using
then we can exploit that to gain access
to their emails and maybe use that to
gain access to the website so I'm going
to delete the Google servers that we got
because they're no use because I just
want to keep the useful stuff in here we
can use each of these entities now
together even more information about it
again you all you have to do is click it
right click and then run transformers
but we're still not finished with the
domain so I'm going to go back to the
domain and I'm gonna go back to the main
menu and right here we can see that we
can get the domain all in our details so
we can get stuff like the email
addresses we can check for entities from
the user information and we can also
check for phone numbers so I'm gonna go
back and run on the double play right
you can click on the double play to run
all the transformations within this
category now I security is used in
privacy so we won't really get much but
if the target website wasn't used in
privacy then you'll be able to get their
phone numbers their address and very
important information
so again I'm going to delete the useless
stuff right here and we're going to have
a look on one more transformation so
again we're going to go back to the main
menu and we're going to look for files
and documents from this domain and again
I'm working on all transformations
within that category and this will show
me any files or maybe any interesting
files stored on that domain
okay so this finished running and as you
can see we got a lot of files now a lot
of these are just PDFs PDF books but
again and in a lot of websites sometimes
you will get files like the password
file or files with sensitive information
so again this could be really really
useful in your information gathering
step okay so now let's see if we can
gather even more information about our
target so I've actually deleted all the
useless files because they weren't any
use and I kept the things that I'd like
to focus on so in a real life situation
you want to go over each one of these
entities and try and gather information
about as much information as you can
about each of them
for now I'm actually going to focus on
the I securities org only and I'm gonna
try to find all the websites that exist
on the same server so like we said
before if we couldn't hack into I
security itself then maybe we can
exploit one of the websites on the same
server and then gain access to I
security so I'm just going to change
this topology from here and use
something useful like this one and then
I'm just gonna drag this one on this
side I should put it down here because
I'm going to be using that and put this
one up okay so I'm going to right-click
it
and I'm gonna get its IP address so I'm
going to resolve it two IP address
and right now as you can see we have the
IP address of the server where I
security dot org is stored on
so I'm going to right-click it
and I'm gonna try to get the DNS
information from this IP address so this
will give me all the websites that exist
on the same server and as you can see
now it automatically changed its
topology for me
and we can see that this IP address to
this
now you can see that this IP address
contains all of these servers now this
server is actually owned by I security
and as you can see that it doesn't have
too many websites so if this was just a
normal website you'll actually see a lot
of websites with it on the same server
but because this is a VPS owned by
security by IEEE security only so it's
only we only have the websites that we
want to have there so it's on the our
website but again we still managed to
get one two three three more websites
and set up our website so in case we
couldn't gain access to this website
then we can go and try to hack into any
of these websites and they're on the
same server so we'll managed to hack
into our target from the websites on the
same server
all of that didn't work we can see that
we have this arrow going into the IP so
usually the IP the websites are hosted
by this IP so you can see the RS going
from the IP to the website here to this
website into this website but right here
we can see that the hosted by to a dim
often dotnet is going to the IP so this
is actually a hosting company and this
is the company that were renting the VPS
from so if we go to this website
you can see that this is a hosting
company it's and that is where I
security is renting their servers from
so in worst case scenarios if you try to
hack into I security you couldn't do it
and then you try to walk into all of
these websites and you can do it and you
looked for exploits and the server
itself and you can do it then you can
try to hack into the data center on the
website or on the company that's hosting
our security and from there you can gain
access to any website hosted hosted by
that company including your target which
is AI security org
now again you can go over any of these
entities and try to gather information
about it as well and maybe get
information that will help you to gain
access to your target for example we can
convert bug bounty to a domain like we
did that with eye security and then from
this domain I'm going to look for email
addresses associated with that domain
and as you can see now we have the abuse
at name.com which is no use but we also
managed to get an email of a person
working in high security which is they
that I security org that's my actual my
actual personal email
so again if everything failed and you
couldn't gain access to it then maybe
you can try to target that person that
works at high security which is myself
and maybe try to social engineer that
person and hack into their computer and
from there again gain access to the
website now this is going to get into
social engineering so I'm not gonna get
into too much detail that because now
we're talking about web penetration
testing so we're only concerned about
the web applications and this technology
is used in that
in this lecture we're going to have a
look on file upload vulnerabilities
these are the simplest type of
vulnerabilities because they allow us to
upload any type of file so for example
if the target computer can understand
PHP then we can upload any PHP file or a
PHP shell and get full control over the
target computer now if the target
computer or the target server
understands Python or any other language
then you can just upload Python code
Python shell or ruby shell you can
create these shells using will evasion
or Metasploit or you can use your own
PHP or Python shell what we're going to
do today we're going to have a look on a
tool called weave Lee that generates PHP
shells and allow us to gain access and
do a number of cool things on the target
computer so first of all I have my DB WI
here and usually when you're trying to
pan test a website what I recommend is
before trying to use any tools or
anything after you do your information
gathering is you just go in and try to
browse the website see you see what you
can see just get a feel of the website
see what's installed on it and all that
and try to exploit any features you see
so for example let's say you went on
everything and then you reach the upload
we can see that this website allow us to
upload a file now this sometimes in in
your penetration testing tasks it could
be a website that's allowing you to
upload a profile picture a picture if
it's a classified website maybe chopped
allowing you to upload pictures of cars
or whatever you're trying to add in the
website so as you can see here the
website expects you to choose an image
and upload an image so let's see if we
can upload an image first so I'm gonna
go on my downloads and I have a picture
here in the resources just a picture of
a car I'm gonna upload it and see if it
gets uploaded and we can see that the
upload was successful and it starred in
this particular location so it's dot dot
dot dot which is
means two directories back and then this
file name so let's see if we picture has
actually been uploaded so I'm taking
away two directories I'm taking away the
vulnerabilities and upload I'm going to
using that and then we're gonna get this
location on the server just to see if
the picture was uploaded properly and as
you can see the picture has been
uploaded so that's all good now the next
thing we want to do let's try and upload
a PHP file and to do that we're going to
use a tool called weave me as I said to
create a payload or a shell if you go if
you want to call it and it's obviously
is going to be a PHP shell you can use
Metasploit as I said to create a PHP
payload but we're gonna be just having a
look on a different tool that's designed
for web application penetration testing
so the tool is very easy we're gonna put
the tool name which is we've Lee and
then we're going to put generate because
we want to generate a payload or a shell
file then we will put a password for
that file so that only us can access it
and control the website when we upload
it to the website so my password is
gonna be one two three four five six and
then I'm gonna say what I want to store
it and I want to start it in root and
I'm gonna call it shell dot PHP so very
simple we've Lee is the name of the
program generate is to generate a shell
the password that the shell is going to
authenticate us with and it's going to
be stored in root shell dot PHP I'm
gonna hit enter and created now if I am
already in my root so if I just do LS I
should see it and we can see it right
here so the next thing is we're just
going to go back to our website and try
to upload that shell
and I'm gonna look for a shell and here
it is
can I have an upload and as you can see
now it's telling me the file has been
uploaded successfully and it's in the
same place that the picture was so all
we need to do now is we're going to use
the same link and we're gonna use Weebly
again to interact with that shell that
we uploaded now let's first of all see
if the shell exists and it's been
uploaded properly so I'm just going to
browse it through my browser shell those
PHP and you can see that you get a blank
page so we're not getting 404 file not
found which means that the file has been
uploaded and it's there so we're going
to try to interact with it from we've ly
to connect to it we're gonna type in
we've lee and then we're gonna put the
RL where the shell is so this is where
our shell has been uploaded and then
we're gonna put the password so my
password was 1 2 3 4 5 6
very simple Weebly the URL where the
file is and 1 2 3 4 5 6 this is very
simple as similar to when you use your
multi hunt they're waiting for
connections are connected to your back
door so we're literally just going to
connect the back door that we uploaded
and as you can see in our in the file
system
so from Weebly from this place you can
actually just type in any Linux command
and you'll be able it'll be executed on
the target computer and you'll see the
result here so if I do a PWD you'll see
them that I'm invertible uw-w hackable
uploads and if i do an ID
i'll see my user at the moment which is
the vww data and if you do you name I
just confirm that this is the Metasploit
able machine you'll see that this is the
Linux with exploitable machine and now
we can do anything we want you can list
the files we can navigate you can do any
Linux command that you want to do now we
have changed our place has been changed
we've Lee also offers much more features
than just this so it actually allows you
to do a number of cool things if you
type in help you'll see all the cool
stuff that you can do
with Weebly so you can try to escalate
your privileges as execute SQL queries
and a lot of cool stuff that is just
designed for web application penetration
testing for now I'm gonna leave it at
this and this just shows you how to use
file upload vulnerabilities
now before we dig any deeper into how to
exploit and discover vulnerabilities I'd
like to pause and just go back for a
second and see what exactly happens when
a user clicks on a certain link so let's
say you're a browsing a website and you
click on any link on that website what
happens so we have here we have the
client side so this is your the computer
with the HTML website that is displayed
to the user so this this is all loaded
on your computer on the client and then
we have the server which contains the
code that gets executed if the website
is functional and if it uses code so
when you click on a link the HTML
website or the client-side part of the
page of the website will generate a
request so it won't actually do any
computations most of the time now
sometimes there is client-side code and
we'll see that but usually the
client-side code will generate a request
which is sent to the website to the web
server at the web server you'll have
some functional codes such as PHP or
Python Ruby any programming language and
that's most of the time that code
interacts with the database gets some
sort of information and then send the
information as a response to the website
to the browser and the browser will
display it as HTML so the code the the
functional code or the computation code
is usually stored at the server side and
the way that most of these websites work
is they generate a request they send it
to the server the server executes the
request and send it back so when we're
trying to hack into website and exploit
them we usually play with the request
sent and try to modify that request so
that it performs some actions that would
help us to gain information or run some
certain type of code that will give us
reverse connection now there is two type
of requests there is get requests and
post requests
let's have an example so if we go here
on the file inclusion you'll see that we
have a variable called page and the
value of that is include dot PHP so
right here this is a get request because
we can see the values of it in the URL
so we can see that page equals include
dot PHP so this page is requesting
another page to include another page
called index dot PHP now we won't go
into detail of what that means all we're
concerned about is to have an example
and this is the example so this is the
variable that were given a value for
which is page and we're giving it a
value of include dot PHP so that's a get
request an example of a post request is
the file upload so if we go to the file
upload when you upload something in here
so let me just upload something
you see that DRL doesn't get modified
but the request is sent so the web's the
image is actually uploaded on the server
and all that but the URL still looks the
same but the website did send
information so the HTML website did send
information to the server you just
didn't see the information in here
because it was sent as post instead of
get
so the first problem now is we can't see
the post requests we can't modify them
because they're not shown here in the in
the URL in the case of get we can modify
them straight away from the URL another
problem is a lot of these websites in
the future they're going to be used in
security and they're going to be used in
client-side code so if that's used then
the request is actually modified before
it gets sent so there will be filters
and stuff working on the client side
that will modify our code before we send
it so the best way of intercepting
requests and so that we can see the post
requests we're going to use a proxy
the proxy that we're going to be using
is birth proxy now burp is a really big
program that can be used for a lot of
things but we're going to be focusing on
how to use the proxy in this lecture so
we're going to be using the letter D
proxy in a lot of lectures I'm going to
explain how to run it and configure the
browser to use it once and in the future
I'll be skipping through this step I'm
just gonna say I'm gonna run burp proxy
and you should carry out these steps
so how burp is going to work is we have
our client here and we have the web
server just like we seen it before and
we have the HTML website loaded on our
Kali machine so when we send a request
instead instead of sending it directly
to the web browser we're actually going
to configure our browser to send the
request to burp so this is our proxy
running here burp will see all the
parameters that are being posted to the
web site so we're gonna see the post
requests the get requests and we'll see
them after all the client code has been
applied so some web sites apply the
client-side code as I said to the
request before they send it so we're
going to be able to see the requests
after the client-side code has been
applied this is very important because a
lot of websites use filtering as
client-side and then we'll be able to
bypass all of these filters by
intercepting the request then once we
modify the request in burp we're gonna
forward it to the website the website
will execute it and give it back to us
so again we're gonna redirect the
requests to burp modify them here send
them to the website website execute sit
give it back to us now we're going to be
using this a lot in the future and the
idea will become much more clear in the
future so if you don't really get it now
just keep going through the lectures and
I think it will become much more clear
let me show you how to configure burp so
first of all I'm just going to start
burp so you can run it here from the
dock or you can run burp suit from the
terminal
now this is just telling me about some
temp project I had we're just going to
click Next to use a temporary project
and we're going to use the defaults
so we have burp runnin here and as I
said it's a really big suit with a lot
of options what we're interested in the
proxy so we can see that the proxy is
set to on and the most important thing
now is to go on options and you'll see
that the proxy is running on port 8080
okay now I've anything we do here is
still not sensible because we are not
redirecting anything to it yet so we
need to set up this we need to tell our
web browser to send all the requests to
the port that burp is running on so burp
is running on 8080 so now I'm going to
go to my preferences
I'm gonna go on Advanced Network
settings and we're gonna use manual
proxy configuration and we're gonna use
port 8080 and the IP is one two seven
zero zero one exactly like it's in here
in the options I'm gonna click on OK and
now anything I do on this web browser
will be redirected to burp before it
goes to the web site so anything I do
here will be redirected to the proxy I
can modify all the requests and send it
to the web server so let's see how is
this gonna work so I'm gonna go back
here to the intercept and I'm just gonna
click on any link in here so if I just
go for example on the file inclusion
you'll see that burp here has
intercepted a packet and if we go here
on the parameters
you'll see the stuff that perp is
sending so we can see that it's asking
for a page called include dot php' it's
telling that the security should be low
and is sending a PHP SSID
so again on the headers you'll see all
the headers that's being sent and you
can modify any of these values by
double-clicking it so you can modify
this that will click it modify it hit
enter and then once you are done
modifying it you can click on forward
and that will forward the packet and
then the page is displayed here now
we're going to be modifying these things
in the future so right now I'm just
showing you that verb is set up
correctly and in the future we'll be
modifying that let me just show you an
example of a file upload now again if I
click on file upload nothing happens I
have to forward the packet here so you
can see the values that's being sent you
can see the header is here as well and I
have to forward it then the website will
load it here and I have to forward again
and as you can see now it loaded so
let's try to upload an image
and when I click on upload again you'll
see that the website pauses and we can
see all the stuff that's being sent in
here so you can see that the image name
you can see the image type and you can
see all the variables that's being set
as well again this is a post request and
usually you don't see anything in here
in the URL but we can modify the values
in here and then send them again this
might not make much sense now but in the
future once you start learning other
attacks and we'll be using verb you'll
see how useful this can be
once done using burp because now if you
if we closed burp the browser will still
try to redirect the packets to port 8080
where burp is running so if I try to
open anything I will lose my connection
because it's saying the proxy server is
refusing connections because I soft burp
so once you're done with burp go back to
your preferences and make sure that you
use you set up your proxy settings to
not use a proxy so advanced network
settings and then go to no proxy hit OK
and then you should be good to go now if
I do a try again the website works as
well so again this is going to be really
handy to intercept post get and bypass
filters and also bypass any type of
client-side code that gets applied to
the requests made by the website in the
future I'll be doing this very fast and
once I say I'm gonna use burp you should
take it that you need to start burp and
configure your browser to redirect
packets to go through burp
now let's talk about how you can secure
your website from file upload
vulnerabilities
the main thing to keep in mind is that
never allow people to upload executables
there shouldn't be a need for you to
allow people to upload executables
really so stuff like PHP bash scripts
executables like exe come all these
files you should never allow people to
upload them because there is a high
possibility that these files could harm
your server the second thing is you need
to check that the file type is what the
what you want is what you're expecting
and check the extension at the same time
so when we seen when we were checking
with our tests and the previous videos
at the low security level obviously
there was no checks at the medium
security level there was checking for
only the file type and at the high
security level they were checking for
the extension only so what you want to
do really is never allow executables
make sure the uploaded file is what
you're expecting so if you're uploading
an image make sure that the file type is
an image and the and the extension is an
image extension so it's a JPEG or a PNG
or any other image type only and once
you do these two checks so that and that
make sure that you recreate the uploaded
file so you check that the file is an
image and you check that the extension
is an image extension then analyze the
file using some sort of a library so
depending on the program and language
you're using on your server make sure
that you analyze you pass this file to a
library and analyze its content and you
recreate the file to suit your website
now this is actually a good step anyway
because since you're displaying this on
your website you want to make sure that
the images aren't too big and that they
are optimized for web applications so
it's a good thing for your website to
run faster and it's also a good thing to
make sure that this image is actually an
image and it's not harm a harmful file
so let's just have a look on the source
code now I know I always say we're doing
black box testing but we're talking
about the security now so you actually
have to see the source code to see how
you can secure it so I'm just going to
set the security level to medium because
the load just doesn't really check
anything so we're just gonna go with the
medium for now and we're gonna go on the
upload
and I'm going to view the source so as
you can see now in the medium it's only
checking if the uploaded file type is an
image now I don't get into too much
details about coding because this isn't
a coding course we're only talking about
how you secure yourself and about
penetration testing so I have to cover
the security part so we're going to talk
about the concepts but not the actual
code that you need to use because you
could be using a different programming
language so in here they're using PHP
and what they're doing is they have just
a simple if statement and they're
checking if the if the image if the
uploaded file type is an image so we see
how we can bypass this easily by
uploading an image and then changing the
extension to by rename in our shelf to
the jpg which will upload it which will
be accepted as an image and then we'll
just rename it as it's been uploaded to
PHP file now if we set this to high
security level
and you go back to the upload and have a
look at the source code you can see that
what they're doing here they're checking
that the extension is a jpg or a jpg and
then you can upload the picture so
they're not checking for the file type
this time so as I said you need to check
for both now in the new versions of dvwa
it actually has an extra security
setting called
impossible and what that is it basically
just shows you the right implementation
of each one of these pages so it's it
actually can't be hacked it's the right
way to do it
the dvwa version that comes in with
Metasploit Apple doesn't have that
security setting but we don't really
need to use it anyway we just need to
see the code so I have it here on github
and the way the right way to implement
this is Africa this is the same if
statement and basically what they're
checking is they check the extension is
an image extension such a JPEG or jpg or
PNG so that's all good so it has to be
one of these things and it has to be of
an image type so it has to be of type
image JPEG or image PNG and it doesn't
stop at that actually checks the sizes
but that's okay what it also does which
I was speaking about which is recreating
the image itself so what they're doing
is they're stripping the metadata of the
image and they're using a library
actually they're not using that library
but you should be using that library
which is called PHP a magic or whatever
there is that they're similar libraries
for Python and Ruby and all that -
basically what they do is they recreate
another image from the uploaded image
once they do that they actually delete
and destroy the old image and use the
new image with a new name so they create
a new image from the old image they
rename it and then they use that image
so these are three things you need to
check for the extension check for the
file type recreate the image itself that
way even if a person tries to upload a
bad file or a malicious file then you'll
be able to protect your web application
and your server from that file so even
if they manage to upload the file then
the file would be destroyed because of
the recreation process
right so now that we managed to upload a
file to the target computer using the
low security level let's see if we can
do it if we increase the security of the
target website so I'm gonna exit out of
this and I'm gonna go to my vulnerable
web let's go to the security settings
and add this before it was set to low so
I set it there to medium then click on
submit and now the security level is
medium so let's go back to our file
upload and try to upload our shell right
here the same shot that we uploaded
before
and I'm going to click on upload the
exact same way and as you can see it's
saying your image was not uploaded and
it's complaining about the headers
let's see if we can upload an image so
let's just make sure that the program
didn't break and we can still upload
images so I'm just going to upload the
same image again the car image and I'm
going to upload and as you can see we
can upload images but we cannot upload
PHP files so obviously now the target is
more secure
and now we're approaching this from a
blackbox point of view so we don't have
the source code to see what's happening
so there's a number of ways that you can
filter the files uploaded one method is
to check if the file is an image to
check the file type if it's an image
then upload it otherwise don't do that
if that's the way that they're doing it
then we can bypass that so let's see how
we can do that first the file has been
uploaded using a post method so to
modify the post parameters we're gonna
use burp suit I'm gonna click on burp
suit here
so we're going to go on the proxy site
in here proxy tab and before we can use
this we just need to set up our browser
to use pursueth
I'm gonna click okay and now everything
I do on this browser right here will be
sent through burb proxy so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna modify our file
right here the shell dot PHP and because
we can upload JPG images I'm gonna
rename this file and I'm gonna call a
shell dot jpg
now obviously if I upload this file this
way it's not gonna work because it has a
jpg and not a PHP extension so the
target computer or the target server
when I try to run it it'll just try to
run it as an image and I won't be able
to execute the code that I want to so
we're going to upload it as an image
first and then we're going to intercept
it in burp suit and convert its
extension to PHP to bypass the filter
let me do it and it will become more
clear so I'm gonna click on shadow jpg
upload it now this upload has been
intercepted in here and let's see what's
happening so you can see that the files
being uploaded the content type is
trying to be image to jpg and the image
is Sheldor jpg now what we're going to
do is we're gonna modify that and set
this to PHP
and we're going to leave the
content-type to image this will allow us
to bypass the filter and it will store
our file as shell dot PHP now just to
make sure that this is not gonna
overwrite the old shell and you'll think
that nothing got uploaded I'm gonna call
it shell 2 dot PHP
so that's it I'm gonna forward this
packet
and as you can see now we get a message
saying now the file has been uploaded
and it's called shell 2 dot PHP now if
we go back to our terminal and use the
same URL we were using before because
it's the same shell same password I'm
just going to call it shell 2 dot PHP
and try to communicate with it I'm going
to hit enter and as you can see now I
managed to connect to the target
computer or to the target server and I
managed to upload my shell by
intercepting the packet and changing the
file name from jpg to PHP
okay now that we can bypass the checking
for the file type let's see if we can
bypass it when we increase the security
level to high so again I'm gonna exit
this and I'm gonna go to the website
settings here in dvwa
and as you can see now this is still
running so it's intercepting every
packet I'm gonna click this to turn it
off so I can browse the Internet
normally and I'm gonna go on high I'm
gonna submit that and now that's all
good so the security level now is high
I'm gonna go to my file upload I'm gonna
try to upload a normal image just to
make sure that nothing broke like we did
before so I'm just going to upload the
car image
and as you can see we can upload jpg
extensions so I'm going to turn on my
interceptor again so I can see what's
happening and I'm gonna try to upload my
shell right here the jpg like I did in
the previous video I'm going to click on
upload and I'll just try the method we
tried before and see if that works
so in the previous method the target
computer or the target server was
checking if the file type is an image so
when we called our file
jpg it was only checking if the content
type is an image so when we come here
and change this to PHP
[Music]
and forward this packet the upload used
to go through now you can see that it's
telling us that the image was not
uploaded so it's probably checking that
the extension is jpg as well so it's
checking the file type and the extension
so we can bypass the file type like we
did before but now it's checking for the
extension so we can't really bypass it
that way so what we're gonna do is we're
gonna do a trick that I'll show you now
so I'm just going to upload the file
again same file share the jpg and I'm
going to click on upload
what it's doing right now it's checking
that the content-type is an image JPEG
which is perfect that's cool we can do
that we bypass that last time
well it's also checking this time it's
probably we don't know about we're
assuming that it's also checking that
the file type is dot jpg at the end so
when we were changing that due to dot
PHP everything is breaking because it's
expecting a dot jpg file or dot PNG so
it's expecting an image extension so
we're gonna do is we're gonna do dot PHP
dot jpg so we're going to call the file
shell dot PHP dot jpg this way it's
gonna check if the last thing is a dot
jpg and it's gonna think that it is a
dot jpg so it's going to upload it to us
then we're gonna browse it like a PHP
file and it should work for us so I'm
gonna call this shell 2 or actually
we'll call it shell 3 so the only thing
we modified now is we modified the file
name in here - shell 3 dot PHP dot jpg
I'm going to forward this packet
and as you can see now the file has been
uploaded successfully now I'm gonna go
back to my weave Lee here and the last
file we interacted with was called shell
2 dot PHP this time our file is called
shell 3 dot PHP dot jpg you can hit
enter and as you can see we managed to
connect to upload a PHP file and execute
it on a target computer using web proxy
to keep the file type as an image and
then we change the file extension to dot
jpg the 2008 PG which bypassed the file
type check as well so if I do ID now I
can get my ID if I do PWD I'll get my
working directory and in the future
we'll see how we can use Weebly but for
now you can see that we managed to gain
access to our target website