now let's try to filter the tables to
the tables that are only in our database
and dvwa
so we're going to use the word clothes
the same way that we were using it
before
so we're gonna say we're
table schema equals
dvwa can enter
and we get an error and again the error
is complaining above the quotes so the
website probably uses some sort of
security that does not allow us to put
quotation marks in the URL and we try to
bypass that using percentage twenty
seven before and as you see and we
couldn't bypass that we couldn't it was
still detected so we need to think of a
way to write the database name and put
it after the equal without putting the
quote marks right here so we need to say
dvwa without the quote marks and we
can't really do that by writing the
database name as text so what we're
going to do now we're going to use burp
suit and we're gonna use the decoder
part of it to convert the text dvwa to
hex now the decoder is really useful and
burp now remember and when I was saying
that the code for the quote is 20
percentage 27 and the code for the
hashtag is percentage 23 now I can just
type it in here and then go to encode us
and pick HTM URL sorry and you'll see
that the code for the hashtag is
percentage 23 you can get a code for any
text you want really for example if you
put a code you get a percentage 27 now
what we want to do is we want to convert
the text in here so that we don't have
to write it between quotes so we
actually have to convert it to digits
and what we're going to do is we're
going to convert the text of DB WI to
hex using the decoder part of burp so
I'm gonna go here
and type dvwa that's the database name
and we're going to
encoded as hex
and we're gonna use this as after the
equal mark so we're going to use it
instead of type in dvw I
so I'm going to remove this
and I'm gonna type in zero X now
everything written in hex has to start
with zero X so I type in zero X at the
start to tell the database that whatever
that's going to come after these two
characters is going to be hex therefore
I don't need to use quotation marks for
it and then I'm gonna put the code that
I got which is six four seven six seven
seven six one
and that's it so we converted the
database name to hex I'm gonna copy this
exploit paste it in here
hit enter
and I forgot to remove the single quote
from the start because this is the
medium level we don't need the quote
and here we go it's working we got the
tables that's only related to our
current database which is dvwa and the
tables are guestbook and users now every
time you need to use a where clause you
need to use it the same way that we did
it now by converting the name that comes
in after the word two hikes and u0x
without the quotes and that's what
you'll be able to execute to select the
columns using the this statement right
here just make sure you remove the
single quote
and it's gonna work for you now because
the tables the Select table statement
worked and this statement will work
because they're pretty much the same
statement the only difference is that
this one selects users and the other one
selects based on the database name
so in this lecture we've seen how we can
bypass some difficulties we can see with
SQL injections and we did that by
converting the text to hex and by
playing around with the injection
parameter so try and set it the other
quote remove a quote maybe try to
encrypt it use percentage 27 or stuff
like that basically just play around
with the parameters until you get it to
work
in this video we're gonna have a look on
some tips and tricks that you can use
while exploiting SQL injections so we
seen before
the two main statements that we'd use to
discover SQL injections is the add
statement and the order by statement now
some websites try to implement security
by checking the query URL for a number
of words and they blacklist these words
so that if they exist they don't execute
the query for example they check for
words like and/or Union select spaces
and stuff like that now we've seen how
we can bypass client-side security or
filtering using burp soot this is just
another way to bypass some sort of some
filters that's used in the server-side
if they're using a blacklist of these
words then you can bypass them using the
ways that we're going to talk about now
for example let's say you're trying to
discover an SQL injection and you're
going to use a valid statement by typing
+ 1 is equal to 1 so instead of doing
that you can just type it like so so a
capital and D and then use 2 - 2 equals
to 2 - 2 another way you can do an and
capital D and then put it 1 1 1 equals 1
1 1 this way your query will pass even
if the target website has blacklisted
and same goes for the order by you can
type it like so and you'll be able to
execute this query even if they
blacklisted the word order right now
lets me let me just actually run it for
you here so that you see when you
capitalize letters like this the query
will still work so if we just type it
order by 1 actually I forgot to put my
comment here and here we go you can see
that it gets executed exactly the same
way when you write order by 1 without
without capitals now another thing that
website sometimes blacklist is the space
so they don't allow spaces in the URL
now we can bypass that by right
applause or a double comment instead of
the space so let's have a look on a
query that we run before so we do you we
usually do Union select one two for
example and then we close it with our
comment which is percentage twenty three
now after this lecture we can actually
run this statement like so so we can
write it as Union with capitals select
again capitalize some of the letters and
then we can put the one two and close it
with our comment and if the spaces are
being used if the spaces are blacklisted
then we can put pluses instead of it so
you can do Union plus select plus one
two or we can write it as Union double
comment so we open a comment and close
it select open a comment and close it
want to open a comment and close it and
that's it
now these statements will be executed
exactly like the normal statement let me
show you here so I'm going to my SQL
injection and we put number one like
usual this works now we can just come in
here close the quote and put our
statement
and as you can see now the statement
gets executed successfully and we can
see that we can use number one and two
to get values from the database
another thing to keep in mind is the
comments sometimes comments are
blacklisted or sometimes not all of the
comments work when you try to comment
out the rest of the code so there is a
number of comments that you can try in
our examples we see in the hash tag or
the percentage 23 was the best which you
can also use forward slash star or - -
as comments sometimes you'll also have
to end this statement so you have to add
a semicolon to tell that this is the end
of the statement and then add your
comment and you can also use the double
forward slash as a comment as well so
we've seen our examples again the hash
tag was the one that works for us but
sometimes if that doesn't work then you
can try everything you can try the
forward for us - you can try the forward
slash star and you can try the - - if
that didn't work then you should go
ahead and add the semicolon at the end
and again try forward slash forward
slash star add - - and the hash tag
in this lecture I'd like to cover a case
that I faced in pretty much 50% of the
websites that I do penetration testing
on so let me first just run and exploit
the one that we've already seen so we're
just gonna run this statement which will
select the table name from information
schema the tables so this should list
all the tables that exist within our
page
and I have my security set too low at
the moment so I'm just gonna paste that
here remove this extra one and hit enter
as you can see it gets exploited and it
shows us the table name here instead of
number one so we see all the table names
that exist within this current database
the case that I'd like to cover is when
you actually run this statement so the
website will be vulnerable and when you
run this statement you will only see one
result at a time and that's because the
page is programmed in a way to display
only one result at a time
to do this we're actually going to need
to modify the code for the low security
level for dvwa we'll do that now and
then we'll come back to exploit it so
I'm actually just going to modify the
code for DB WI this is not part of the
exploitation this is just to make this
exploit a little bit trickier so I'm at
mr. MIT exploitable now and I'm going to
open the low security level of the SQL
injection file so I'm going to use sudo
because the file has root permissions
and I'm gonna use Nano as the text
editor
so this is the program that we'll use to
modify the file and the file is stored
in VAR w w dvwa
vulnerabilities SQL injection
source and then lo dot php' so again I'm
just going to go through this command so
what we're doing is we're still we're
saying sudo to run the file in root
privileges nano is the program that
we're going to open the file with and
then the file is stored and VAR w w w DB
wi vulnerabilities SQL i source lo dot
PHP I'm gonna hit enter and asking me
for the admin password now the root
password is MSF admin exactly like the
username
and we have the source here for the file
so I'm gonna modify here I'm actually
going to modify this loop so what this
loop does it actually loops through all
the characters all the records that the
this SQL statement gets right here and
then it displays them on screen so what
we want is we want to modify it to only
display one result the first result so
I'm just going to comment this line two
forward slashes add a comment so
basically this line will be ignored and
I'll also come at this line because it
closes the while loop so this line will
be ignored as well
now you don't really need to care to
worry about what this means if you're
not a programmer it's not very important
just comment these lines and we'll see
what happens
at the client sites because what we're
interested in this lecture is not the
programming we're interested in to the
penetration testing so I'm just gonna
hit control X to save this I'm gonna hit
Y and enter and that's it quit and save
the file so we're back here and I'm
gonna run exactly the same statement so
I'm not gonna modify it so I'm still
saying unions select table name from
information schema dot tables
I'm actually gonna refresh the page and
as you can see now this is not really
working or is it working
but it's only showing us the first the
first record that's been selected which
is the admin record so this is not even
useful so the first thing that I'm gonna
do is this is bringing us the admin
record because the admin has the ID of
number one so what we're going to do now
is we're actually just going to give it
an invalid ID so I'm gonna give it an A
- one
and as you can see now this statement
works we're getting a table that exists
in the information schema our tables but
we're only getting one table at a time
were not getting the full list of the
tables and this is because the page is
programmed in a way that will only
display one result and this happened to
me a lot of a lot of times when I'm
doing penetration testing so keep in
mind that we can run any SQL statement
that we want on the tape on the server
so we can modify our SQL statement to
iterate over all the records and display
their content so what we're going to do
is we're going to now obviously you can
use the where statement to on the show
database the tables within your current
database but at the at the at the moment
I want to show you how it had to iterate
over all the tables so what we're going
to do instead is use the limit keyword
to specify which record we want to
display with the current statement this
way
we'll be able to iterate over the
records one by one and display all of
them so the statement is going to be
Union select table name from information
schemas or tables and we're gonna say I
want to limit and the limit keyword
takes two values the first value is the
location of the record that we want to
start displaying records from so where
we want to start displaying records so I
want to start displaying records from
the first record so I'm gonna put 0
because the record numbers start at 0
and the second value that the limit
keyword takes is the number of records
that we want to display on screen
starting at the value that we specified
in here now we know that this page right
here can only show me one record at a
time so the second value to the limit
keyword can only be one in this case so
basically what we're saying is we want
to select the table name from the
information schema dot tables and I only
want you to display one record starting
from record 0
so if I copy this
and paste it here
you'll see I'll get the first table
right now and then if I want to go to
the second table all I have to do is
modify this so like I said this value
the first value in here means I want to
start at record zero so if I want to
start at record one I'm just going to
put one and then I can copy this and
paste it up in here again
and as you can see we got the next table
now again if I want to get the table
after this all I have to do is modify
this and set it to two and that means
that I want to start this playing from
record two and I only want to start to
display one record again if I had enter
as you can see I'm getting the next
table and I can keep doing this to
iterate over all the records manually
now we can also enhance this statement
by using the word close so before the
limit we can say I want to select table
name from information schema door tables
where table schema is equal to DV W a
now if we paste this in here
as you can see this has shown me the
users and again I can iterate over the
tables by changing the number here so
this is displaying the record at offset
one I can set this to zero to display
the first record and as you can see the
first table or the first record is
guestbook and that's it so just a quick
a nice lecture to show you how to bypass
this problem if you face it in pages
that would only display one value or one
record for you at a time
in this lecture we're going to go and
have a look on the high security level
and we'll see why it's uninjected so
let's go ahead first and set the
security level to high
and now I'm going to go back to my SQL
injection and let's make sure that the
page works first so I'm just going to
put number 1 like we always did and as
you can see now the page works now let's
try to inject it after the one after the
ID parameter like we always did and I'm
gonna put and 1 is equal to 1 so I'm put
in a true statement and as you can see
now the page doesn't really work so
let's try to put a single quote here to
close it like we did with the low-level
and again this injection doesn't work
either even though we're given a true
statement
that shouldn't interfere with the
current request we usually don't look at
the code when we're trying to hack but
as I said this is uninjected so let's
have a look on the code and we're going
to compare it with the code used for the
medium security level and we'll see
what's the difference is between the two
codes so that we can learn how to secure
our websites so I'm going to set change
the security level to medium here just
so that we can compare the two codes and
I'm going to go back to the SQL
injection
and I'm going to view the source as well
and got the put them beside each other
so in here in the medium security level
you can see that the ID is being read in
here and to be installed in the ID
variable and then they're using a
function called MySQL real escape so
what this function does it will go
through every character in the ID
variable and it'll look for special
characters such as single quotes and
double quotes and remove them therefore
any quotation marks used or injected in
the ID variable will actually be removed
at this line because of the use of the
MySQL real escape string now the thing
is once we go down to the SQL statement
you'll see that we actually don't need
to use any quotes to inject code into
this statement so our statement is
select first name last name from users
where user ID is equal to ID so we
actually don't need to close any quotes
we don't need to inject quotes in the ID
variable all we have to do is just put
any ID like we did that in the last
video so we can put just number one and
then inject code straight away after the
number one so when we use this code
right here we're basically we we didn't
use the quote in the medium so we are
literally just given the ID as number
one and then we're saying Union select
column name whatever from information
schema tables so the code has just been
injected right away after the ID and
then the database will read it and
execute it no need to use quotes again
because the code doesn't use any single
quote so the code just says user ID is
equal to ID now comparing this with the
code that we have for the high security
level you'll see that it uses the same
function to skip special characters but
it's implemented in the right way and
that's by using single quotes in the SQL
statement around the ID therefore
because the code is keeping the quotes
that we put and because they're using
quotes in there any code that we try to
inject in here will actually be
considered as if it's part of the ID so
when we use this code right here so if
we just use the code as it is without a
quote
then obviously it will just be inserted
instead of the ID variable between the
two single quotes so it'll just be
considered as the idea whereas if you
inject that code in here it will
actually be executed as part of the SQL
statement so let's have a look on what
the SQL statement will look like when we
inject our code in both in the medium
and in the high security level so I'm
just going to bring down the text here
so we have the SQL statement for the
medium here
and the SQL statement for the high
security level and we'll just try to
inject and one is equal to one because
as we see in if you can inject that then
you can inject anything you want really
and get it executed on the database okay
so looking at the medium statement we're
going to copy this code now this code
will actually go and pass through the
MySQL real escape character so it will
be removed from any single quotes that
it has but it has nothing and the code
will look like 1 & 1 is equal to 1 so
this statement is valid and and once
equal to 1 will be injected now looking
at the high security level notice this
use of these single quotes which will
mean that the user ID is equal to 1 and
1 is equal to 1 so and 1 is equal to 1
will not be considered as part of the
SQL statement but it will be considered
as part of the user ID now let's try to
add the single quote and see what effect
would that have on the SQL statement I'm
actually going to get rid of this
statement because we managed to inject
it and we're only going to focus on the
height in the statement used in the high
security level so we're using a single
quote here to close it and we're going
to copy this now this will actually pass
through the MySQL real escape string so
the single quote that we're using here
will actually be removed and this line
will become 1 and 1 is equal to 1 so
it's going to be equal or exactly the
same as the line we used before now 1
once they
is substituted in here again the 1 + 1
is equal to 1 will be considered as part
of the G of the user ID and it won't be
considered as part of the SQL statement
from this we can see that the use of the
MySQL real escape string is not enough
it has to be used with the single quotes
right here and combined with that
function then this specific SQL and
statement becomes uninjected now in
future lectures were actually going to
discuss a better way to build web
applications so that they can't be
injected with SQL statements but if you
needed a quick solution then you can go
for this until you have time then you
can change the implementation of your
website so that it can't be injected
in this lecture I'd like to show you how
we can use SQL injections to read any
file in the server so even if the file
exists outside the WWE root we'll be
able to read it exactly like a file
disclosure vulnerability and we'll also
see how we can use it to write files and
upload them to the system just like a
file upload vulnerability so the first
thing we're going to have a look at is
the read in the file and I'm gonna set
everything to null here so I have my
statement here and I'm gonna set select
one I'm gonna need leave number two
because I'm gonna do stuff in that and
we're gonna do another three notes here
so no no no so we have select null
something no no no so 5 because we have
5 records when we did the order by and
instead of selecting something remember
in the third video we did select
database
for example and it showed us the current
database what I want to do now is I want
to do another function and that function
is called load file
and in here I'm gonna set the file that
I wanna load and I'm gonna use the same
file that we had to look on in the file
inclusion of vulnerability and it was
etc' password so we're trying to read
that file and our statement is Union
select that file and that's it
so I'm gonna copy this
and I'm gonna inject it here and I'm
going to add my percentage 23 which is
my comment
and as you can see we managed to read
all the information all the content of
etc' password even though it's not in
the web root so it started in etc'
password so we can read anything in the
server from other websites from other
files anywhere in the server we can read
it by specifying the full path of that
file the next thing I'd like to show you
is writing to the server so we're
actually going to write stuff to the
server and this is very useful because
you'd be able to write any code you want
so for example you can write the code
for a PHP script you can write a write a
code for a shell a virus or a PHP code
to get the reverse connection to you so
it'll basically just act like a file
upload vulnerability and to do that I'm
going to write the code that I want to
do here and I'm gonna call that for
example just example example
and we're going to use a function called
out file so we're gonna do into out file
and then we're gonna specify where we
want to store that file now in best-case
scenarios you'd be able to write to your
web root and that will mean that you can
access the file through the browser and
execute it so you can upload a wiggly
file and then connect to it and do stuff
like that so let's try to do that first
so we're gonna do it in VAR www and
that's our web root so we'll be able to
access things through it or you can put
it even var www and then put Matilda
after it to store it in there
so the command is very simple again
Union select make sure you set
everything to null so that nothing gets
written to the file except what you put
in here and I put example example and
it's going to be stored into a file and
var www Matilde and we'll call that
example
dot txt let's try to run this and see if
it works
you
now this didn't work and if you come
down here you'll see that SQL or MySQL
is not allowed to create or write to
this directory so the problem is were
not the permissions that we have don't
allow us to write to this particular
location so just to test this exploit
I'm going to change this location to TMP
which is the temp and you'll see that
you can actually write to temp so in
real life scenarios it depends you can
try it and see if you're able to write
stuff or not and this we're trying to
write to temp now and if we read in temp
if we clear and then LS
can't you'll see that we have something
called example and if we try to read
that you'll see that it contains
obviously it contains the content of
what we did before which was the normal
selection that you'd see so what you see
for putting the stuff for admin and then
it shows us what's in there which is
example example which is what we wanted
to write to the file
now you can obviously get rid of the
admin and the admin pass stuff but I
just put in a wrong username and
nothing's going to be displayed here so
the only thing that you'll see is the
output which is example example well
again this is only useful if you're able
to write your webserver so you can
access it and then use your shell or use
your payload and further exploit the
system
in the previous lecture we've seen how
we can write stuff to the server using
an SQL injection using the into out file
function and if the server allow us to
write to the web directory to a place
that we can browse then we can just
write our reverse shell using the same
code that we've seen before using the
pass-through and then we can browse it
and we'll get a reverse shell exactly
the same way that we did when we upload
a file
the problem is we weren't able to write
stuff to the web directory so we can't
actually read the stuff using the URL
the only place that we could write to
was the TMP so you can't actually browse
the TMP through the URL therefore you
can't just browse that file so what I'm
gonna do today is I'm going to show you
a workaround for that problem but this
for this workaround to work the same
website or the same server has to have a
local file inclusion this is very
important the same web server not the
same website because we see and remember
in the first section how we can discover
all the websites that are within one
server so if one of them has an SQL
injection and the other has a local file
inclusion you can combine both of these
and get a shell and I'll show you how to
do that so I'm actually going to be
doing this on the DV WI you can do it on
Matilda but I'm just doing it here just
for a change to show you just another
example so I'm going to the SQL
injection and I'm gonna put number 1
here
submit it and then we're gonna start
doing our injection exactly the same way
that we always did so we close the quote
and we do Union select
one two
and add our comment
and that'll work as you can see now what
I'm gonna do I'm gonna write my shell to
TMP and then I'm going to browse that
shell through the local file inclusion
so my exploit is going to be Union
select one two and in one I'm actually
gonna write what I want to write to the
file so I'm gonna write a PHP code the
same PHP code that we've been using to
get a reverse connection to my computer
and the code is going to be passed
through
and Cee Ben Sh my IP
the port which is 8080
and instead of number two I'm gonna put
null so nothing will be written to the
file
and then we're gonna say into out file
and we'll call this reverse dot php'
so let's just have another look on this
exploit so what we're doing we're doing
a normal Union Select and we're doing a
normal into out file and we're still we
saving this in the TMP exactly like we
seen in the previous lecture but instead
of writing just normal stuff we're
actually going to write PHP code and
we're gonna do a pass-through nce bin Sh
my IP port and what this is going to do
it's actually going to try to connect to
this IP using netcat so let's exploit
this
and I'm actually gonna set the ID here
2-1 so that no values come in for the
admin and admin in here in the first
name and the surname so I just said that
2-1 and then I'm gonna put my exploit
here after the minus one
same way that we always do it
hit enter
and it tells us that the file already
exists but it actually doesn't this is
just a normal error so this file has
been written now to the server now the
problem is if if we load this file to
somewhere else other than TMP so for
example if we can actually write this
file to say var www dvwa then we'd be
able to just go and browse this file
from here
so all we have to do is just go to DW to
this and then right in reverse dot PHP
and then would be able to see it but
again we actually don't have permission
to write in here you can try to write in
images for example DB WI images so you
can actually before you go to this
method you can go ahead and try to find
a place a writable place on the server a
lot of the time you won't because if web
admins should actually know about this
and show you they shouldn't allow you to
write stuff like that but if you did
then you're lucky you can just go ahead
and browse it like this if you didn't
then just continue this video and see
how we're gonna exploit it so now I'm
just gonna listen for connections use an
netcat so I'm going to do and see
VV LP
and that will listen for incoming
connections on port 8080 so when we
execute this code it will try to connect
back to us and we'll get the connection
here so now we have the file written and
we're listening on connections all we
need is a way to browse this file to get
it executed so we see in that we can't
actually write anywhere that we can
browse it and because we stirred this in
temp if you manage to run it from
anywhere on the web server then you'll
have connection and you'll have access
to this website so it doesn't hurt you
don't have to find a local file
inclusion in the same website you can
find it in any website in the same
server and this is where the information
gathering part comes in really handy so
I'm gonna do what I'm gonna do now is
I'm actually just gonna run from within
dvwa but I just want you to know that
you can do this since we start it in the
TMP you can open it and browse it from
within any website on the server so all
you have to do is just find a website on
the same server that has a local file
inclusion now I'm gonna go to the file
inclusion and we've used this before so
what I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna
browse to et Cie password first to make
sure it works and it works
now we're gonna browse to our file that
we just uploaded which is stored in TMP
reverse dot PHP
and as you can see now we've got a
connection and we can run any commands
we want on this server
and pretty much we have a reverse shell
and we can do whatever we want on it
now I'm going to listen on 8080 again
and what I want to do is I want to show
you how you can exploit this now from
anywhere within the server so I'm
actually going to go to Mattila day
instead of dvwa
and we're going to go to the local file
inclusion vulnerability in here
so we'll try to exploit this now the
same way so it's five times back
et Cie password and as you can see we
can read the ATC password now all we
have to do is just read the TMP so this
is a completely separate website from
dvwa
we found let's assume that we found an
SQL injection in DB WI and then we found
the local inclusion in this combining
the two because the two websites are
installed on the same server on the same
computer we can actually get a reverse
shell on that server and doing that
we're just going to go to TMP reversed
our PHP
and again as you can see we have our
shell here where we can do whatever we
want on the target web server so again
the idea to take from here is using into
out file you can write stuff anywhere if
you can write stuff within the web
directory then you're lucky you can
write your reverse shell and just browse
it through the orell as if you're
browsing any file on the web server if
you can't then look for another website
on the same server that has a local file
inclusion and if you do then you can
just write the file using the SQL
injection and then browse it using the
local file inclusion and you have your
reverse shell
and all of the lecture so far we were
exploiting SQL injections manually so we
were injecting the code into the URL or
into the text boxes in this video I'm
going to show you a tool called SQL map
which allows you to do everything we
learned so far and even more stuff this
tool can be used against MySQL databases
which the one that we were having the
example on it can also be used against
Microsoft SQL Oracle and other database
types the tool is very useful in is very
handy in many cases sometimes the
injections aren't as nice as the one we
seen sometimes you only get one output
for each record and you have to loop
through all the outputs so the tool can
automate that and just do everything for
you much easier and much simpler so
let's first of all get the URL that we
were using for the injection so I have
that text file here that we were using
and I have the URL that we were using
before so it's the user info dot PHP
username is admin password admin pass
you don't really need to not user name
and password so I'm actually just gonna
put anything here so just to assume that
we don't know the password so we're only
inject injecting SQL injections we don't
really need to know any of this stuff
all I'm gonna do is copy this and then
I'm gonna run SQL map and I'm gonna do
you to specify the URL and I'll put my
target and I'm gonna make sure that I
have it between two quotation marks so
that it doesn't ignore anything in any
signs in the middle so we have some
settings and characters in the middle
that I wanted to all be treated as one
URL so all I did is SQL map you my
target I'm gonna hit enter and it will
automatically look through all the
parameters so it's gonna look through
the user info through the username and
the password to see if any of them is
injectable and then once it does that
it's going to store it in its memory so
it's gonna know that this is injectable
and then we'll be able to further
exploit the target so as you can see now
it's
thinking that our target could be MySQL
or PostgreSQL that's asking me if I if
it should skip other tests and I'm gonna
say yes because I know it's MySQL and
now it's asking me if it should do all
the tests for both databases and I'm
gonna say yes assuming that I'm not sure
which one it is
I know it's minus QL but I'm just gonna
let it do its thing and we'll see if it
can do it properly or not so at the
moment it's checking if it's PostgreSQL
and I'm assuming it's gonna know that's
not and then we're gonna it's gonna know
that it's MySQL it just found out that
the username seems to be injectable and
sure enough what's telling us here that
the parameter username is vulnerable and
we can inject it so it's asking me do I
want to check the other parameters such
as the password and all of them I can
say yes and let it do it well I'm gonna
say no because I don't mind if it just
uses the username for the injection so
it's all good now SQL Mac knows that the
target is injectable and it knows that
it's going to use the username parameter
to inject stuff and we can see that it's
figured out that it's running Linux
Ubuntu and it figured out that it's used
in PHP with Apache to point to point 8
and it's using MySQL server as the
database server so let's run SQL map
help and see what we can do now now this
tool is really big and it allows you to
do a lot of things so in this video I'm
actually just gonna show you a quick
look on the video and I recommend you
spend more time with it and try to see
what else you can do with it okay so
let's try to get the current user and
we're gonna try to get the current
database so we're gonna use the same
command that we used before and I'm just
gonna add to it DBMS to get the current
databases or DBS sorry as you can
see we got all the database that we have
so we have dvwa we have information
schema Metasploit MySQL I was 10 which
was the one that we were exploiting
before and Tiki Wicki now if we do
current user you can see that we are
root and if I do current database we'll
see that I was 10 is our current
database so now let's try to get the
tables for our stance so remember when
we did a select table name from
information schema the tables where
table name where a table schema is equal
to OS 10 we're gonna do we're gonna let
SQL map do all of that for us and so the
command is going to be we're gonna ask
it to get all the tables for us
and we're going to use the D option to
specify the database and our database is
going to be called our ask 10 and as you
can see it got us all the tables that
exist and remember it's the same we got
accounts blogs table and the credit
cards as well and now if we want to get
the columns then we can use the same
command again and we're gonna say get me
the columns where the table is called
accounts and the database is a wasp tan
and right
here we can see that we got the columns
so we have the ease admin the password
in the username and we can get the data
using the dump option so it's the same
command that we used before so we're
getting the from the table that's called
accounts and the database that is called
I was 10 I want you to get me all the
data and here we go we got all the data
we have the admin it's password admin
pass and we have Adrian and his password
is some password and we got all the data
right here so as I said as I said the
tool is very useful it can be used to
make our life much easier and it does
everything automatically and it can do
everything we did and can even do more
stuff
SQL map also allows you to get different
types of shells on the target server so
you can actually try to get an OS shell
using the OS shield argument so all you
have to do is just run SQL map and put
the URL and then ask for an RS shell
now in my case we've seen that we can't
actually upload files to the server so
now it's asking me what do I want what
what's the language that's used on the
server it's using PHP
and you can see that the file is cannot
be uploaded it's given a 404 error
because my website my target doesn't
allow the MySQL user to upload stuff if
this works you'll actually get an OS
shell and you'll be able to run OS
commands on the target computer
another the cool thing is you can ask
for an SQL shell
and what this will give you it'll allow
you to run any SQL statement straight
away as if you're running it through my
SQL so we were able to do that before
anyway using the new the Union Select
but in this you'll you'll actually be
running proper SQL queries and they'll
look it's much easier to write much
easier to read so you'll actually be
able to run more powerful attacks for
example we can just select the user by
saying current user
or we can just say user
we can also get our current database by
asking for the database
you can look up SQL syntax and then run
any SQL command you want for example if
we wanted to select all the tables like
you are doing before we can just do
select
table name
from
information schema the tables
we're table schema
is equal to OS 10
you
and I probably made a mistake here I
forgot an N so I'm just gonna be in here
enter
and I actually need an underscore here
sorry about that
and as you can see now we're getting all
the tables related to the database
called our stand again and here you can
run any SQL statement that you want it's
just a nicer and easier way to execute
your queries
as you've seen so far SQL injections are
very dangerous and also they're very
easy to occur and very easy to find
you'll find them everywhere in some
really famous websites people try to
prevent these vulnerabilities using
filters filters can make it look like
there is no exploits but if you actually
try harder by using encodings different
types of encoding or using a proxy then
you'll be able to bypass most of these
filters some programmers use a blacklist
so for example they prevent the use of
Union they prevent the use of insert and
stuff like that again it's not 100%
secure it can be bypassed using a
whitelist exactly the same issues as the
blacklist the best way to do it is to
program your web application in a way
that it does not allow code to be
injected into it and then executed so
the best way to do that is to do to use
parameterised statements where the data
and the code is separated and the best
way to show you what I mean by that is
using an example
I'm keeping the least amount of
programming in this example I don't want
it to be a programming example there's
actually mistakes in the program and in
there but I'm trying to give you the
concept more than how to program it so
the vulnerable code that we were looking
at used to do this so it used to do
select star from accounts where username
is equal to whatever we put in text box
1 and then we used to put in text box 1
let's just put it here
we used to say admin and then close the
quote
and then we're able to do a union select
and execute something else and then once
we're done we used to add the comment
which basically ignores everything that
comes in after it so when you copy this
and you paste it in here you'll see
what's happening so it's selecting now
let's just get rid of this because this
is just making the colors not nice and
I'm actually going to just put a comment
on this
so it's going to do a select star from
accounts where username is equal to
admin Union select and execute whatever
we want to do this is very bad and it's
very hard to protect against as I said
using filters and stuff will only hide
the problem will not fix it the best way
to do this is using the parameterize
statements just like so so this is the
safe way to do it first of all you can
repair your statement most languages
like PHP and all of them they actually
have a function like that and you can
prepare select star from accounts where
username is equal to question mark and
then you send the values so PHP now
knows the SQL statement is select star
from accounts where username is equal to
something and then it's going to take
the value of textbox 1 so even if we
come in and we use our very sneaky
statement right here
and paste it in there the web
application will know that the value for
this is admin Union select so they'll
actually try to go and select star from
accounts where the username and then it
actually it will add its own quotes and
they try to find a username with the
following username so this whole thing
will be executed like so
so it'll be select start from accounts
where username is equal to admin Union
select this hashtag so it'll never
whatever you put in your text box will
be sent as a value and the web
application will know that this is a
value it's not a code and it will never
execute it therefore this will protect
you against SQL injections you can use
the filters as second line of defense
and I also advise that you use the least
privilege as possible so use for each
database use one user with the least
amount of privileges they want so don't
allow the users to do anything that they
want Aladin if it's a simple website
only does selection then only allow the
user to select if it only needs to
select and insert then only allow them
to select an insert and this is a rule
you should keep with everything even
with Linux systems make sure the per the
permissions are always as least as
possible each user don't have any extra
permissions that they don't need in this
lecture and the next few lectures we're
going to talk about a vulnerability
called XSS XSS is short for cross-site
scripting this type of vulnerability
allows an attacker to inject JavaScript
into a page so javascript is a
programming language and using this
vulnerability an attacker would be able
to execute code written in JavaScript
into a certain page into a website
javascript is a client-side language so
when the code is executed it will be
executed on the client on the user on
the person who is browsing the web page
it's not going to be executed on the
server so even if your code results into
giving you a reverse shell the shell
will be coming from the user who is
browsing the page and it's not going to
be coming from the website so any code
you write in JavaScript will be
exploited or will run on the target user
on the people who see the pages and it's
not on the web server so the web server
is only going to be used
as means of executing the code or
delivering the code
there are three main types of XSS
vulnerabilities persistent or stored
reflected and Dom based the stored XSS
gets stored into the database so the
code that you inject will be stored into
the database or into the page so that
every time any person views that page
your code will be executed and the
reflected one the code will only be
executed when the target user runs a
specific URL crafted or written by you
so you'll be manipulating some sort of
URL and send it to a target and when
they run that target when they run that
URL the code will be executed
the dom-based results from javascript
code written on the client so the code
will actually be interpreted and run on
the client-side without having any
communication with the web server this
could be very dangerous because
sometimes web servers apply some sort of
security and filtration to check for XSS
but with dom-based the code never gets
sent to the web server so the code would
be interpreted and run on the web
browser without even interacting with
the web server and these will be present
in two websites that update their
content without refresh so we've all
used websites where you put your user
name for example and it loads in
straightaway without having to check
with the web server or if you do you put
some sort of a string and it does a
search without communicating with the
web server or does something without
communicating with the web server so if
you're able to inject into that then
this injection will not be validated so
it will be executed straight away and
bypass all validations so let's talk
about how to discover these kind of
vulnerabilities very similar to SQL
injections the way to do this is you
browse through your target and try to
inject any text box or any URL that
looks similar to this so whenever you
see a URL with parameters try to inject
these parameters or try to inject into
text boxes
so let's have a look on a reflected as
xs/s example so these are the non
persistent non stored vulnerabilities
where you have to actually send the code
to the target and once the target runs
the code it will be executed on their
machine
so let's have a look on our dvwa website
and I'm just going to login
and then we're gonna have an example of
a reflected XSS so as you see now you
can put your name here for this textbox
and it's just gonna say hello now this
is obviously just an example but the
idea is you can inject into text boxes
also if you have a have a look at the
URL here you'll see that it's a get so
you can inject into the URL as well so
let me start the beef pad
and let's try to inject xs/s code on
this and see if the code will be
executed our JavaScript code sorry so
what I'm going to use is a very simple
script so we're using this script and a
slash script tag now there is a lot of
ways into discovering these kind of
vulnerabilities and a lot of ways to
bypass filters but for now we're just
having a look at the basic case where we
can inject a normal script and I'm going
to say alert which is just a function to
give an alert to give a text box and I'm
gonna say
and XSS so I'm going to click on submit
and we'll see if this code will be
executed and as you can see now it's
actually executing my code so instead of
saying hello is 8 here it said hello and
my code has been executed and it
produced this XSS so we can do the same
here if you have a look on the URL it
actually already did it for us but if we
look at the URL here it's just going to
be a bit bigger there we can see that
the name has been now obviously all of
these characters are just HTML escape
characters and now if you send this URL
to anybody however if you've used that
URL well the code will be executed on
their machine and it's gonna say XSS so
let me show you here you can also inject
this in the URL I just want to show you
the whole idea of that so we have script
/ script XS
you
and if I had entered the code will be
executed so as I said we can copy this
and send it to a certain person and once
they run that code this code will be
executed on their machine
now let's have a look on the medium
security level and see if we can inject
our code and run JavaScript code on the
target website so this is the exploit
that were using or the payload that were
using so I just want it before I change
the security level to medium I want to
show you what the website looked like so
if we just right-click in here on the
hello and go to inspect element
I'm gonna make this a little bit bigger
so this will actually show us the source
code for this specific part of the
webpage so if we look at it
you'll see that we have hello which is
being written automatically by the
program and the hello is followed by
this script that we injected so it's
being injected exactly the same way that
we we write it in the text box which is
why it's been executed on the webpage so
we can see script alert XSS and then the
script tag is closed which is causing
the script to be executed on the page
now let's go ahead and increase the
security level
and we're going to set it to medium
now we're gonna go by
to the xs/s reflected
and I'm gonna paste the same exploit
that were using hit submit and you'll
see that it's not gonna work also notice
in the low security level we only seen
hello and everything here was blank we
didn't see anything now we see alert XSS
so it's not the pop-up is not showing up
and if we look at the code you'll see
that the start of the tag and the end of
the tag are not being ejected in here so
it's being filtered somehow because all
we see here is just hello and then we
can see the alert XSS that's why the
code has not been executed because it's
not placed inside the script tags this
tells us that they probably are using
some sort of a filter removing the
script from here
now there is so many ways that you can
bypass filters and other type of
protection from XSS the best resource is
a cheat sheet made by OS 10 which can be
located on the following link now I'm
gonna add this link in these resources
of this video for now I'm actually not
gonna use anything that's mentioned in
the link we're just gonna do something
that's really simple because I think all
they're doing is they're just looking
for this world and they're removing it
from the input so we can use the exact
same exploit right here instead we're
just gonna do what we used to do with
the SQL injection and just capitalize
some of the letter so we're gonna have
secret I'm just going to capitalize it
like this and then I'll capitalize this
one as well I'll probably just add an R
in here and then I'm gonna inject this
in the page
and as you can see now this works which
allowed that allowed us to bypass the
filter used on that website now this is
a really really simple way of exploiting
it
now some websites actually check for
quotes and enable magic quotes which
basically remove the quotes from the
string that you input from the text that
you input and in a future video we'll
see how we bypass that that's also
included in the cheat sheet that I'm
gonna add in the description in the
resources also there is a number of nice
exploits or payloads that's included in
the cheat sheet as well for example you
can inject stuff as an a tag you can
inject stuff as as an event of a jar as
a JavaScript event so when the mouse
goes over that particular priority code
will be executed and you can also inject
it you can give an image and give a
wrong source code and get the script to
run when there is an error since you're
given a wrong source code or source URL
for the image the code will work anyway
let's have a look on this one
so again we're just going to paste it in
here
and as you can see the code will work
here now all this is included in the
cheat sheet and you can go ahead and
there I'm going to add it in the video
resources you can have a look on them
and try them all