hello and welcome my name is Zaid I'm an
ethical hacker a computer scientist and
I'll be your instructor in this course
in this course I'm gonna teach you
website hacking and penetration testing
so we're gonna start from scratch and by
the end of the course you'll be at a
high intermediate level being able to
launch attacks exactly the same way that
black hat hackers would do not only that
but you'll also learn how to secure web
applications and prevent these attacks
from happening so this course is going
to start from scratch we're going to
start with the basics on how to set up
your lab how to set up your computer for
penetration testing once done with that
we're going to start talking about
website so before we talk about hacking
we're gonna talk about how websites work
how the requests are sent and received
so that we can exploit this and launch
our attacks once we understand how
websites work we're gonna move into our
first section of connotation testing
which is going to be information
gathering and this section you're going
to learn how to gather very important
information about your targets such as
the technologies used the DNS servers
used and the other websites on the same
server and we'll talk about why this is
important and why you need to know this
once you understand how websites work
we're gonna move into our main
penetration testing sections where
you're going to learn how to discover
exploit and protect from a large number
of vulnerabilities so the course is
going to be highly practical without
neglecting the three part we're gonna
first talk about why these
vulnerabilities happen how to discover
them how to exploit them and gain full
control over the service over over the
website and at the end we're gonna see
how you can secure websites from these
attacks and prevent them from happening
so if you're a programmer you'll know
what to avoid so that these
vulnerabilities won't happen once done
with this section we're gonna move into
our post exploitation where you're gonna
learn what can you do with the access
that you gained in the previous section
so you're gonna learn how to upload
download files navigate within the
target web server navigate from website
to another and even access the database
of the target server this is just an
overview of the main sections the course
will contain even more cooler stuff
so as described earlier the curse is
going to be highly practical so in order
to be able to do that we will need a lab
a place where we can learn and perform
attacks against so to do this we're
going to use a program called virtual
box now virtual box is a program that
allows us to install machines just like
normal computers inside our own machine
so I have one computer and I'm going to
install other computers inside this
computer so they're gonna be virtual
machines now these are very important in
terms of penetration testing we're gonna
be using them a lot to set up the lab
now it's very important to note that a
virtual machine is just like a
completely separate working machine
there is nothing you're going to lose by
installing an operating system inside a
virtual machine the operating system
will perform just like installing it on
a separate laptop so basically instead
of having four or five computers or
laptops around us so that we can try and
hack into them we're going to install
these computers as virtual machines
inside our own machine this might be a
bit vague now but once I do it it's
going to become very clear to you how
this is gonna work so basically I'm
gonna have three computers inside my
main computer so I have my main computer
which is Mac OS and I'm not gonna do
anything like that that's just going to
be my computer that I record the videos
from now I'm gonna have a machine that's
gonna be my attacker machine and that's
gonna be a Kali Linux and I'll talk
about what Kali Linux is once we get to
that and then I'll have two victims I'll
have a victim that runs Windows right
here just a normal Windows machine and
then I'll have a victim that runs an
operating system called Metasploit level
and I'll talk about what that is so
basically we're going to have our own
machine and then we'll have three
separate machines inside this main
machine the three separate machines are
the ones that were going to use to carry
out the penetration testing attacks and
they're going to be Kali Linux which is
the one that we're going to use for
attacking and - victim machines now
this is going to be possible because of
the program that I told you about which
is called VirtualBox now a VirtualBox is
free and you can download it from the
following link
now I'm gonna show you right here if you
just go into if you literally just
Google
download virtualbox and we're just gonna
go for the first link right here and
just grab the version that's compatible
with your operating system so there is
VirtualBox for Windows and here is for
for Mac OS X and for Linux so just
download the VirtualBox version that is
compatible with your operating system
double-click it and install it in
silence is very simple very easy he
literally just even for Linux you double
click it click Next Next Next and it's
installed now I have that installed and
ready
now this is my virtual box as you can
see it's installed and I have no
machines right here now in the next few
lectures we're going to learn how to
install Kali Linux and the - victim
machines and I'll talk about what each
of these machines does and why are we
going to use them now throughout the
course we're going to be using a number
of penetration testing tools you can go
ahead and install each of these tools
manually or you can do what most pen
testers do including myself and save
time and effort and use an operating
system designed for hacking we're going
to be using an operating system called
kali linux and it's just a flavor of
Linux based on debian and it comes in
with all the programs and the
applications that we need to use
pre-installed and pre-configured this
means that we can just install this
operating system and then start learning
our hacking
there are two options to install Kali
you can install it as a virtual machine
inside your current operating system or
you can insult as a main machine as a
main operating system
the course I'm actually going to be
using it as a virtual machine because
using it as a virtual machine works
exactly the same as installing it as a
main machine because it will be
completely isolated from your computer
because it's only going to run inside
VirtualBox so if you break it or if you
mess things up it's very very easy to
fix it's very easy to go back to other
snapshots other configurations and also
you won't lose any functionality by
using it as a virtual machine that's why
I always use it as a virtual machine and
in this lecture I'm gonna cover how to
install it as a virtual machine inside
VirtualBox now I'm going to be doing the
steps on a Mac OSX computer but these
tapes are exactly the same regardless of
what operating system you use so if
you're on Windows or on Linux you just
have to download the VirtualBox version
of your computer and then the steps
shown in this lecture are exactly the
same after installing VirtualBox so I'm
gonna include the download link in the
resources of this lecture and I have it
already opened in here all you have to
do is just scroll down
make sure you click on the Kali Linux
VirtualBox images not on the VMware and
then download the version of Kali that's
compatible with your system so if you
have a 64-bit computer download the 64
bits if you have the 32 bits download
the 32 bits
now one click on this will start the
download for you if you are using
Internet Explorer or edge browser then
you're gonna have to right-click and
save target as on Chrome and Firefox you
can just click the link now this is
downloading for me and I'm gonna stop it
because I've already downloaded
so I already have it downloaded in here
and as you can see you should get a file
with a dot ova extension so you have the
name followed by dot OVA in here so to
install this in VirtualBox all you have
to do is literally just double-click the
file
and as you can see I get a window which
will allow me to import this virtual
machine
now I'm going to keep everything the
same for now and I'm just going to click
on import
now that's it the virtual machine is
ready to be used
now before I started I want to show you
how to modify some of its settings so
we're gonna click on it
then we're gonna click on the settings
in here and the first thing that I'm
gonna do I'm gonna go to system and I'm
gonna modify the amount of RAM it has
now depending on how much total RAM you
have on your computer you can leave this
at two if you want but one gigabyte is
enough for Kali I usually leave it at
two because I have 16 gigs of RAM but if
you have less one gigabyte is enough for
it also if you come here on the
processors you see that by default I
have two processors assigned to it again
I have eight CPUs so two is not gonna
cause too much pressure on my computer
if you have less one CPU is enough for
Kali
now we're going to go to the network
settings and we're gonna set this to use
an ad network
now sometimes when you set this to an ad
network you won't see a network name in
here if you don't please check out my
link in the resources and to show you
how to create an ad network for me it
already has an ad network so I'm going
to keep it on this one and what this
setting basically does is it's gonna
create a virtual network where my host
machine which is my Mac OSX computer in
here is gonna be the router for this
network and then all the virtual
machines are going to be clients
connected to this network so they're
gonna get internet connection from my
host machine and at the same time all of
my virtual machines will be connected to
a virtual network this is very handy
because my virtual machines will be able
to communicate with each other we can
use one of them to hack into the other
we can use it to test networks attacks
and much more so it will first allow my
virtual machines to have internet
connection it will also allow them to
communicate with each other and it will
do all of this through a virtual network
it will not use any of your wireless
adapters or any of your wireless cards
it will create a virtual Ethernet
network so as far as the virtual machine
is concerned they're gonna think that
they're connected to a network through a
wire
so that's it I'm done with my settings
right now and I'm gonna click on okay
and we can start our virtual machine now
to start it all we have to do is just
click on the start button in here
now I'm going to click inside the
virtual machine and hit enter
and we are inside the virtual machine
now if you followed everything that I
did so far started Cali and got stuck at
a black screen so if you did not get the
screen that I have right now then don't
worry about that this is a common issue
and I've included a link in the
resources of this lecture that shows how
to fix this issue you can access the
resources of this lecture or any lecture
by clicking on the resources icon on the
top left of the player if you follow all
of the steps shown in the link and
you're still stuck at this issue or if
you're getting a different issue then
please post this issue in the Q&A
section and we'll respond to you within
15 hours and help you to fix this issue
now it's asking us for the username and
the default username is root so our OoT
and thence asking us for the password
and the default password is the reverse
of that which is T oor
and that's it now I'm inside my virtual
machine now since we installed this
using the ready image we can just go to
view full screen and we'll be able to go
in full screen and the screen will
resize automatically to the size of our
screen
now note in here you see that I have a
network icon appearing in here and if I
click it you'll see it looks like I'm
connected to a wired network as you can
see in here it says wired connected so
Callie thinks it's connected to a wired
network because we set this machine to
use a not network so if I open my
browser in here
you'll see that I have internet access
so that's it that shows how to install
Kali Linux as a virtual machine don't be
intimidated by this new operating system
we're gonna go through the basics and
we're gonna use it a lot and it's
actually going to become very easy for
you to use also like I said you won't
lose any functionality when you install
Kali Linux as a virtual machine it's
actually better to install it as a
virtual machine because it's completely
isolated from your computer and it will
be very easy to fix if things go wrong
keep in mind installing this on
different Hardware in different
computers might show you some errors on
some issues so please if you have any
errors just add them in the discussions
and I'll help you resolve them ok so
after installing Kali Linux we're going
to proceed to install in the second
machine in our lab so the second machine
is going to be Metasploit able
Metasploit able is another Kali is
another Linux machine you can think of
it as the opposite to Callie so Kali is
designed so that you can use it to hack
into other devices Metasploit ervil is
designed so that you hack into it so
it's designed for people who want to
learn penetration testing it is designed
so that it has a number of
vulnerabilities and we're gonna try to
use Kali Linux and order to hack into
MIT exploitable you can download this
from the following link you will end up
with a zip file like this one so sorry
not this one like this one so once you
uncompress it you'll get this directory
double click it and you'll see the
following files so we're gonna create a
new machine here and virtual machine and
I'm going to call it Metasploit Abel and
this is going to be a Linux machine and
I'm gonna hit continue and I'll only
gonna give it a gigabyte of RAM should
be enough and then
gonna use remember with Kali Linux we
created a new virtual hard disk with
this we're gonna use an existing one the
reason for that is because the image
that we have right now is actually it's
designed for VMware Player so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna import the hard
the hard disk file or the hard disk
image in here so that we're gonna have
an already installation without having
to install it the way we install Kali
Linux so we're just going to use an
existing virtual hard disk file and I'm
just going to navigate to select what it
is I'm gonna go into the MIT exploitable
directory and I'm gonna select the dart
VM VK file so it's this file right here
I'm gonna click on open and create so
we're gonna start this machine right now
okay so the machine has ran out
completely installed as I said you don't
really need to install anything we just
imported a ready installation already
hard disk so it's asking me for the
username and the username is m/s F admin
and the password is the same so it's MSF
admin as well and as we can see now we
logged in now this is only this machine
only has a terminal as you can see right
now and it's giving you a warning that
you should never expose this machine to
external internet connection because it
is a vulnerable machine it is designed
to be vulnerable now right now it's only
inside our lab it's only installed as
virtual machine so literally nobody
outside our lab can access it so this is
a really good way of using it now this
is if the machine is installed as I said
in the future we're gonna talk about how
we're gonna try and hack into this
machine again don't be intimidated by
the terminal we're gonna be using it a
lot and we're gonna learn how to use it
step-by-step so at the moment just we
have this installed and we're going to
move on to the next step and we will
talk about this once we actually need to
use it in the future so
you want to turn off this machine all
you have to do is just type in power off
and hit enter and telling you that you
need to be rude so again I'll talk about
this later
for now pseudo power off so just run the
command like this and asking you for the
admin password and that's it it's going
off now and here we go the machine is
off the last machine that we're going to
talk about installing today is the
Windows machine so this is just a normal
Windows machine that with Windows 10
that we will also try to hack into so
this is going to be another victim
another target and we're gonna see how
we can try and hack into this victim now
again we installed Metasploit able
because Metasploit able has a large
number of vulnerabilities and it can
it's just designed so that you can hack
into again we've seen that it has a
terminal it's not very user friendly as
and it doesn't really mimic a normal
user for the Windows machine this one
will be used with scenarios that mimic a
normal user that is just using their
windows to browse the internet or do
whatever normal people do with their
machines so Microsoft has actually
released a free free versions or free
virtual machines of Windows that you can
download and use these are free and
you're allowed to download them and
we're downloading them from Microsoft's
website so you need to go into this link
to download it as you can see here this
is the same link so make sure you select
what host operating system you have so
if you have Windows you click on the
windows tab if you have Mac on the Mac
and if you have Linux on the Linux I
have a Mac so I clicked on the Mac tab
and from here make sure you select
Windows 10 stable and make sure you
select the VirtualBox image so these are
all applications that allow you to
install virtual machines at the moment
we're using VirtualBox for everything so
make sure you use the VirtualBox image
once you do that you will have a zip
file like this one
I'm compress it and you will get this
file right here now this is a virtual
machine a VirtualBox virtual machine
file so I'm going to double click it
and as you can see in our virtual box is
asking me to import this machine and
it's already set up the settings for it
right here now we can import it the way
it is and then modify the settings now
as you can see here I have my windows
installed right here and I'm just gonna
boot into it by actually I'm gonna
modify the settings first because I
remember I think it gave it four gigs of
RAM and I think that's too much so I'm
gonna go in to here and I'll set this to
gig two gigs and yeah so that okay and
I'll start it
and as you can see windows starting
straightaway no need to install it it's
already installed and ready and given to
us by Microsoft
you
now as you can see we have a fully
working Windows machine right here
Windows 10 and this is going to be our
third machine that we're gonna use as in
our lab and it's gonna be our second
attacking machine so it's our second
victim or target machine the Kali Linux
machine is the one that we're going to
be using to attack both of these
machines the Windows machine and the
Metasploit able machine okay now that we
have Kali Linux installed I want to give
you a basic overview of this operating
system in this lecture so that you're
comfortable with it and we're going to
be using it throughout the whole course
so everything is going to become easier
for you as we go through the course now
the first thing that I want to talk
about is the status bar in here
so you can see we have an applications
menu in here and inside it you can see
all the applications are categorized so
we have information-gathering
applications vulnerability analysis web
application analysis reverse engineering
and so on so you can go on each one of
these entries and just select any
program that you want to run and the
next menu that we have is the places
which shows you the most common places
in the file system so we have home we
have the desktop we have the documents
downloads and so on so you can access
the places from here and then you click
on home or you can just click on the
files icon in here on the left and both
of these will bring you to the home
directory which is actually the root
directory
so it says home in here but the actual
location of this if I do ctrl L you'll
see it is /root so inside this you can
see we have our downloads music pictures
similar to the way that you'd have it in
Windows and OS X we also have the time
in here and in here on the right we have
more controls so the first thing that we
have in here is the workspaces so Linux
comes with multiple workspaces by
default base
what this allow us to do is we can have
this desktop in here for example we can
open the places and we can for example
navigate to downloads and do some work
in here but if we go here to workplaces
and go to the second one you can see
that I have an empty desktop that I can
do whatever I want and for example I can
launch Firefox in here
and then again if I want to go back to
the first workspace all I have to do is
click on here click on number one and
I'm back in here and because I've
already used up two spaces the system is
already creating a third empty space so
I can click on that and as you can see
I'm in there third space where I can do
more stuff now you can also navigate
between the spaces by pressing ctrl alt
up or down to go up and down in the
spaces the next part of the Salus bar is
this last part in here and if you click
on it basically the first thing it'll
allow you to do is control the sound
next you'll see your connections so as
you can see right now and as I showed
you before this is showing up as if were
connected to a wired network because I
configured this network to use an ad
network if you have a wireless adapter
connected to this computer you should be
able to see it here if you don't see it
then follow the link in the resources of
this lecture to see how to properly
connect your wireless adapter or any USB
device to a virtual machine now I should
note you can only use external USB
adapters in order to access Wi-Fi
networks from Kali you cannot use the
built-in Wi-Fi card but Kali should have
internet connection anyway because it is
configured to use an ad network and as
you can see in here it's telling me my
wired is connected so if I actually go
down to Firefox I'll close this
and if I just go to google.com you can
see it is connected to the Internet so
let's go back to where we were and if we
click here we also have the battery
settings the user settings you have this
button to turn off the Machine this is
to lock the machine and this will show
the Preferences where you can modify the
Preferences of the machine so you have
Bluetooth Wi-Fi change the background
change the languages and so on so you
can spend some time getting familiar
with this it's very easy and very
intuitive same goes to the file manager
and here very intuitive double click to
go in you can right click an archive and
extract here to uncompress it you can
navigate throughout these files by
clicking them and then you have the
trash here which contains the deleted
files
now we also have the doc in here which
contains the favorite applications and
you can also access all the other
applications by clicking on this icon
right here the show applications and
this will show you a menu with the most
frequent applications and then if you
click on all it will show you all the
available applications
okay now that we had a quick overview of
kali linux i want to spend some time
talking about the linux terminal so you
can access the terminal through this
application right here so if we click on
that it will open the terminal window
for us and as you can see all it is is a
black screen where you can type commands
now the linux terminal is actually very
very powerful because it can be used to
do anything that you can think of really
a lot of the applications and linux that
have a graphical interface where command
prompt programs first and then people
made a graphical interface for it so a
lot of the time maybe the graphical
interface will be buggy or crash and the
terminal program will still work also a
lot of the penetration testing tools do
not even have a graphical interface a
lot of them can only be used throughout
the terminal not only that but in many
scenarios you might only have an SSH or
a command prompt access to a machine so
you need to know how to use this command
prompt in order to achieve your goals so
throughout the course we're going to be
using the terminal a lot and that's why
I want to spend some time just showing
you the basics of it and making sure
that you're going to be comfortable
using it now the basic idea is you type
a command and the result will be
displayed for you on screen so let's
have a look on a very very simple
command which is PWD now this command
prints the current working directory has
the name PWD so if I hit enter you can
see it's printing /root which means
right now I am in the root directory so
basically I am in here this is the root
it's home
so if I do LS which is a command to list
all the directories and files in the
current working directory we should get
all of these directories that we see in
here so if I had enter as you can see I
can see all these directories in the
current working directory now another
very useful command is the CD command
this command allow us to navigate into
another directory so for example let's
say I want to navigate into the
downloads all we have to do is type CD
followed by the name of the directory
that I want to navigate to so I'm gonna
type downloads
now if I hit enter I should be inside
the downloads now so if I do PWD to see
my current working directory you'll see
that it's saying I'm enroute /downloads
so if I do LS here it should show me all
the directories and files inside
downloads so if I do enter as you can
see I have a directory and the file in
here and these are the exact same files
that you'll see if you double click the
Downloads here
now if you want to go back one directory
so similar to pressing the back button
in here all you have to do is do CD
again the command to change the working
directory followed by dot dot and now if
I do PWD you'll see I'm back in route
and if I do LS you'll see all the
directories and files in route so that's
all good and there's actually a huge
number of commands that you can use so
I'm going to include a link in the
resources of this lecture of all the
Linux commands that you can use you
don't need to know them by heart we're
actually going to be using a lot of them
throughout the course so you're going to
naturally learn them as you go through
the course now if you are using a
command and you're not sure about how
this command works you can just use the
man command to display the manual of
this command for example we've used the
LS command here to list the files and
directories in the current working
directory but if I do man followed by LS
this basically means I'm requesting the
manual of LS
so I'm asking how can I use the LS
command so if I had enter you'll see
I'll get a screen similar to a text file
and basically it's given me a lot of
information on how to use the LS command
so you can see that it's telling us that
this command will list the directory
contents you can see the way it works by
typing LS followed by the options
followed by a file if you if you want to
run it on a file you can see a longer
description of the command and then you
can see all the options and the
arguments that we can use with this
command now in Linux most of the time
the options will always follow the same
syntax so you either use - letter or - -
a word to specify the argument for
example and here the - a and - - all
will ignore entries starting with dot
so if you keep going down in here you'll
see all the options and arguments you
can use with the LS command and we have
another example here we have the - L
which means it's going to use a long
listing format which will display more
information about the files in the
current working directory so let's have
a look on that I'm going to press Q to
exit this and then we're going to do LS
as usual and since we read the manual we
know we can do - L to see more
information about the files and if I had
entered now you can see I'm still
getting the same directories but it's
also showing me the permissions the
users the date created and so on so you
can use the man command on any command
you want not only on the LS so you can
use it on the PWD you can use it on the
CD or any other command and it will show
you full description or the manual page
of how to use this command
now I'm going to clear the screen by
typing clear and the next thing that I
want to show you is the dash dash help
so this is something that you can use
again in almost all commands and all
programs in Linux so you can just type
the program name or the command name
followed by dash dash help as you might
think
this will show you a help message
telling you what this command is or what
this program is the arguments that it
takes how to use these arguments and
examples at the bottom now another
useful thing with the terminal so I'm
going to clear this again is the arrows
so you can press up to go up to see all
the commands that we executed before and
again you can go down to C to navigate
between the commands that you executed
previously you can also use the tab for
autocomplete so again let's do LS and
you can see all the files and let's say
we want to go into documents so we can
do CD followed by documents you can type
documents or if you're lazy like me you
can just do do C and press tab and as
you can see it's automatically
completing the rest of the word for me
so this is something that comes very
very handy when you're using the
terminal for a long time
now what I also want to show you is how
to install programs in Kali from the
terminal so first I'm going to clear
this and the first thing that you want
to do is update the sources where Kali
can search and download programs from so
we're going to do apt-get update now
apt-get is the name of the application
that allow us to download and install
programs and we're saying update because
I'm saying that I want you to update the
list of all the programs that I can
install so I'm going to hit enter and
you want to make sure that you have
internet connection when running this
and as you can see it's telling me that
it's done and now we can go ahead and
start installing applications so the
first program that I want to install is
actually a terminal program so similar
to this one but it allow us to have
multiple terminal windows open in the
same window so in order to install a
program through the command line we're
going to do apt-get which is again the
name of the program that allow us to
install programs on the system we're
going to say that I want to install and
the program that I want to install is
called Terminator
so very very simple first of all were
typing the name of the command which is
apt-get we're saying that I want to
install and the program name that I want
to install is called Terminator so I'm
gonna hit enter
and this is going to download and
install Terminator for me so you can use
the same command to install any program
that you want you just need to replace
Terminator with the name of the program
that you want to install now I've
already downloaded and installed this
before so it didn't ask me to confirm
but if you're running this for the first
time it might ask you to confirm whether
or not you actually want to install this
program so all you'd have to do is press
Y from the keyboard and hit enter now as
you can see it's done so if I go to my
all applications in here and just type
Terminator you can see that I have it
here so I'm actually gonna drag it and
put it in my dog so I can access it
easily in the future
so now I can just click it in here and
that will open Terminator for me now
this is another application that allow
me to run commands so it's exactly the
same as this so again I can do LS and
PWD the only difference is with this one
I can actually right click and click on
split horizontally for example and this
will split the same screen into two
screens where I can run commands at the
same time so I can have some commands in
here and I can run commands in here and
then I can even split this more if I
want again vertically or horizontally
and as you can see I can have as many
terminal windows as I want and this will
be very helpful in the future when we'll
be running a number of programs and a
number of commands at the same time
so now that we have all the machines
installed I just want to show you final
configurations of the lab and I want to
show you how the lab is going to look
like and how we're going to use the
computers in the future videos so the
first thing I want you to make sure that
all the devices are connected to the
same NAT network this is very important
so that we can access one device from
another so I'm gonna click on the cat in
Linux and if you go on the settings and
go to network you'll see that it's
connected to a network called not
network
also if you go here you can see that the
network name is 10 2014 not now you
might have a different name it doesn't
matter just make sure that you could you
select the name that you have there if
you don't see any names in there have a
look on the link in the resources you'll
see how you could fix it this issue but
by default VirtualBox should should
automatically create an ad network for
you and you can just select it from here
now you probably won't see this advanced
so just not Network
make sure that the name is selected here
press ok then go to the Metasploit able
machine and make sure it's connected to
the same not network so make sure you're
actually connected to this you might
have more than one not network so make
sure you select the exact same not
network so when I come here you can see
that it's connected to not I'm gonna
change that to not network and I'm gonna
make sure that you can see that the name
is called only not network here but the
Kali machines network was called Nath
network 10 2014 so I'm gonna make sure
that I select the same night network
that is selected in the Kali machine
I'm gonna press ok and now my settings
are good
now like I said before we're going to be
using the Cali machine to launch our
attack so this is going to be our
attacker machine and we're going to use
the Metasploit table as our victim or as
our target now the Metasploit a ball
comes in with a number of websites so
it's a computer but it has a number of
websites installed on it and this is
usually the way web servers work usually
you'd have more than one website
installed on the same web server and
this is very useful to us we'll talk
about that later we'll see why it's very
useful for now let's see how we can
access the web sites on Metasploit a
table so I'm just going to log in like I
said the username is MSF admin and the
password is MSF admin
and to see the IP address of this
computer all you have to do is just type
in if config so IIF config
and the IP address here is 10 2014 to 14
so if I go to the callee machine here
and if I open my browser
and if I navigate to 10 2014 to 14
you can see that I can access my
Metasploit table machine and it says
Metasploit able to so this is the web
server
installed on the Metasploit Abel machine
now throughout the course this IP might
be changing so I might be going to a
different IP because sometimes the IP of
the net network changes every time you
run it for you if you access that IP and
nothing works for you all you have to do
is just go back to the Metasploit able
machine run if config and see what IP
you get then if you navigate to it here
you'll see that you can access the web
server now as you can see there is a
number of websites installed in
Metasploit tables so if we click on
metal day you'll have a website if we go
back if you click on DV WI you have
another website and we'll talk about
these websites and we'll talk about how
to hack them in future videos
one more thing that I want to point is
the configuration of one of the websites
is misconfigured with MIT exploitable so
I'm just going to show you how to fix it
now so that in the future you won't have
any errors on once we start running the
attacks
the website that's misconfigured is
Mattila day so we're just going to
modify its configuration using nano
which is a text editor so we're going to
type in nano and then we're going to
type in the path for the config file
which is stored in VAR www Mattila de
config dot Inc so Nano is the program
that we're going to use to modify the
configuration and VAR w w tilde config
don't Inc is where the config file is
stored and to run this as admin as root
you have to type in sudo in front of it
so I'm going to do sudo
I'm gonna put the admin password which
is msf admin and now what you need to
modify is the last line so if we you can
navigate down using the arrows in the
keyboard and you can see that the DB
name is set to meet as Floyd here you
want to modify that you want to remove
that and type in OS 10
so OWA ESPE 10
now this is all done it's perfect now
all you have to do is just press ctrl X
to exit press Y to save it
hit enter
and that's it now it's saved and we're
ready to start penetration testing and
learn how to hack into websites
web application penetration testing
before we can start talking about that
we need to understand what is a website
and just like I said before a website is
just an application installed on a
computer that computer probably just has
better specs than your computer but it
fundamentally it works exactly just like
another computer so it has an operating
system and it also has a number of
applications to allow it to act as a web
server so the main two applications that
it probably has is a web server and a
database our web server is like Apache
and the database is like MySQL and these
are the web server basically understands
and executes the web application so your
web application would be written in PHP
or Python and any programming language
really the only thing is that the web
server needs to be able to understand
and execute this web application the
database contains the data used by the
web application so all of this is stored
on a computer called the server the
computer is connected to the Internet
and it has a real IP address so anybody
can access that computer and can ping it
so the web the web application is
executed by the web server which is
installed by which is installed on your
server on your target therefore any time
you request a page or you run the web
application it's actually executed on
the web server and it's not executed at
the clients computer it gets executed at
the web server and then it sends a HTML
page which is ready to read for the
target person or for for the client so
let's have a look on an example and
let's say you're on the phone or on your
computer and you wanted to go to
facebook.com so you type in facebook.com
into your URL this will be translated
using a DNS server to an IP address so
there is a server that translates and
every name com
you or any website with a name with a
domain name so this is a domain name -
it's relevant IP address so your request
facebook.com/ the request goes to a DNS
server it translates facebook.com to the
IP where Facebook is stored and then you
go little a go to Facebook to the IP
address of Facebook it will execute the
page that you wanted using all of the
applications that we spoke about and
then just give you ready HTML so what
you get back is just a markup written in
HTML which is a markup language of the
result of executing the program so the
program gets executed on the server and
then you just only get the result this
is very important because in the future
if we wanted to get anything executed on
the web server if we wanted to get a
shell a reverse shell or a BYOs
executed on the target computer then we
need to send it into a language that the
web server understands so for example
PHP and once you execute it there it
will be executed on that computer not on
your computer so regardless of the
person that accesses the page the this
the web shell that you're gonna send if
it's written in PHP in a language that
the server understands is going to be
executed on the server and not on your
computer therefore it will give you
access to the server and not access to
the person who accessed that server
javascript on the other hand there is
some websites use javascript and
javascript is a client-side language so
if you manage to find a website that
allow you to run javascript code then
the code will be executed by the clients
so even though the code might be
injected into the web server it will be
executed on the client-side and it'll
give you it'll allow you to do things to
the client computer and not to the
server so it's very important to
separate between a client-side language
and the server-side language now let's
translate this into our example so in
our example we're gonna be targeting the
Metasploit able machine so our web
server is going to be the Metasploit
able machine and we're not going to be
using a DNS
server so we're not going to be using a
name like facebook.com/ we'll be
accessing the website directly using its
IP address so like we seen before if we
just go here to our meters potable
machine I type in if config you'll see
that my IP is 10 2014 to 14 and if I go
here to my Metasploit mesh to my Kali
machine you'll see that if I type in 10
2014 to 14
you see that I can access my Metasploit
able machine so the web server here is
the meatus toy table machine itself the
web applications are Matilda II PHP
myadmin dvwa and all of these so these
are web applications and when we click
on them you can see for example here
it's written in PHP so it's written in
this programming language it's also
using a MySQL server which can be
accessed through phpMyAdmin so these are
just technologies used on the web server
but the web server itself is the
Metasploit able machine here so when you
put the IP address when you put 10 2014
214 were actually accessing the
Metasploit able machine and inside the
Metasploit able machine we have
technologies we have interpreter that's
running PHP code we have a web server
and a database and these are running the
web application for us which is Mattila
des dvwa and all of them
so knowing these components leave us to
knowing how we can hack a website so
there is more than one thing that we can
exploit to gain control over a website
now the main thing the obvious thing
that you'd think of is the web
applications so it's the thing that you
always interact with for example in
facebook it's where you search for stuff
and where you upload pictures will you
write posts all of these things are
handled by the web application because
it's the thing that you click the thing
that you interact with so for example if
I go here on Mattila day and I start
browsing the web page this is my web
application so every time I click on
something it's being handled and
executed by the web application on the
web server so if I could exploit this
web application in some way if I could
gain access to it if I could connect to
the database because it's obviously this
web application connects to the database
then I'll be able to maybe gain control
over the web site and maybe even gain
access to the web server and then get
access to other web sites on the same
server we'll talk about all of that
later in the course
the other way of gaining access to
websites is using the computer itself so
let's say you came your target was DB WI
and you couldn't get in you couldn't
find any exploits in the web application
itself you tried everything you tried
all the exploit so we're going to talk
about and you just couldn't get in then
your other option would be to exploit
the programs installed on that computer
because we said a web server the website
is installed on a normal computer just
like your home computer so if you
couldn't get in using the web
applications what if there is one of the
programs installed on the web computer
and the computer itself has an exploit
has a buffer overflow or a remote
execution exploit what if the web server
itself or the database program the
program that's running the database
itself had a remote root exploit that
allows you to just gain access to the
whole web server including the all the
web sites inside it so this will be
really cool if you could get it if you
could have find anything wrong with the
applications installed on the web server
on the operating system then you could
target the humans because we know web
sites are managed by humans for example
Facebook you can target mark or you can
target the admins of Facebook for
example these admins obviously have more
privileges on that web site than you and
then they might be able to upload
sensitive files to that web site and
then you can control it and hack it by
hacking into one of those people so
instead of maybe the web site is very
secure and the server is very secure and
there is no way that you can get in but
you can always exploit the humans using
social engineering attacks and
client-side the tags to gain control or
hack one of the people that managed that
target website and then maybe gain
access to it
now this course will be concerned with
the web application penetration testing
so it's concerned with the first step
with the first approach so we're going
to learn how to discover and exploit a
large number of vulnerabilities that can
be fine
found in the web application itself
we're not going to be talking about
server-side attacks so the attacks that
exploit the operating system and the
applications installed on the operating
system itself of the web server and
we're not going to be talking about the
client-side attacks about attacking
humans and how can their accounts and
then gaining access to the website all
of these these two the last two sections
are actually covered into my general
ethical hacking course so I have a
course called learn ethical hacking from
scratch which which covers those two
aspects therefore in this course we're
going to be focusing on the web
application penetration testing site so
on hacking the web sites based on the
web applications installed on that web
site
today we're going to learn how to get
information about the technologies used
by the target website so we're going to
use a website called nut craft and I'm
gonna put my target here and as you can
see I already put it there I security
world so I'm just gonna hit enter and
again first of all you'll see some basic
information such as the website title
the description the keyword and when the
website was created scrolling down
you'll see the website itself the domain
name the IP address just like we seen in
the previous video the domain register
are so the company who registered the
domain for us for eye security and
you'll also see information about the
organization and here you can't see it
for this example because I security is
using privacy protection but usually
you'll be able to see it and see more
information we can also see that it's
hosted in Netherlands we can see the
name server which is dim Knopf dotnet
and again if you just go to dim nerf net
you'll discover that this is a website
for web hosting so we know this is a web
hosting company and worst worst case
scenarios we can use this or try to hack
into dim nerf itself to gain access to
eye security
scroll down you'll see history of the
hosting companies that I security used
and we can see that the latest one is
this one and it's running on Linux with
Apache same server that we seen in the
previous video two point three point
three one with UNIX mode SSL and all the
other add-ons again this is very
important to find vulnerabilities and
exploits on our target computer in the
security section you'll see if the
website has any spam and you can see
that it doesn't really have any spam
scrolling down on the web trackers it
will show you the third-party resources
or applications used on our target so we
can see that our target uses Google
Analytics Google CDN and other Google
services so this could also help us to
find or gain access to the target
computer the technologies is one of the
most important tabs or sections in here
because it shows us the technologies
used on the target website so we can see
it's used in Apache web server we
already know that on the server side we
can see that the website uses PHP so
this means the website can run can
understand and run PHP code this is very
important because in the future if we
manage to run any kind of code on our
target then we know this code should be
sent as PHP code so for creating
payloads and Metasploit or even
relevation we should create them in PHP
format and the target website will be
able to run them because it can support
PHP on the client side we can see that
the website supports Java Script so if
you run Java Script or if you manage to
run JavaScript code on the website it's
not going to be executed on the website
it will be executed on the users who see
the website because javascript is a
client that the client-side language and
PHP is a server-side so if we if we
manage to run PHP code it will be
executed on the server itself if you
manage to run JavaScript it's going to
be executed on the user's
or the people who visit the website
same here with jQuery this is just a
framework for JavaScript scrolling down
we can see that the website uses
WordPress this is very important so net
crafts will also show you any web
applications being used on the website
so WordPress is just a web application
so you could see other examples in your
case and it's a open source web
application that a lot of other websites
might have the good thing about this is
you can go and find exploits or
vulnerabilities within this web
application if you are lucky enough to
find an existing one then you can go
ahead and exploit it on the target web
site so for example we have wordpress in
our example and i'm gonna go to exploit
database
and if we go on the search here
so I'm just gonna type in WordPress here
and I'm gonna say I'm not a robot then
we're going to search
and as you can see we've we managed to
find a lot of exploits related to
WordPress now these are related to
different versions of WordPress so you
need to make sure that you have the same
version on your target and we'll have
examples to see how to use exploits like
these but it just shows you how powerful
information-gathering is again going
down you can see that the website uses
cPanel this is another web application
it's a hosting control panel again you
can go on exploit database and see if
you can find any vulnerabilities or
exploits related to it and you can also
find other information such as that the
website uses html5 uses CSS and all that
kind of stuff so net craft is really
useful from it we managed to know that
the website runs PHP runs JavaScript it
uses WordPress so we can use WordPress
to hack into the website and cPanel and
we can also if we go up we also manage
to know the web hosting or even we found
that in the previous video that demon of
is the web hosting company of this
website so in worst case scenarios we
can try to hack into that web hosting
and gain access to our target website as
usual the first thing that we do before
we start trying to exploit or find any
vulnerabilities we do information
gathering so we try to gather as much
information as possible about the target
and web applications are no different so
we're going to start by trying to get as
much information as we can about the
target IP address the domain name info
the technologies used on the web sites
are what programming languages used what
can a server is installed on it what
kind of database is being used we're
going to gather information about the
company the DNS records and we'll also
see if we can find any files that are
not being listed or any subdomains that
are not visible to other to other people
so the first thing that we're going to
have a look on is who is look up who's
the cup is a protocol that's used to
find owners of Internet resources for
example server and IP address or a
domain so we're actually not hacking or
doing anything we literally just
retrieve an info from a database that
contains information about owners of
stuff on the internet so for example
when you sign up when you sign up for a
domain name if you wanted to register a
domain name for yourself for example is
a calm when I do that I have to supply
information about myself my address and
then the name would be stored in my own
name and people can see that Zaid owns
this domain name so this is all we're
going to do if you google whose look up
you'll see a lot of websites providing
the service so I'm using who's the
domain tools calm and I'm just gonna put
my target domain name and I'm just gonna
use I security at org
you
so as you can see very simple and we get
a lot of information about our target
website you'll see the email that you
can use to contact the domain name info
usually he'll be able to see the address
of the company that has registered this
domain name but we can see that this
company is using privacy on their domain
so you can't really see the address but
if they have if they're not using
privacy you'll be able to see their
address and more information about the
actual company you can see when the
domain name was created you can see the
IP address of I security org so if you
ping this you should get this IP address
and I'll show you
I do think I see here it you'll see it's
the same domain name here the same IP
address here sorry you can see the IP
location we can see the status obviously
it's active you can also access the
history but you need to register for
that and obviously we can see the title
here and something that's very useful
here we can see that it's using Apache
web server so this is a software that
can be used as a web server and we can
see that I security uses this web server
and of version 2.2 0.31 so again we can
use this to find exploits and we can see
that it's using Unix the operating
system of the website of the server and
it's using the following add-ons as well
as using mod SSL and open SSL now right
here you can find more information about
the company who registered this domain
so again I security is using privacy so
you won't be able to see the address you
can see that it's saying that the target
person is using privacy protection but
usually you'll be able to see phone
numbers and addresses of that company so
as you can see very simple stuff but
it's very helpful in the long run just
to know what your target what's their IP
what services are they using we can also
here actually I didn't show you you can
see the name servers that are being
being used and we can see that they are
provided by a company called Tim not net
now if you go on them now if you'll see
that this is a hosting company
so if we go on the English version that
you'll see that this is a hosting
company and again you can even use this
hosting company and try to social
engineer your way maybe into hacking
into your target into eye security