hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about virtualization so what is
virtualization so virtualization in the
term of computer it actually means the
duplicity of computer hardware as well
as the software so what it means
so with the help of virtualization we
can properly utilize the computer
hardware and its processor even with the
help of virtualization we can create and
install different operating system in a
single operating system so here you can
see that this is a single computer or a
single operating system and with the
help of virtualization technique we can
install different sub operating system
inside it so the most popularly
software's which are used in order to
perform virtualization czar Oracle
VirtualBox and VMware so now let's see
how we can install one of them that is
Oracle VirtualBox in our system now
let's see that how we can install
VirtualBox in our operating system so
here you can see that right now I am at
VirtualBox dot R and here are different
download links so depending upon your
pedestal you can download one of them so
I have already downloaded the VirtualBox
setup which you can see on my desktop so
I'm let's double click on it ok click on
next next ok so now task for the various
things like you want to create a
shortcut in a quick launch bar you want
to create a shortcut on desktop so
uncheck these two click on next ok
yes and install
okay now click on finish' and it will
start VirtualBox for us ok so here you
can see that the system first menu of
the Oracle VM VirtualBox so here are
some few options like file machine help
so by clicking on new we can create a
new virtual machine and by clicking on
file we can import our appliance and we
can export an appliance so here you can
also change some network settings so
this was all about this video so in the
next video I will show you that how we
can install Kali Linux inside the
VirtualBox thanks for watching this
video