hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about a unique kind of programming
language which is used in Windows in
order to automate a day-to-day tasks and
that programming language is called as
best programming language and this best
programming language is also used by
hackers and trackers in order to create
some malicious files and with the help
of that files the hackers and the
crackers can do some malicious
activities on a particular system so
this batch programming language is also
used by developers in order to automate
some day-to-day tasks but before going
further let's talk about that what's
what is the execution environment of
this batch programs or is there any
special software we need in order to
create these files so the execution
environment of batch file is very simple
we need nothing all we just need is we
need a text editor we can even use
notepad and a notepad plus plus and
that's it so what we have to do is so
any command which can be run on a
command prompt can be used in batch
files or a batch programming language so
here you can see that any command which
can be run on a command prompt can be
used in our batch files so these
commands can be written in batch files
so which means our batch file or our
batch program will actually run on a
command prompt so that's why we need
nothing just the notepad in order to
create our batch file now let's talk
about some sample programs which we will
make in this video so these programs
include lock your system so the help of
some programs we can even lock a
particular system so what we can do is
we can make one batch file and we can
send that file to anyone and if any one
just open that file then its computer
just get locked so what else we can do
is we can also open multiple pages in
browser and even we can create a
malicious batch files which may result
in firewall disabled and we can even
create a backdoor for Windows and the
process killer so with the help of some
batch programming files tools we can
even some extract data from the system
so that's why the batch programming is
used is the most popular feature and
windows now let's see how we can make
some batch files in order to automate
day-to-day tasks and let's create some
malicious file with the help of batch
programming language
now let's make some batch files in order
to understand that how batch programming
works well in order to make batch files
and test them I will use Windows 7
operating system in my VirtualBox so
that my main parent operating system
will not be affected by that batch files
so I recommend you to please use Windows
7 in VirtualBox in order to test the
batch files which we will make in this
course so as I told you earlier that in
CMD that any command which can be run
inside this command prompt can be used
inside the batch files or in in other
words any command that is supported by
this command prompt can be used inside
our batch files so just for example if
we write here ping google.com you can
see here that the ping command is
supported and if we want to see the
directory listing just right here dir
and it will list out all the directories
and if you want to check that Who am I
that whether we are root or
administrator here you can see here so
which means any command which we can
type here and if that command runs we
can use that command inside our batch
files so we don't need any kind of
special text editor in order to make
batch file and we also don't need any
kind of execution environment in order
to run that batch files all we just need
is one notepad so you can use any text
editor so I am using notepad here and
the next thing we need is command prompt
so first of all before starting the
batch files let me give you a short
introduction of the commands which we
can use inside the command prompt so let
me close this up and let's start the
command prompt as administrator so
whenever you start the command prompt as
an administrator so you will notice here
that we are inside the system32
directory so this is our current path
that where we are right in so if we want
to find and list out the files and
directories which are present inside
this directory system32 you just have to
write dir hit enter
and it will list out all the files which
are present inside this directory then
if we want to change the directory just
for example if I scroll up you will find
here there are old files but just for
example you want to come back one
directory so you want to go here Windows
so just right here CD CD for change
directory and two dots so if you hit
enter you will see that we are came out
one directory back and right now we are
here in local disk C Windows and let's
go back again so now you can see that we
are in local disk C directory so let's
list out the files which are present
inside this so you can see here there is
one directory called as Windows users
and if we want to change your directory
and you want to go here to the users
just right here CD users hit enter and
you can see that right now we are inside
users directory the main thing to be
noticed is that in command prompt it's
not mandatory that you write all the
command in small letters and even in
capital letters you can see here that if
I write here dir then it will also work
and if we write here in dir in small
letters then that will also work so the
same thing we can apply while making our
batch files now let's make a simple
batch file but before going there let me
give you an introduction of echo command
so if you are familiar with this command
echo so this command is also used in
Linux in order to print something so if
I write here echo hello and hit enter so
here you will see that the hello is
printed right after this command and you
can see here here is our output now
let's do one thing let's first of all
let's create a simple batch file which
will print out hello for us so whenever
we are going to make a new batch file we
always have to write at the rate echo
off so why we are writing this as the
ratico of i'll explain you a little bit
later so hit enter and then here we have
to specify a command which
we want to execute when this file will
run so just right here Eko I am new file
hit enter and in the last we have to
write here pause so I am writing here
pause I will explain you when I will
explain this concept at the reticle off
so let's save this file you can save
this file on desktop and anywhere else
so write down the name demo and we
always have to save the batch files with
dot dat extension that is dot bat so
once I save this file you can see that
this file is created on my desktop and
all the batch files are looked like this
this is the icon of the batch files and
if I go to its properties it will say
that it's a Windows batch files and if I
open this file you can see here that it
has printed I am a new file and as
asking us to press any key to continue
and if I press any key it just
terminated so now let's go back here to
our source code now this thing is clear
to you that the echo command is used to
print out something and now what is the
use of this at the rate echo off so just
for example let me remove this line let
me save this file again and let me run
this again so that you can understand
the difference between the echo and at
the ratico of so now you can see here
that if we not use at the rate echo off
then what happen is this command prompt
will execute this line first then once
it executes this line or the first
command then it executes the second
command after the previous one and you
can see here so you can see here that at
the first this command prompt has
executed echo I am a new file and here
you can see its output and then later on
it has executed this pause and you can
see here that there is a positive and
it's saying press any key to continue
and the main other disadvantage
of not using at the rate Eco office that
if we don't use at the rate eco off then
the code which we will write in our
batch file will also be printed on the
command prompt you can see here that
here is our code echo I am a new file
and the same code is printed on the
command prompt so that's why it's
mandatory to write at the rate echo off
in order to hide our code and if I just
run this file again you will see a clean
neat output so let's remove this pause
and run it again and you will see that
whenever I double click on it a command
prompt will come and suddenly disappears
you can see here so that's why we use
pause in order to hold our command
prompt and you can see here now here is
our command prompt so this is the basic
usage that how we can create a batch
file and how are the batch file works
now let's make some batch files in order
to see that what else we can do so first
of all we will see that how we can make
a folder bomb so we can say the batch
files are viruses so we can just say
that the batch files are actually the
files which are used in order to execute
a particular command on a particular
system so the folder bomb is actually
just a batch file which will make a
random folders in in a target machine so
how to make a folder first of all let me
just open my command prompt ok so let me
let's list out everything so you can see
here the list of folder now in command
prompt if we want to make a folder then
what you have to do is so just right
here MD that is for make directory or a
make folder followed by the folder name
which you want to create so just right
here demo hit enter and if you just
write here dir you will see that a new
directory named as demo is created now
what we will do is in our batch file we
will make a code which will make a
thousands of folder
in our target machine let's go back here
to a notepad file let's create a
separate one so I will start with eco
off then here I will start one loop
which will iterate and go still infinity
so in order to start loop and batch
programming we have to write here : then
ax so you can write here anything like X
Y B there just a variable then here we
have to write down a command which we
want to execute so you want to execute
MD then here I will write here random
inside the percentage so what is the
meaning of this so as I told you earlier
that in order to make folder or a
directory we have to write here MD
followed by the directory name which we
want to create like first so now we want
to create a directory or thousands of
time but we don't want to wrap specify
any particular name so that's why I have
written here random so it will start
from any random number so that is MD
percent I random and in the last we will
write here and go to and X so here you
can see that we have specified a
particular loop that just started from
here then execute this line until how
till how long you have to execute this
code I have written here go to X means
we haven't specified any particular
point that after 10 times you will
terminate after 15 times you will
terminate just execute this command in
infinity so let me just save this file
and let me say every return or desktop
and name it as a folder bomb dot bat and
here you will see that a file folder
bomb is created now let's make a new
folder and put it inside
okay so here you can see that the file
is here and let's just double click on
this file and you will see here a
subdirectory or a file already exists
and if you look at here at the
background you will see here that to
start making folders you can see a long
list of folders so in order to stop this
file and in order to stop the folders we
have to just close this file and you can
see here that within the seconds this
file has created 14,000 to sixty-six
folders so this is the beauty of batch
files now let's just try to make a file
which will add a random user accounts in
any of operating system so let's go here
so in Windows if you are not familiar
with that how we can check the accounts
in command prompt then there is one
command called as net user which we can
use in order to check that how many
accounts are associated with this
Windows operating system so if I hit
enter here you will see that right now
there are three accounts
the first one is administrator then
there is a guest then there is a root so
we can also verify here that right now
we are logged in as a root so in order
to add a particular user inside the
Windows operating system the first thing
we have to do is we have to open a
command prompt with the administrator
privileges and then here we have to
write here net user the net user
followed by the username we want to add
so just for example you want to create a
new user so let it be demo one and then
we have to write here /ad so if I hit
enter here you will see that the command
completed successfully now let's verify
that whether this user is created or not
and you will see here that a user named
as demo 1 is created so we can just
verify it from here
so manage other account and here you
will see that the user named as demo -
created now let's do one thing let's
create one batch file which will add an
thousands of users in a Windows 7
operating system so what you can do is
you can send these files to your friends
in USB drives from via through email and
if someone just open this file and that
person will just get affected so let's
create a new notepad file okay so the
same thing I will write here at the rate
echo off then I will add here in an
infinite loop and I will write here
command net user then here the same
thing I will do I will write here random
because we don't want to specify a user
name then add and in the last I will
write here go to tell X we haven't
specified a particular position so
that's why I am writing here go to X to
make it as an infinite infinite loop so
let me save this file so user add dot
b8e let's just save this file and you
can see here that the file is created so
if you remember then I told you that in
order to create user by command prompt
we have to open a command prompt with an
administrator privileges so just for
example if I just run this script
without administrative privileges let's
see what happened so you can see that
it's giving us an error that access is
denied but if I just run this script as
an administrator what we will see the
command completed successfully so let's
just stop this file and let's go here
click on manage account and you will see
here that this file has created lots of
users in this operating system
so I it's not letting me to close this
but no worries so what we can do is we
can even verify by writing here net user
and you can see the user names now let's
have a look at one more batch file that
is called as folk bump so in operating
system there is one call called as for
call so the so the what fork to it
actually create a lot of processes in
our system which eventually makes our
system to crash now let's write here at
the rate echo off and you will just get
a Miss that in order to crash any system
all we just need is the five digits code
or the five letters the first one is
percentile then 0 then again percentile
then again 0 and if I save this file and
let's just rename it as a fork
dot bat click on save and here is that
file you can see so if I just open this
file wait for five seconds
and here you will see that my system is
stuck now I can't do anything if I want
to close this file it will not letting
me to close this you can see here the
system is out of environment space
because it has created lot of processes
at the background you can see here that
I can do anything so the only thing I
can do is just reboot the system so
let's just reboot the system and let's
start it again so this is the beauty of
batch programming then we can do lot of
things if we know properly that how we
can create a batch files and here you
can see that they have lot of users but
here is mine
so now let's create a batch file which
will turn off the firewall when the user
opened that batch file by administrative
privileges but before going there let's
see that how we can turn off firewalls
by using command prompt so there is one
command called as net SH firewall set up
mode that is operation mode and we want
to disable it and if I hit enter you
will see that the requested operation
requires elevation which means this
command is not successfully executed
because we are not an administrator so
that's why we have to run this command
in command prompt by with administrator
privileges now let's write here firewall
set up mode and disabled and if I hit
enter here you will see that the command
executed successfully here it's the
success message okay now let's just
verify this let's go here to control
panel security Windows Firewall and here
you will see that the Windows Firewall
is off you can see the status Windows
Firewall status now in order to enable
this firewall just right here enable and
you will see that the firewall is
enabled now you can see its status now
let's add this functionality in our
batch file
so let me save this file on my desktop
and here is that fine let me just run it
as an administrator and let's just go
back to our control panel system and
security Windows Firewall and here you
will see that now firewall has turned
off so this is how we can use bad
programming in order to automate a today
task and even we can create some
malicious script which can infect a
particular system so in this video we
have discussed that vertex based
programming and how to make some simple
batch files in order to see that how
much programming works so thanks for
watching this video