hello everyone in this video I will give
you and short introduction of ethical
hacking so before talking about ethical
hacking first let's discuss that what is
hacking so hacking is actually an act of
finding a possible entry points or for
finding a vulnerabilities flaws in a
particular system or a network device or
a networking device or a network so that
a hacker can get into that system
through that new vulnerabilities or
entry points so hacking is usually done
in order to gain and unauthorized access
of a particular computer system so
intentions behind hacking would be
different like some hackers wants to
hack a particular system in order to
steal some sensitive information so
whereas another hackers may usually want
to hack a system in order to destroy or
a harm a particular organization so now
we know that what is hacking now let's
discuss about ethical hacking so ethical
hacking the term ethical hacking is
actually used in order to do hacking for
a legal way or for a good purpose so the
person's who performs ethical hacking
are called as ethical hackers so the job
responsibilities or the functions of
ethical hacker is to perform penetration
testing finding vulnerabilities in their
own company's organization in order to
protect their company's data so their
job responsibilities are as follows so
they actually their main goal is to
protect systems of their organization to
protect their data to eliminate any
potential threat the ethical hackers not
perform hacking in order to in order to
do harm for a particular organization so
now we know that the hacking is of two
types
so now let's discuss about that what are
the types of hackers so there are three
types of hackers which are most
popularly called as black hat hackers
white hat hackers and grey hat hackers
so as the name suggests black hat
hackers so black hat hackers are very
dangerous hackers because they are not
associated with any kind of company they
actually do hacking in order to harm
peoples or organization and also you do
hacking in order to steal some sensitive
information whereas the white hat
hackers are associated with the
particular organization and they always
do hacking in order to protect their
company's data from another hackers
whereas the grey hat hackers are
actually combination of black attackers
Whitehead occurs so sometimes gray
attackers are associated with the
particular company and they do hacking
for a good way but side-by-side they
also do hacking for any illegal purposes
so that's why they are called as gray
attackers so in this video we have
covered that what is hacking what is
ethical hacking and types of hackers so
thanks for watching this video