hello everyone in this video we'll start
with the first topic of Windows hacking
that is Windows password storage policy
so before getting into windows hacking
we must know that how windows store ever
password so Windows operating system
stores our password in the form of
hashes and these passwords are present
inside Sam files so the Sam file stands
for a system account manager and this
file is responsible for containing our
password so the directory in which this
file Sam file is present is here you can
see it's a C local disk C Windows then
system 32 config and Sam so we can find
this file Sam file in this directory now
let's talk about some features or affect
about Sam file so the Sam file system
account manager is one of the most
secure file in Windows operating system
so why it is more secure file now let's
talk about it
so the San files can't be opened can't
be edited and can't be copied if the
Windows operating system is running
which means if we are using a Windows
operating system then we can't copy this
file we can't open this file and we
can't even edit this file so this is the
first security feature of this file then
the next feature is because we know that
this Sam file contains the password in
the form of hashes so what we can do we
can over crypt this file in order to
make it more secure so you can see here
that it can be over kept by Windows
using special features so these are the
two security features of San file but in
order to find the password from the Sam
file or in order to see that what is the
content which is present inside the Sam
file we need one more file that is
called a system so the system file
actually contains key which is used in
order to see the content of Sam files so
as a hacker we need two files the first
one is Sam file then the second one is
system file in order to find password
from the Sam fight so these all things
make a Sam a good account manager so now
let's see how we can copy the Sam file
and can crack or find the passwords from
Sam file in our system now let's copy
Sam and system file in order to find
password of a particular user so I'm
using Windows
címon operating system in my virtual box
so you can see here so the reason behind
it that I'm using this window salmon
boarding system because in Windows 8 and
Windows 10 the way Microsoft stores
passwords in window is totally changed
due to the association of Microsoft
account so that's why I'm choosing this
Windows 7 operating system as my first
target well I told you earlier that the
Sam file contains the passwords and
there is one more file called a system
which contains the key to open that Sam
file and one more thing I told you that
we can't copy a SAM file
we can't edit it and we can't modify the
same file when the system is running but
is there any way so that we can export
the same file yes there is so what we
have to do is in the just run bar just
right here regedit and click on yes so
this will open a registry editor for us
so here you can see that the registry
editor so then we have to go here to the
H key local machine and here you can see
there are two folders or the files Sam
and system so what we can do is we can
export both of them so just right click
over here click on export you have to
give a location so just right here Sam
and here we have to do little
modification we have to change its type
to registry hi files click on save and
you will see here that on my desktop
assign file is exported
similarly knowledge export system file
click on export so we have to give right
the same name system and we have to
change the file type also to the
registry hi files click on save so you
can see here that the system file and
the Sam file is present now what we have
to do is in order to open these files
and in order to crack and find the
passwords inside them we have to
download one tool that is called as kan
and Abel so you can download this tool
from here from oxide I T and Cain so
this tool is very powerful tool in order
to do cracking and we can also do some
wireless attacks by using this tool so
just click over here download Cain and
Abel for a Windows and I have already
downloaded this
to my Windows operating system so you
can see it here now let's install this
tool
so this tool requires also additional
there are drivers of WinPcap so you also
have to download it and install this
software wind pcap click on finish
and here you can see that on my desktop
the tool icon is present so let me just
open it up and it requires an
administrative privileges and when every
time you start this tool this will give
you this warning that Windows Firewall
is enabled so you have we just have to
ignore this click on ok and here you can
see the main menu of this tool there are
a lot of sections like decoders network
sniffers crackers we can even trace a
particular trace route then wireless and
Kure so but for the time being we are
interested here in the cracker and as I
told you earlier that in Sam file our
Windows passwords are stored in the form
of LM and ntlm hashes so once we are
here inside the cracker menu we have to
select this one LM and ntlm hashes so
once we click over here and then we have
to click over here this plus icon in
order to add a Sam database along with
the system file so click over here so
the first option is import but we want
to import from a Sam database because we
already have a Sam file so click over
here import hashes from a Sam database
and here we have to give a Sam file
location so it's on my desktop so let me
give the location and then here you can
see a boot key so it's a system file so
we have to give a location of a system
file also and here you can see that the
key comes so let me copy this key click
on exit and let's paste this key here
and click on next so here you can see
that our Sam file is opened inside this
tool you can see here a user names and
along with the element n T hash and here
you can see that currently there are 3
users in my Windows 7 operating system
administrator guest and root so now
let's just verify so here you can see
that right now we are logged in as a
root so what we will do first of all we
will find the password
this user that is route and here you can
see that if I select this one route and
in the column of a lemon and T hashes
you can see here there are two hashes
associated with this user which means
this user is password protected now in
order to find a password or in order to
crack a password of a particular user
there are different password guessing
attacks so the first one is dictionary
attacks then the second one is brute
force and so on so in dictionary attack
what happen is there is one dictionary
file which contains lot of words so we
will pick one word and then we will make
element e hash of that word and then we
will match that element e hash value
along with this value and if the value
matches then we are successfully able to
find the password then other kind of
attack which we can do is brute force
attack
so in brute-force attack we actually
make a combination of different letters
and digits in order to create ntlm
hashes and then we'll match a value and
then another kind of attack is also
called as a rainbow tables attack but
here in this video we will do a
dictionary attack and then we'll try
that whether we can find the password of
this user or not but in dictionary
attack there is one limitation that we
can only be able to find a password of a
particular user if the password of that
user will be present in that dictionary
file so there are lot of online websites
from where you can download a long
dictionary file which contains million
of passwords but in this tool can enable
so when we download this tool and if we
just go here inside its directory so
let's go here to the Program Files and
here is its folder and if I open it up
it also contains a one directory called
as word list in which it contains lot of
passwords which we can use in order to
find a password of a particular user but
I already have one word list file so I
am using that file in order to find a
password so what we have to do is just
right click over here here you can see
that there are different different
attacks dictionary attack brute-force
attack cryptanalysis attack so now let's
go here prediction area attack and then
we have to sell
ntlm hashes click over here and here we
have to give the location of a
dictionary file so just right click and
click on add to list and my dictionary
file is present in my documents so I
have selected this file and click on
open so here you can see that a
dictionary file is added now what we
have to do is we just have to click on
start and here you can see that it
started searching passwords and here you
can see a password per second and
dictionary position so 37% of dictionary
file is completed password
so here you can see that it's a ntlm
hash of the password of this account and
the value is 2 which means this is the
actual password which I have settled for
this account and here you can see that
attack stopped hashes cracked and here
you can see that it's a password now
click on exit now let's just verify and
I'm just writing here twr hit enter and
here you will see that we are
successfully able to find a password by
using dictionary attack so similarly you
can also use different attacks like
crypt analysis rainbow table attacks and
brute force attack also so in this video
we have discussed that how we can copy
Sam and system file and how we can find
password by using dictionary attack so
thanks for watching this video