hello everyone in this video we will
talk about steganography
so what taste eggnog Rafi so
steganography is actually an art of
writing a hidden messages so with the
help of steganography we can write a
hidden message which can only be viewed
by our receiver so with the help of
steganography we can hide a one piece of
information behind another piece of
information so just for example you can
see here that here is our text file
which contains our hidden message so we
can hide this text file behind any jpg
image and even we can hide this text
file behind any mp3 file so it's the
same vice-versa
we can even hide one mp3 file behind any
jpg file and even we can hide any jpg
file behind any text file so this is the
beauty of steganography that we can hide
one piece of data behind the another
piece of data so there are different
different techniques like LSB that is
last significant bit so there are
different techniques which are used in
order to hide our data so now let's see
how steganography works now let's see
how we can hide a text behind an image
file by using one Python script so in
order to do so we have to start our Kali
Linux and here you can see that my
College Linux is up and running so let's
download that script from my github
profile so just right here G is T dot
github.com /r Kumar 97 and here you will
find one file named as tag Oh stagger
dot py so let's download this file click
over here and let's just save the page
so I'm saving this on my desktop okay so
the file has saved now you can see here
now let's open our terminal and let's go
here to the desktop here you will see a
list of files and here is our files
tiger dot py so the first thing we have
to do is we have to change its mode and
we have to make it executable so let's
right here chmod and our filename and if
I do LS you will see here that now our
file is an executable file so before
running this file we have to install pip
which is actually a Python lab library
manager which is used to install python
libraries so just right here apt-get
install python yep and this file
staggered py is actually compatible with
Python 2.7 meanwhile let's read out the
source code of that file so when our
Python purpose is also installed so
let's see that what's inside this file
ok so here you can see that Here I am
importing some libraries steganography
libraries then I have added this parser
which actually takes three parameters
the first one is carrier in which we
will specify a carrier file then styro
text in which we will write down a text
which will be hidden inside our file and
in the last the third parameter is
actually used to find out the hidden
text behind any image file and here I
have created two functions def hi text
which is used to hide the text behind
the file and then def fine text which is
used to find the text behind any file so
this says a small source code of this
file and here you can see that now our
pep is installed so you can just read
its main page
so it's a tool for installing managing
Python packages now let's install
steganography package in our system so
that can be imported by our file so just
right down here pip install
steganography hit enter
okay and here you can see that this
steganography package is successfully
installed now let's do LS and here is
our file so first of all let's run this
file and let's pass it one parameter
called as help in order to see that what
kind of parameters this file accepts so
here you can see that right now we can
give three parameters the first
parameter is carrier in which in which
we will specify the path of a carrier
file which will contain our text then
the next parameter we have to give - -
stego text and way in which in which we
will enter the text - height now the
third parameter is used to find out the
text behind an image so first of all you
can see here that on my text of there is
one image called as demo dot jpg so with
me just rename it and make it as demo
okay so let's run this file Python
staggered py and let's give the first
parameter that is carrier and here I
will specify that file name jpg name
called as demo dot jpg then I will give
a next parameter that is tag Oh text and
here I will write down a text which I
want to hide behind this file so let it
be this is secret and just hit enter so
it's give us an error no file or demo
dot jpg okay I think we have to rename
it again
now let's see what happened okay so here
you can see that our script is running
and behind this shell on my desktop you
can see that this script has created a
new file called a stager dot PNG and
this file actually contains a text
behind it so what we can do is we can
even check the properties of our old
file so you can see here that it's size
is 138 kV and now let's just take the
property of our new image file which is
created by the script and its properties
is 7 7 8 KB so you can see here that
there is change in the size and even in
small little exif data in this new image
now let's do one thing now let's try to
find out the text which is present
inside this file star dot PNG so we have
to run over this file against a Godot py
but here this time we will specify this
parameter - - star go find and we'll
give the path or the name of this file
stager dot PNG so let's just write here
stego fine and here we'll specify the
name that is stager dot PNG and we'll
see that whether the script is able to
find the text which is hidden in this
file or not so just hit enter and here
you will see that we have founded one
text hidden text found and this was the
text which was found this is secret so
this is how we can hide a text behind
any image file so this was a short demo
of steganography but this was all about
Linux means we can run the script on
Linux and windows but what about you
want to hide a one file behind another
file means there are two images file you
want to hide one image file behind
another image file or you want to hide
an PC
file behind an image file so in order to
do so there is a very good tool called
as invisible secrets so you can see here
so you can download this tool from here
invisible secrets dot-coms les downloads
and it's available for two versions the
pro one and the free one so I have
downloaded and install this one this
free trial copy so you can download it
from here so once you download this tool
and install this tool so it will looks
like this so you have to click over here
continue trial and if you want to buy
this tool then you can because this tool
is very good tool in cryptography so
here you can see the menu of this tool
so it contains lot of functions like
hide files we can hide files and we can
unhide files even we can encrypt files
using a particular algorithm we can
decrypt the files we can create ourself
decrypting packages we can even send the
file from one IP to another IP by using
secure password transfer even we can
lock a particular application in our
computer like you have downloaded and
installed one software and you want to
encrypt that software and you want to
lock that software so that the another
user will not be able to access that
software then you can with the help of
this function logged application but
first of all we'll see that how we can
hide one file behind another file and on
my desktop you can see here I have two
images the first one is carrier and the
second one is height now let's do one
thing click over here hide files and at
the first here we have to give the file
which we want to hide in the carrier
file means here at the first point we
have to give the file which we want to
hide so let's give this file click over
here add files and select this file
click on next and here we have to
specify the name of a carrier file which
will carry the hide file
so click over here now this time we'll
give this file carrier
okay so karyotype is jpg and let's click
over here view jpg image so this is the
image which will be displayed after this
steganography or after hiding this file
so click on next and click over here
wipe carrier file after process so once
this file is hidden inside the carrier
file this image will be deleted and the
new image will come and there is one
more option that we can even specify a
password in order to encrypt our file so
if you want to give a password then you
can otherwise you can skip this
encryption but I think it's not letting
us to skip let's just add the password
here
so let's write here demo and here you
can select a particular encryption
algorithm you want to use so I use this
Blowfish click on next and here we have
to add or write down the name of a new
file which will be created and which
contain this height dot jpg file so
click over here and we can even select a
particular location so we want I want to
save a new file on my desktop and the
new file name will be new hidden click
on save and here click on hide and here
you can see that our carrier file is
deleted and a new file named as Newton
is created on my desktop so if I open
this file you can see a no change but
let's try to find out the size of this
file it's 1 MB but here you can see that
its size is increased because it
contains this file in itself now click
on next and finish so now you can send
this file to anyone and in order to
unhide this file or to retrieve the
hidden file from this file so first of
all let's do one thing let's delete this
file hide ok now click on unhide files
and here we have to give the location of
the file which contains hidden file and
here is that file new hidden click on
open and click on next and here we have
to specify the password which we have
given while hiding that file and we have
to select a particular algorithm which
was used while encryption so I have used
this Blowfish so I have to use the same
algorithm in order to decrypt click on
next and here you can see that this tool
has found one file named as hi dot jpg
inside this file so where we want to
retrieve it so let's retrieve this
height or jpg file on my desktop so
select this click on OK click on unhide
and here you will see a new file called
as hi dot jpg which was actually hidden
this file is retrieved so this is how
you can hide a one file behind another
file by using this tool invisible
secrets now let's see how we can encrypt
files by using this tool so click over
here in crypt files so here we have to
give the location of file which we want
to encrypt and we can even encrypt a
particular folder so click on add files
let's try to encrypt this file hide hi
dot jpg click on open and click on next
and here we have to specify the password
we can even select a particular
algorithm now this time that means like
tarsi for that is reverse cipher for
algorithm click on encrypt and click on
finish and here you will see a file
called as hi dot jpg is created and if
we just look at its properties
it says invisible secrecy encrypted file
and in order to and if you open this
file it will ask us for the password so
we have two right here password we have
to select the same algorithm rc4 click
on decrypt and here you see do you want
to replace it yes and here you can see
that we got our same file hi dot jpg so
this is how we can encrypt a file we can
decrypt the files by using this tool so
you have to click over here logged
application in order to lock or encrypt
a particular application in Windows so
let's click over here and when for the
first time you will open this link local
application it will ask you for entering
a new password and then confirm password
and I have already set it my password so
that's why it's not asking me to enter a
new password and it's asking me to enter
a existing one so let me enter my
password here
and here you can see that right now we
are inside this menu lock applications
and here is one button lock new
application so click over here and it
will search and list out all the
application which is installed in our
computer here you can see here now let's
do one thing let's try to log this
calculator so hit enter
because it is in use okay so let's try
to log this one okay so here you can see
that I have locked this Python ID le and
now click on finish and now here you can
see that if I search for Python and so
here you will see that I'm seeing the
Python ideally 3.6 but the Python
ideally which I have logged is Python
2.7 and you can see that that Python 2.7
is nowhere even we can confirm it by
going to Python directory it's here
python 2.7 and if i scroll down you will
see that there is a no file of python
ideally that is 2.7 python now in order
to decrypt or unhide that file or the
application we have to click over here
log the application again we have to add
our password here click on ok select
this application and click on unlock
selected and you will see now that
application is not locked we can even
confirm it by just typing here python
and here you will see at the top we got
our ID le python so this is how a stack
monography works and in this video we
have discussed that what is technical
fee and how we can hide one file behind
another file by using steganography
techniques thanks for watching this
video