hello everyone now let's talk about
email header analysis so as we all know
that the email stands for electronic
mail and it's one of the most popular
medium used in order to send our data or
send our message across the internet but
what does the email consists of so email
consists of three things the first one
is envelope email body and email header
so the email envelope actually contains
some server configuration settings files
and data which actually used for routing
and the email envelope can't be seen by
the user then the next part of the email
which the emails ancestors body so the
email body actually consists our message
which we see and then the next part of
the email is email header so email
header contains interesting information
which one can use to find a good
information that from where the email
came from and what's the IP of that
sender so the email header consists of a
message ID date to from and user agent
also and IP address of originated server
or the IP address of receiver so
analyzing the email header is important
because through analyzing email header
we can come to know that from where the
email came from and whether it came from
a legitimate resource and whether it's a
fake email now let's see how we can
analyze email by analyzing its header
now let's analyze email header in order
to find out the sender's IP address so
the first of all you have to do is you
have to open any email and here you can
see that I have opened this emails and
this email was sent by CloudFlare so
just click over here and now click over
here show original and here you will see
the email header so the first thing we
have to do is we have to copy this email
header so once we got the him a letter
then we can analyze it so let's just
start copying it from here and we have
to copy it before the body starts and we
have to copy it here and here you can
see that right after this email header
our body starts so just copy this email
header and then we have to go here to
this website that is what is my IP
dot-com slash email header
lyza so there are a lot of other
websites which provide the same
functionality of analyzing email headers
so example of that websites are like MX
toolbox com you get signal com so what
we have to do is just paste the
simulator here click on analyze and here
you will see the sender's IP information
so here you can see the email source IPS
this so this is the IP address of the
sender and the host name is also same
and here you can see the email source IP
lookup info that this IP is of United
States the countries United States and
city is Hillsborough and here you can
find out the longitude latitude along
with the area code and the ISP
information also along with the
organization name so in order to just
verify we can just go here to what is my
IP address comm and we can copy the
sender's IP address from here and let's
go here and paste the IP address here in
the search bar click on search and here
you will see the list of information or
the list of details of this IP and if I
scroll down you will found the same
information the host name along with ISP
CloudFlare and first scroll down a
little bit more you will see here
continent country state city along with
the longitude and latitude so this is
how we can analyze email header in order
to find out the IP address of sender so
in this video we have covered that what
is the importance of analyzing email
header and how we can analyze him al
header thanks for watching this video