hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about WN authentication or wireless LAN
authentication so there are two types of
authentication which are being supported
by WLAN so the first one is open
authentication and the second one is
shared authentication so in open
authentication there is no need of
adding a passphrase we can just simply
connect to the access point without
adding any passphrase but in the case of
shared authentication phosphorus is
required and that passphrase should be
present both on client side as well as
on access for inside so this is the two
Thant ocation which are being supported
by WLAN now let's talk about that what
kind of encryption are supported by
wireless local area network so right now
if I talk about personal WLAN so you can
see here that for the personal WLAN
authentication there are two encryptions
which are being used so the first one is
WEP and the second one is WPA and wpa2
so I'm not talking about enterprise WLAN
standard so I am just talking about WLAN
encryption of personal network so you
can see here now we will talk about each
of them in bit more detail so first of
all we'll talk about WEP encryption so
WEP stands for Wired equivalent privacy
and this WEP is no used anymore because
it's less secure as well as its most
vulnerable so you can see here that the
WEP encryption uses rc4 algorithm and
it's a less secure and it's going to be
depreciated so you can see here that
here is our client and here is our
access point so the first of all the
client will send authentication requests
to that access point and once our access
point receives authentication request
from the client then that access point
will send a long random text of 128 bit
as a challenge to the client so you can
see here that our access point in
sending 128 bytes random text as a
challenge to the client so once our
client receives that 128 bytes long text
then what our client will do and client
will encrypt that challenge or encrypt
that text with the passphrase and by
using rc4 algorithm and once our client
generate our long rc4 key streams after
encrypting that challenge our client
will send that challenge or the rc4 key
stream to the access point back so you
can see here that our client is sending
our c4 key sting to the access point and
once the key stream is accepted by the
access point then what access point will
do the access point will decrypt the key
string with the key which is present
inside the access point and then it
matches the challenge which it sends
down the second step and if the
challenge is matched then
the 10th occasion is successful and the
data transfers between a client and a
access point begins so this was in the
case of WEP but we know that most of the
security researchers started founding
vulnerabilities and the weaknesses in
the encryption of WEP then what happen
is the I Triple E Committee has
introduced another kind of wireless
encryption switch are far better than
WEP and data encryption standard was WPA
so WPA stands for Wi-Fi protected access
and WPA uses tkip and this WPA was based
on WEP and you can see here that
hardware changes are not required so
what happen is at that time our access
point used WEP and if we want our access
point and if we want to configure our
access point to use WPA
then there is no need of changing the
hardware so this is the main benefit of
WPA and the WPA was also available for
personal as well as enterprise but later
on the I Triple E committee has
introduced another encryption which was
the advancement of WEP WPA and that was
wpa2 so wpa2 was also called as Wi-Fi
protected access but instead of using
peak if wpa2 uses ccmp but the thing to
be notice say that in order to use WPA
the hardware changes are required so at
that time if I talked about that time
when the people use WEP so if we want to
configure our wireless access point to
use WPA then at that time hardware
changes were required but nowadays our
hardware are highly equipped then there
are no changes required they by default
support WPA and wpa2 encryption so this
wpa2 encryption is also available for
personal as well as enterprise use so
now we will see that how WPA and wpa2
encryption works so the communication or
the encryption of WPA and wpa2 is
divided into two steps so first of all
this the first
generating shared keys and the second
step is four weig handshake so first of
all I will talk about generating
pre-shared keys so what are the
pre-shared keys
so the ppreciate keys are the first
steps of WPA and wpa2 encryption so you
can see here that here is over user and
once our user add a passphrase so you
can see here our passphrase and this
passphrase then it passed through this
function that is PB pbkdf2 function that
is password-based key derivation
function and once our passphrase is
passed through this function then we got
a pre-shared key of 256 bit so this was
on the client side but similarly on the
access point side the same process take
place so what happen is the access point
also generate the same key pre-shared
key of 256 bit and if these two keys
that is on a client side as well as the
access point side match then the next
process take place and that process is
of encrypting the communication and that
process is called as form a handshake
now let's see how hora handshake works
so you can see here that once our
connection is established between the
client and access point so in this
connection establishment the client and
access point must have pre shared key on
both sides so here you can see the once
the connection is established our access
point will send a long random value to
the client so why our access point is
sending a longer end of value to client
because instead of static keys the WPA
and wpa2 wpa2 uses dynamic keys in order
to encrypt our session so once our
access point sends long random value to
the client and this long render value is
called as a nouns that is access point
nouns and once our client receives a
nouns then the client will send s nouns
or that is supplicant nouns plus mi see
that is message integrity check to the
access for it and once our access point
to receive the s noms
what access point will do the access
point will send a key by a key
installation message or a packet with
the key installation and once the key is
installed on a client side the client
will send acknowledgement that is key
economic
so this is how all the process works in
the WPA and wpa2 that the first of all
the client and the access point generate
appreciate keys and then they will do
form a handshake in order to encrypt the
session now what we will do we will try
to sniff for a handshake between a
client and access point then we will see
that how we can find a password from
that four-way handshake
now let's see how we can crack WPA and
wpa2 wireless encryption so first of all
we have to start our Kali Linux and here
you can see that my colleague Linux is
up and running and I have plugged in my
wireless adapter so now let's just
verify so here you can see that I have
already plugged in my wireless adapter
and I have converted my wireless
interface to monitor mode here you can
see wlan0 moon so we will use this
interface to capture wireless handshake
then we will apply dictionary attack
over that handshake well I told you
earlier that what is WPA handshake or WP
handshake is nothing but just a
communication between a client and
access point at the time when client and
passphrase to that access point so what
I'm going to do here is first of all we
will sniff the packets by using
airodump-ng let's see on which channel
this access point is residing
so you can see here that I have set it
up the SSID for my access point called
as wireless hacking demo so you can see
here and my access point is residing at
channel 6 so let's do one thing let's
copy this be SSID and then we will sniff
or capture the packet of particular this
be SSID so now let's just write here
airodump-ng then I am specifying here a
particular channel so channel is 6 then
let us specify here be SSID and then
interface that is wlan0 Mon and then
here we will save this packet in a dump
file so by adding here this argument hi
- w and here we will write a name called
as WPA so if I hit enter here you will
see that we are monitoring and capturing
the packets off this access point called
as wireless hacking and you can see it's
be SSID so now what I am going to do is
I will turn on Wi-Fi on my mobile phone
and then I will connect my mobile phone
with my this wireless router and you
will see here that we will capture a WP
handshake at this point so let me turn
on Wi-Fi of my mobile phone and let me
enter a passphrase
so I have entered my pass phrase and you
will see here that we got a WPA
handshake so this is the first way of
collecting WPA handshake so let me just
stop this packet collection so the main
thing we want is a WPA handshake so here
you have noticed that I have added a
password or I have connected with my
wireless access point now what else you
can do is in order to get to the bloopy
handshake of a particular access point
what you can do you can first send a
Death packet to that access point and as
soon as access point accepts that Diaz
packet the access point will send a do
tenth occasion message to all its client
and once the clients receives the
authentication message then the client
sends an authentication message back to
the access point and at that point we
will get our WP handshake it's another
method of getting a WPA handshake now
let's check our dump and here you can
see that we got one file called as WPA
oh one dot tap and this file contains
our handshake now we will use this file
in order to crack the password well
there is one utility in kali linux
called as aircrack-ng which we can use
in order to crack wireless passwords but
before going further so let me take you
to the directory in kali linux which
contains lot of word lists which we can
use in order to crack the wireless
password so that word list directory is
present inside user us our shear and
word list so you can see its path it's
present inside us our share and the
directory name is word list so this
directory contain lots of folders and
directories and files which contains
million of passwords so you can see here
all the directories named as the a our
directory buster DNS map and an map LST
Metasploit so there is one file called
as Rho Q dot txt dot GZ so you can see
here so this file contains near about
fourteen million passwords which we can
use in order to crack wireless
encryption so here you can see that I
have all
I extracted this file so the way you can
extract this file by just writing here a
small utility name called as runs it
followed by this file name and if you
hit enter you will see here that we got
one file called as rocket or txt now
let's see what's present inside this
file
so you can see here that this file
contains lots of passwords and now let's
check that how many password is present
in this file by using word count utility
so I'm just writing here word count - L
followed by this passphrase file and you
can see here a long values near about 40
million passwords are present inside
this file so we will use this file in
order to crack the password by using
dictionary attack so let's go back to
our peak app dump file so it's present
here WPA oh one dot cap so what I'm
going to do is I'll just write here
aircrack-ng then here we have to specify
one argument or we have to give one
parameter called as - W and here we have
to give the location of that txt
password file and that file is present
inside us I share then wordless and that
file name and then we have to give the
location or the name of this P kept file
which is WPA
cap just hit enter and just sit freely
and it will start cracking passwords for
you so you can see here that it has
started finding all the passwords and
here you can see the current passphrase
so we have to wait for a time meaning
here you can see the master key
transient key and Ipoh Lech Mac so you
can see that number of keys that this
tool has tested and here you can see the
tested rate and this aircrack-ng tool
will also tell us a particular time that
how much time it takes
so I'm pausing this video and I'll
resume the video once we got our
password and you can see here that we
got our key so our password is RR 9 7 rd
bi so here you can see that this
aircrack-ng utility is able to find out
the password and here you can see that
the time is was still left but our this
key was present in this location and you
can see here it's master key is
transient key its Evol H Mac so this is
how we can crack WPA and wpa2 passwords
by using dictionary attack so there are
another attacks which we can do like
brute force attack and we can even
perform the same attack by using cow
patty tool and they are lot of tools so
in this video we have discussed that how
WPA and wpa2 handshake or encryption
works and how we can crack the WPA and
wpa2 encryption by using aircrack-ng so
thanks for watching this video