hello everyone in this video we will
talk about different encryption
algorithms which we can use in order to
in kept our data so in the last video I
told you about ciphertext that the
ciphertext is obtained after converting
our plaintext or after encrypting our
plaintext and the cipher text is in the
unreadable form so that a normal person
can't be understand that what's the
meaning of that cipher text now we will
discuss about types of type ciphers
first so there are two types of ciphers
the first one is stream cipher and the
second one is block cipher so the stream
ciphers know what a stream ciphers so
stream ciphers actually encrypt one
digit at a one time just for example our
data contains five digits that is hello
H e double L o so the first digit that
is H will be encrypted first then the
next digit that is e encrypted then the
L will be encrypted then another L and
then o will be encrypted so in the
stream cipher one digit is encrypted at
a one time and the stream cipher
contains only symmetric key encryption
which means the key for encrypting the
data and the key for decrypting the data
will be same now let's talk about block
cipher so as a name suggests block which
means the block cipher converts a
particular block or the block cipher
encrypt a particular bit of block so
here you can see that it operate on a
fixed length of a group called as block
so one group at a one time which means
one group of a block that is a 64-bit
will be converted at a one time so here
you can see that it might be D ciphers
so block ciphers are not secure so they
might be easily deciphered but there are
different different ways and now let us
talk about different kind of encryption
algorithms so the first one is rc4
stream cipher so rc4 algorithm is called
as reversed cipher for and it's actually
a stream cipher which means it will
convert a one digit at a one time and
here you can see that it's also
symmetric key algorithm the key for
encrypting the data and key for
decrypting the data is same now let us
talk about some block ciphers algorithm
so the first one is des algorithm so des
algorithm stands for data encryption
standard here you can see
so data encryption standard algorithm
actually operates on a fixed length of a
block so it's fixed length string so
ciphertext of a plain site and the block
size is 64 bit which means if our data
is actually a 128-bit then the first
64-bit will be encrypted first then the
another 64-bit will encrypted after our
the previous 64-bit data and one more
thing to be noticed that in the block
ciphers the key the key and the size of
a data which convert at one time is same
so as the des algorithm is actually
converting the block size of 64 bit data
which means it's key should be also of
64-bit but this des algorithm is verne
able to brute-force attack or different
dictionary attacks so that's why it's
not secure so in order to make it secure
information security researchers
actually developed one more algorithm
that is three DES so three DES algorithm
stands for triple data encryption
standard so in addition to DES this
algorithm contains three keys so in
order to protect our data and with the
help of these three keys our data is
secure from different kind of password
guessing attacks like dictionary attack
and Booth force attacks and in the last
there is one algorithm called as AES
which is one of the most popularly used
algorithm around the globe so ei stands
for advanced encryption standard so this
is the one of the most powerful
algorithm which is used for encrypting
our data why because the key size of
this AES algorithm is 128-bit 256 bit
and even five one two bit key which
means the key size is 128 five one two
and the data or the block size should be
the same as the size of the key so
that's why this algorithm AES should be
considered one of the most powerful
algorithm used in the world now let's
see how encryption work with the help of
one Python program now let's have a look
at different encryption algorithms and
they're working so in the previous video
we have downloaded this clipped Swiss
crypto and in this video I will use the
same script so let us open the script so
as I told you earlier that the
encryption is of to type symmetric and
so in symmetric encryption the key for
encrypting the data and the key for
decrypting the data is same whereas in
asymmetric encryption the key for
encrypting and the key for decrypting
the data is different so this tool which
I have created actually supports
symmetric encryption at this time so let
us click over here and then it asks us
for the cipher we want to use so first
of all let us click over here to the
block cipher and we know that there are
different kind of block cipher
algorithms but common one our advanced
encryption standard algorithm and data
encryption standard algorithm so first
of all we'll discuss data encryption
standard algorithm so click over here as
soon as we click over here it asks us
for the data to convert so as I told you
earlier that in data encryption standard
algorithm we always have to add the data
and multiple of it which means if I add
here hello 1 2 3 so the total length of
this data is 8 so we have to add data
multiple of eights means if you want to
add more data we have to add the till 16
then 24 and multiple of eights so let's
click over here to ok and here you will
see that our data is converted to the
cipher text and here we got our
encrypted text you can see here and here
is our key encryption key which we got
but you might be wondering that why this
key is not a long random key the reason
is that I haven't added a random key
generation function in data encryption
standard algorithm and this Python
program so that's why I have made this
key constant in this Python program so
that's why you are seeing this eight
digits key so the another reason of
making this key constant is that I want
to show you that the key or in DES
algorithm is always should be in eight
digits or in the multiple of AIDS so the
data and the key should always be in
multiple of eight so now let's try to
decrypt the data encryption standard
algorithm so let's click over here
decryption symmetric encryption
then we have to select the decryption
algorithm so the point to be notice is
that we have to select the same
algorithm which we have used in order to
encrypt the data so let's select this
and here it asks us for the key to
decrypt and our key is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
and let's copy our encrypted text or a
cipher text from here from this Python
shell and let me paste it here and click
on decrypt give us an error okay I think
we misses something so we have to copy
the text very carefully otherwise it
will give us an error and let me paste
it here click on decrypt and here you
will see that we got our normal text
back that is hello 1 2 3 so this is how
data encryption standard worked so and
the main disadvantage of data encryption
standard is that it always accept the
data and key in multiple of 8 bits and
there is some restriction of ethat we
can't add up to 64 bit so that is why
the key size is very small in data
encryption standard which is vulnerable
to some brute-force attacks now let's
have a look at advanced encryption
standard and it's working and let's
start the script again let's go here
block ciphers and now now let this time
click over here advanced encryption
standard so in advanced encryption
standard we can add the data and but
it's not mandatory that we have to add
the data in multiple of it which means
we can add any data of any size just for
example let's write here this is secret
and if I click on OK here you will see
that our text is encrypted and we got
our encrypted text here at the bottom
and above it we got our long random key
the same thing we got in Python shell
you can see here so this is the beauty
of advanced encryption standard that the
size of key is very long that makes the
key and our data secure from wolf force
attack so we can add here any data click
on OK you will see we got
another key parent encrypted text so
this is how advanced encryption standard
work and in order to decrypt it the
steps are same so this this was all
about block ciphers algorithm now let's
have a look at one stream cipher
algorithm that is rc4 so let's go here
encryption symmetric encryption then
stream cipher rc4 algorithm that is
reversed cipher four and here it asks us
for enter the key and data so as I told
you earlier that in rc4 algorithm it's
not mandatory that we have to add data
in multiple of eight bits so we can add
here any key like hello let's make it as
hello one two three so it's every key or
a password and let's add here text which
we want to encrypt so our text will be
you can write here anything very secret
so if I click on convert you will see
that we got our cipher text or encrypted
text so let's copy this text from here
and now let's go here to decryption
let's try to decrypt this text we have
to select the same algorithm rc4 so here
we have to add our key so our key was
hello one two three and our text which
we have copied so I have pasted it here
click on OK and here you will see that
we got our normal text back that is very
secret so this is how block ciphers
stream ciphers and the different
algorithm works so this was the short
example of demonstration of different
encryption algorithms so in this video
we have covered that what are different
ciphers and what are different
algorithms supported by them so thanks
for watching this video