hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about VPN so what is VPN so we peel
stands for virtual private network so
VPN is same like a proxy but with a
little difference so the difference is
that VPN is more secure than proxy why
because a VPN creates a tunnel between
us and the internet so you can see here
that here is our computer here is
Internet and the VPN creates a tunnel so
by using this tunnel technique our data
or our communication will get encrypted
so once our data or communication is
encrypted then nobody can intercept our
request or can figure out that what's
going on so you can see here that here
are hackers government so nobody can
intercept our request why because our
request will be protected by the VPN and
the VPN uses various protocol in order
to secure our communication so you can
see here that the VPN stands for virtual
private network and it's a secure tunnel
between two or more devices it's same
like a proxy but the thing is we cannot
intercept our request now let's talk
about benefits of VPNs so the benefits
of VPN are somehow same with the
benefits of proxies but with a little
difference so the first benefit is that
we can hide our IP address as well as
location so we can use three protocol in
order to secure our data or a
communication so the first protocol
which VPN uses PP to PPTP protocol
so the pptv protocol stands for
point-to-point tunneling protocol which
is used in order to make a tunnel
between us and a remote server so the
next protocol which VPN uses lt2
protocol so Alta to be protocol stands
for layer 2 tunneling protocol which is
responsible for creating a tunnel on OSI
model layer 2 in order to protect our
MAC addresses then the third protocol
which VPN uses is called as IPSec that
is Internet Protocol security by using
this protocol VPN tries to secure our IP
addresses so these are the few
techniques which we can use in order to
secure our communication and encrypt our
communication so then another man if
it's a VPN are same like proxy like we
can view the blocked website we can
change their IP address we can protect
our identity and the main benefit is
that we can prevent
third parties from tracking us so if
over request is encrypted then nobody
can track
nobody can figure out the words present
inside that request now let's see how we
can use cyberghost VPN in order to see
that how we PN works now let's use
cyberghost VPN in order to see that how
VPN works well first of all we have to
download the cyberghost VPN and you can
download that VPN from here from this
URL cyberghost VPN comm and here you
will see one link of free download so
let me click over here and let me save
the executable file so I personally
recommend you to please use cyberghost
VPN in order to serve anything online
because this is the best VPN I have ever
used and let me install this
so you can also buy the premium pack of
this VPN and once this VPN is installed
it will start running and here you can
see that on my desktop icon of
cyberghost is created
and here you can see the first of all it
will tell us with which verify
connection we are connected and here is
the advertisement
let me also close this thing so here you
can see the main menu of cyberghost
there are a lot of options so let's
click over here surf anonymous click on
start an anima surfing and here we have
to wait for a few seconds so this is the
main limitation in the free version of
cyberghost that we have to wait for a
some time in order to access this VPN
and here you can see that they are
saying all free user slots are booked
and your waiting queue position and we
have to wait for these few seconds and I
will resume the video once this seconds
are over now here you can see that our
cyberghost VPN is up and running here
you can see the uptime and now the
cyberghost VPN has replaced our original
IP address and here you can see that the
country is Romania where we are
connected and here you can see the
server location also and if I go here to
the Mozilla Firefox so first of all
let's checks our IP address and here you
can see our IP address is actually an
ipv6 address along with a country name
city and ISP now let's just open
google.com and here you can see that the
Google of Romania is open so this is how
VPN works and by using VPN there is no
need to configure our browser proxy
settings and in order to stop the VPN
you can just click over here stop an
anima surfing so that's it for this
video and in this video we have covered
that what is VPN and how VPN is better
than proxy and then we have discussed
that how we can use cyberghost VPN so
thanks for watching this video