hello everyone in this video we will
cover web application penetration
testing so what is web application
penetration testing so web application
penetration testing is a process of
penetrating the web application and
finding out security issues
vulnerabilities inside them so I have
already made a separate course on web
application penetration testing which
you can find on tutorials point so I
have covered lot of vulnerabilities
inside them and I have listed some
vulnerabilities here so you can see so I
have covered various injection
vulnerabilities like HTML injection
where we can inject HTML into a web
application CSS rejection SQL injection
and demon I have also covered some web
2.0 burn abilities which are highly
complex vulnerabilities like CSRF idor
SS RF attacks server-side request
forgery and even RFI lfi vulnerability
so if you are curious about finding out
security issues and web application or
even if you want to hack websites then
what you can do you can refer my course
of web application penetration testing
and you can check out all the videos so
thanks for watching this video