hello everyone in this video we will
talk about batch files extension so in
the last video you have seen that the
batch files which we have created
contains the extension of dot bat that
is dot dat but if someone just look at
that file then he may or may not open
that file because he can think that it's
a malicious file so its must to change
the extension as well as the icon of our
batch file now how we can do that so we
can change the icon and the extension of
that file by using some softwares so we
can use icon changer in order to change
the icon of that batch file so here you
can see that I have change the icon of
this bat file and here you can see that
it's a Windows batch file but the icon
is changed similarly we can also change
the extension of batch file that is got
dat to dot exe so in order to do that we
can use extension changer in order to
change the extension of that batch files
and here you can see that I have changed
the extension of the batch files now the
extension is hello dot exe now the
extension is dot exe and it's the
executable files so now let's see how we
can change icon as well as extension in
our system now let's try to change icon
as well as extension of batch file in
order to make people believe that the
batch file which we are going to create
is not a malicious one well in order to
change icon and extension we need to
download some softwares so the first
software we have to download it is
called as icon changer which we will use
in order to change the icon so you can
download the software from here from
this link and once you install this
software then the next software which we
will download and install is is called
as bad to exe converter so this software
is used to change the extension of bad
file that is not be a t2 dot exe file so
you can download the software from here
from this link that is f F 2k or dot de
so I have already downloaded and install
both of them in my VirtualBox so let me
open my VirtualBox so you can see here
so here is my icon changer so first of
all let's create a sample batch file
and I'm creating a very simple file
which will just print out a demo user
and let me save this file on my desktop
let me rename it as sample dot bat and
you will see here that here is the file
and if I open this file here you can see
that it's printing out demo user now
let's try to change the icon of that
file so let me open the software so as
soon as I click on that software here
you will see it asks us for the file
which we want to change or we want to
change the icon of that file so we can
also change the icon of a particular
file and even we can change the icon of
entire folder by clicking over here but
for the time being
let's click here file click ok and let's
go here to the desktop and let's select
this file so once we select the file
then the next thing we have to do is we
have to select the icon so you can see a
list of all the icons but these are like
icons are present in our system so this
software has scanned our system and find
out all these icons so if you are not
entrusted to set these kind of icons
then what you can do is you can download
icons from the internet also there are a
lot of free websites which provides free
icons but the thing to be notice is that
the icon which you will download from
the internet must have the extension of
dot ICO that stands for dot icon then
the software will pick that I can
otherwise not but for the time being
let's try to change the icon and let's
try to put it this so as soon as I click
over here
you can see that this comes in set so if
I click over here set and let's go back
and here you will see that the icon of
our batch file is changed and let's
check its property you can see here the
windows batch file so this is how we can
change the icon but now let's see how we
can change the extension of this batch
file so let me start my bad to exe
convertor so here you can see that the
bad to exe converter which I have
downloaded from that website and
installed in
my system so here at the top I have to
give the location of a batch file or I
have to select a particular one so let
me click over here click on desktop and
here is our batch file click on open
then at the bottom just after the batch
file you will see here a save as so here
you can specify a particular name and
the extension should be dot exe because
it's a dot exe converter and here you
will see a lot of options so if I click
over here the first thing is visibility
whether you want to make it visible or
not some very yes we want to make it
visible now the next thing is we want to
add administrative privileges or not so
as I told you earlier in the previous
video that there are some batch files
which requires administrative privileges
to run so what happen is if I open this
batch file you can see here it doesn't
ask for administrative privilege but if
I select this option then what happen is
once the file is converted into dot exe
file and when I open dot exe file the
first thing it asks us for the giving
the administrative privileges so if you
want to give identity privileges to the
file then you can select this option
otherwise you can just simply uncheck
and there is one more feature of this
tool that even we can encrypt a program
by specifying a particular password but
we are not interested and the main thing
to be notice is that we have to select a
particular architecture of where we are
converting the exe file so whether your
target system is 64-bit then you have to
select this one and if your target
system is 32-bit then you have to select
this one so let me select here and
another thing which you can do is you
can even specify a version information
so if you click here include version
information then it just add a fake
random version information in our exe
file so that the people can't be figure
out that it's a malicious one so they
will trust now let's go back here to the
options and let's click on compile and
you will see here that the file Exe file
named as sample is created and if I
check
properties you can see here this
application in dot exe but in order to
confirm that whether it's working or not
let's double click on this file and you
will see that this file is still working
and Held's printing demo user in this
video we have discussed that how we can
change the icon as well as the extension
of batch files in order to make people
believe that they are clicking on a
genuine file so thanks for watching this
video