hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about very important concept called as
IDs and IPS system so idea stands for
intrusion detection system whereas IP
stands for intrusion prevention system
so these both systems works together in
order to detect intruder activity on our
network and once they found intruder
activity then they take appropriate
steps in order to stop that activity so
here you can see that here is our local
area network here is our idea system
here is our firewall router and internet
so any request for internet which is
going into our local area network will
have to pass from IDs and any requests
which will go out from our local area
network have to be pass from IDs so into
gene detection system and intrusion
prevention system are can either be a
hardware or a combination of both or
combination of hardware and software
which we can deploy on our network and
the web application in order to detect
intruder activity so depending upon
their capabilities that how complex they
are they use different techniques in
order to scan intruder activities on our
network so some of their techniques
which they use are signatures so they
match the signature of malicious packets
with the original one and some of them
may use anomaly based techniques in
order to detect intruder activity and
intrusion detection systems are
different types depending upon on which
platform we want to deploy so some of
the examples are n IDs so an ID a stands
for network intrusion detection systems
which are deployed on a network in order
to scan intruder activity or hackers
activity on a network whereas HID stands
for host intrusion detection system
which are deployed on a particular host
in order to scan intruder activity on
that host whereas some of intrusion
detection systems are also deployed on
web application in order to scan or
detect hackers activity on that web
application so there is one open source
an IDs network into injection system
called as snot so we will use not in
this video to see that how we can deploy
an IDs on our network and we can detect
intruder activities so you can see here
that snot is an open source network into
an induction system and it's available
for Linux and Windows and you can
download snot
here from the official website that is
not dot all right now let's see how we
can deploy it's not now let's deploy and
configure snot on our network well we
can download snot from here from their
official website
snot dot dot and here you can see that
right now I am on snot Ark so let me go
here to down notes so you can deploy
snot on any operating system like you
want to deploy snot on your windows you
can even deploy it's not on cent
operating system on your server and here
you can see the binaries of snot
so these minor E's are available for
different operating systems like the RPM
package for Red Hat 7 and then send to
us but what the time being I'll deploy
the snot on Windows operating system so
let me just click over here so snot here
you can see the binaries of a Windows
installer dot exe so let me click over
here and download the snot dot exe so
let me click on save file so I'm using
Windows 7 as my virtual machine in order
to deploy snot so I have already
downloaded snot dot exe so you can see
here the snot Installer so let me
install snot on my Windows 7 operating
system so here you can see that the snot
installation setup is completed click on
close and the additional thing we have
to do is we have also have to install
wind pcap so which you can download it
from here from wind pcap dark and i have
already downloaded wind pcap installer
here you can see here so let me install
wind pcap also so in peak app is
actually a contains network drivers
which snot will use in order to capture
and sniff network packets so here you
can see that I have installed snot and
winpcap
so let me go to local drive see where
snot is installed and here you will see
that a directory or a folder named as
not is created so if I open this up you
will see the snot directories well I
told you earlier that snot works on
different rules that we can set our own
rule and we can also use predefined
rules in
- let the snot to sniff the packet so
the next thing we have to do is we have
to download the snot rules so in order
to download the snot rules the first
thing you have to do is you have to
create an account and then once you
create an account and snot website you
have to login so let me just login
so once you are logged in the next thing
you have to do is you have to download
the snot rule so go here to downloads
and here you will see one option of
rules so let me click over here
and here you will see a snot rules so we
have to download this one snort rule
snapshot and it's the latest one 298 3
into 9 0 tar and it's a tar file so let
me download this one two nine eight
three tar.gz and I have already
downloaded snot rules and which are
present on my virtual machine so you can
see here a tar file of snort rules so
let me extract it
so if you are deploying snot on your
server then you can follow the same
steps as I'm doing here in my windows so
once we got the snot rules let me open
this up and show you so it contains
different directories the next thing we
have to do is we have to copy these all
directories or a folder and we have to
paste them inside the snot directory
that is inside local drive sea so here
you can see it's not so let me paste all
these folders and files here and then it
asks us that whether we want to replace
some existing one
so yes click over here click on yes so
yes copy and replace everything so here
you can see that our snot is ready to
work the next thing we have to do is we
have to create two files inside the
snort directory so let me open notepad
so you can use any text editor so we
have to create a two files named as
whitelist dot rules and blacklist rot
rules so snot will configure and the
slot will work depending upon our rules
which we will provide so I am creating a
file named as whitelist dot rules so we
have to save this file inside snot
directory so click on snot and here is
one directory called as rules so I am
just leaving this file empty and I'm
renaming it as whitelist dot rules and
then we have to create another file
called as blacklist dot rules and we
have to save it inside that same
directory snot rules so that file name
is blacklist dot rules now here you can
see that the two files blacklist are
rules and whitelist dot rules are
created and I told you earlier that in
this short video I'll just give you a
small overview of snot but in the next
video series of snot I'll show you that
how we can set our own custom rules by
adding them in these two files blacklist
our rules and whitelist our tools
now everything is ready let me give a
small recap that what
have dead so we have downloaded snot and
we have installed the snot
with this wind pcap utility then we have
downloaded snort rules and then we have
extracted the snot rules and we have
copied these all files inside the snot
directory so then we have created two
files that is whitelist or tools and
blacklist our rules now in order to run
snort we have to open command prompt and
we have to go to local Drive see where
snot is installed so let me go there and
here you will see one directory called
as not so let's go there and then we
have to go bin directory which is
present inside snot so here you can see
that right now we are inside snot bin
and inside the bin directory there is
one file called as na dot exe so this is
the file or the main executable file of
snot which we will use so the first
thing we have to do is we have to check
that what are the network adapters or
network interfaces which are available
in this operating system so we can do so
by writing snort exe and then we have to
specify one parameter that is - capital
W hit enter and here you will see that
it has listed out that there is one
interface or a one network adapter which
is present inside this Windows seven so
you can see its index value that it's 1
here you can see the physical address or
a MAC address of that network adapter
here you can see the IP address that is
ipv6 and then here you can see the
description and it's in desktop adapter
you can see here so what this adapter
means so just for example in your
operating system there are two network
adapters means you are also using
Ethernet connection and you are also
using wireless adapter so all the depth
s which are present in your system will
just get listed over here so snot will
actually work on a particular adapter
whether you want to configure snot on
physical adapter whether you want to
configure snot on wireless adapter so
you can by checking the adapter from
here then the next thing we have to do
is in order to snuff snot we just have
to write snot or exe then here
by one parameter that is - V and - V's
for verbose mode then here we have to
specify the network adapter on which we
want to configure the snot so we can do
so by specifying this parameter - I and
here we have to write down the index
number of that network adapter so right
now there is only one network adapter
which is listed over here so I am just
writing here - I and the index number is
1 so hit enter so here you can see that
our snot is started and it just started
sniffing that packets now in order to
verify what we can do let me open
command prompt again now what I am going
to do here is I'll ping the Google comm
and you will see that any internet
packet which will come inside our
network will just get monitored by snot
so if I just write here ping google.com
and you will see that the echo reply of
google.com will be monitored by snot so
if I just hit enter and here you will
see the Eco reply packets echo then you
can reply which means any packets which
are going in and going out from our
network will be monitored by snot so
this is how snot works and in the
advanced video series of snot I will
show you that how we can set our own
custom rules in order to block a
particular traffic or a particular port
but this was a small overview of snot
that how we can deploy snot so in this
video we have discussed that what is not
and what are the different type of idea
systems and then we have seen that how
we can deploy is not on Windows 7 so
thanks for watching this video