hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about that how a wireless access point
and a wireless client communication
takes place so a communication process
between an access point and a client is
divided into six steps so by looking at
this image you can see here that here is
our client and here is our access point
so the first thing is whenever our
client turn on his Wi-Fi then the our
client starts sending a probe request
into the air so you can see here that
first of all our client will send a
probe request into the air so probe
request means that hey I am new here is
there any accessible towards to connect
with me so if there is an access point
who wants to connect with that client so
that access point will send a probe e
spawns to that client and in that probe
response the access point will send a
particular requirement which is needed
in order to connect with that access
point so once the probe response is
received by our client then our client
or our mobile phone will send the
authentication request to that access
point so in that authentication request
our client will send a passphrase to
that access point and once the
passphrase and the authentication
request is accepted by that access point
then that access point will send
authentication response and once our
client receives the authentication
response so till here our access point
communication takes place
so once authentication response is
received by our slides
then our client will send Association
request to an association request nice
ok we are connected now let's start
transferring some data so in order to
transfer some data the first of all our
client will send Association request and
the client will wait for Association
response from access point so these are
the six steps which are needed in order
to communication takes place between our
client and a wireless now let's try to
make Wireless packets and analyze the
how of communication between access
points and a client take place with the
help of Wireshark
now let's analyze a communication
between an access point and a client
with the help of Wireshark
so here you can see that my colleague
Linux is up and running
and I already has captured some packets
with the help of arrow dump utility and
here you can see one pcap file called as
Klein dot tap so let's analyze this file
in Wireshark so first of all I will show
you that how we can add filters in
Wireshark in order to get a clean neat
output so here you can see that right
now there are so many packets and all
these packets are of different clients
but I know that my access point name is
this one so what I am going to do here
is first of all in order to apply a
filter in Wireshark there are two ways
so the first way is that you can write
down a filter here a filter string here
in this bar then other ways you can
select a particular packet and then you
can go to its header and then you can
add a filter so what I'm going to do
here is so first of all I will apply a
filter of a bssid of my access point
then we will get all the packets of that
access point so my access point name is
Hawaii and here you can see that the
bssid of my access point is this so in
order to add a filter just right click
over here we can apply as filter and
click on selected and here you can see
that a string is automatically written
here in this bar and here you can see
the filter now the thing to be notice is
that in the source column all the
packets are of this bssid or our address
so the next thing we have to do is we
can just write here instead of bssid
addr which means address now what i have
to do is we will apply the next filter
of our client so that we can analyze the
communication which is happening between
our access point and a client so my
client name is samson and you will found
one packet of that here and here is that
packet so here is my client so what i'm
going to do here is i'm adding one more
filter of my client bssid
and my client bssid is this so let me
add one more filter
and now this time I will do and select
it and I will change the same and make
it as a DDR hit enter and here you will
see a communication happening between
our access point and our client so while
I told you over here that the first of
all the client will send a probe request
then the access point will send a probe
response
so in this Wireshark packet dump I don't
have any probe request packet but you
can see here a probe response which is
being sent by our access point to our
client so once client got a probe
response then the client will send an
authentication request including
passphrase to that access point and here
you will see an authentication request
which is being sent by our client so you
can see here our client is sending an
authentication request to our access
point and then we'll got the
authentication response and here you can
see the authentication response is being
sent by our access point to our client
and once our client got an nth occasion
response packet then our client will
send an association request to that
access point and right after this packet
you can see here that our client has
sent an association request to this
destination so this destination is our
access point so right after the
authentication response packet here you
can see that our client has sent an
association request to our access point
and once our access point receives
association request then the access
point will send an association response
to our client and here you can see that
as an association response is being sent
by our access point to our client so
this is how and communication between so
this is how a communication between an
access point and a client occurs in
order to transfer data so in this video
we have discussed that how a client and
an access point communication
communicate in order to transfer data so
thanks for watching this video