hello everyone in this video we will
talk about information gathering so what
is information gathering so as I told
you earlier that information gathering
is also called as reference which is the
first phase of ethical hacking so
information gathering is actually
process of well knowing the target and
finding the interesting information
about our target which we can use in
order to exploit that target in the
future so here you can see that it's a
process of well knowing the target
digging details footprinting and keeping
in touch with the target so that's why
we called as in the first phase of
ethical hacking so information gathering
is actually of two types the first one
is active information gathering and the
next one is passive information
gathering so in active information
gathering the information is gathered
directly which means if our target is a
person that in order to get information
from that person by using active
information gathering what we can do we
can gather the information through a
phone call we can do a face-to-face
meeting we can take interview of that
person but whereas in passive
information gathering the information is
gathered using a third party so most of
the hackers use this passive information
gathering techniques in order to gather
information about their targets because
if you use a passive information
gathering techniques then that your
target will not be able to know that
someone is searching information about
me so that's why the passive information
gathering is one of the best so what we
can do is we can even find the
information about our targets using
search engine tools or even from the
third party vendors or web applications
so this is the difference between active
and passive that in actively gathers
information directly and the passive we
gather the information using a third
party or a secretly then let's talk
about passive information gathering
targets so our target could be anything
either it could be a website email
address web server and a person so what
if if our target is a web site then what
we can do so here you can see that the
information gathering web site so just
for example if our target is a web site
then before testing that web site in
order to find vulnerability what we can
do we can gather some interesting
information about that website so that
interesting information my friend
in who is information that what is the
Registrar information of that website we
can find the website DNS records we can
also check on which platform or the
framework that website is built and even
we can do a reverse IP check where we
find that what are the other website
which are hosted on the same web server
so this was all about if our target is a
web site so what if if our target is a
web server then what we can do
so if our target is a web server then in
order to find information about that we
can find it open ports we can find the
services running on that server and if
that port is open we can also try to
make a connection with that port and
even we can find interesting services
which is running on them including their
version number so once we got these
interesting information about our target
then we can use these informations in
order to exploit that target now let's
see how we can do information gathering
through our system now first of all
let's find the Whois information about a
particular web site so in order to find
the Whois information are there a
destroyer information of a particular
website just go to who is dot s C so
there are lot of web sites which
provides the same functionality but this
Web site is one of the best so just
write down who is dot SC and hit enter
so here we have to write the website
name left-side tutorialspoint.com and
click on search
and we have to prove that we have not a
robot so we have to fill this CAPTCHA so
here you can see all the Whois
information of tutorialspoint.com so the
registration organization has tutorials
point India Private Limited and the
Registrar is GoDaddy and here you can
find the domain name server details
along with the IP and the IP location so
if you scroll down here you can find the
website title the response code and some
additional information including the
domain name and the rajah strength name
so this was all about who is calm so
once we find the Whois detail of our
target what we can do is we can do a
reverse IP lookup of our target which
means to check that how many other
websites are hosted on the same server
of our target so to do that go to one
website you get signal calm so this
website provides various features which
we can use in order to do information
gathering of our target but right now we
are interested only in this reverse IP
domain check it also provides the same
who is function of which function also
so here we have to write the website
name
click on check
so here you can see that 80 other
websites 80 other domains are hosted on
the same web servers of
tutorialspoint.com so by checking the
reverse IP it also give us some idea
that whether our target is hosted on a
shared web server or a dedicated web
server so for an example if I just write
here google.com and click on check now
here you can see that 124 domains are
hosted on the same web server of
google.com but here notice that all the
domains are associated with google.com
which means this is a dedicated hosting
or a dedicated server now the next step
after collecting the Whois information
and the reverse IP check is finding the
subdomains of our target so to do that
we have to start our Kali Linux so right
now I am inside my Kali Linux instance
so in order to find the subdomains
I am using this Knox subdomains scan so
it's a very good tool to find the
subdomains and you can download it from
here from this URL otherwise what you
can do is you can even install it
manually by going to command line so now
now let's install the stool so here is
my terminal which you can just see and
let me just copy this thing so it's a
Python script so that's why it's
installing by using pip
so just paste the command here and hit
on enter
first of all it will download this zip
file and install this so I have already
installed this tool so it will just give
me an error that requirement already
satisfied okay
so now in order to run this tool we have
we have to write down knock PI followed
by the website name of which we want to
scan the subdomains just for example
just write down here google.com and hit
enter
so here you can see that it's performing
some checks and some scans
okay now how you can see that started in
emulating the different subdomains of
google.com so here you can see the sub
domain name like accounts.google.com
status and along with its IP address
there are some additional websites which
you can use to find out the subdomains
but most of the times that not work so I
recommend you to find out the subdomains
by downloading this tool so once we done
with it then the next step is to
detecting the operating system on which
the website is hosted because if we know
as a pentester that on which operating
system the website is hosted we can just
find out the ways to exploit the
operating system so in order to find the
operating system on which the website is
hosted there are different different
ways but the most easy way is to just
the ping that website and check the
response now let me open my command
prompt so just for example I am writing
here ping and the website name and hit
enter so hey so if I just look at the
response so here you can see reply from
bite and TTL value so here is the thing
to be notice
TTL value so TTL stands for time to live
so if the TTL value of any of the
website is near about 60 or less than 60
then it means then the website is hosted
on a Linux a Linux server so if the TTL
value is more than 50 or more than 60
which means then the website is hosted
on a Windows
so if the TTL value is near about 110 or
more than 110 then that means that the
website is hosted on windows server so
once we find the operating system then
the last step is to find that on which
platform the website is hosted or the
website is running whether the website
is running on WordPress or on any
content management system or the website
is running or some kind of framework
like PHP or any open source language so
in order to accomplish that task there
is one website called as built with calm
so here we have to write the URL
okay so now it's showing us the detail
of techcrunch.com
so web server you can see that the web
server is nginx and the SSL certificate
is WordPress SSL means this website is
running somehow on WordPress so here you
can also find the registrar detail
GoDaddy and name server is a WordPress
again so email servers in email services
details then hosting providers and
content management system so this
website techcrunch.com is actually
running on WordPress which is a content
management system and the framework is
PHP and if I go down you will find a lot
of juicy details juicy information
interesting information about JavaScript
libraries version audio video media
payment providers also even if it's
using and you can also find out the
detail of CDN content delivery network
of your website and meta tag information
so recapture information also all the
techniques which we can use to find the
important information of our target so
thanks for watching this video