hello everyone in this video we will
talk about an interesting tool which we
can use in order to see Windows password
in a plain text so that tool is called
as mimikatz so mimikatz is an open
source tool which we can use in order to
find Windows password in a plain text so
you can download mini cats from here
from this github link so the main
feature of this tool is that we don't
need any same file we don't need any
system file all we just need is this
tool in order to view Windows password
so you can think of that it's very good
tool because we don't need to crack any
password all we have to do is we just
have to download this tool and we have
to use this tool over a particular
system now let's see how we can use many
cats in our system now let's try to find
windows password in a plain text without
using any kind of password cracking
techniques well in order to find windows
password in a plain text we have to
download the small utility called as
mimikatz so this is a very small utility
purely written in c language and with
the help of this we can find a Windows
password in a plain text so here you can
see a link of its binaries and a link of
its source code also so let me open the
link of it binaries in the next step and
here is official block of this tool blog
dot genteel tv.com slash mimikatz and
here you can see the github page of this
mini katz and it's available in
different versions along with the source
code but i recommend you to download
this file movie catstrong because it's a
stable one and i have already downloaded
and stored this file in my Windows 7
operating system so you can see here an
archive of this file so let me extract
all the files and here you can see that
a directory named as mimikatz trunk is
created now let me open this up so
depending upon your system architecture
that whether your system is 32-bit or
64-bit you can download one of them and
let me open this one windows 32 because
my system is windows 32-bit operating
system and here you can see the
maquettes application well in order to
run this application we have to run it
as an administrator so click over here
and
it looks similar to the command prompt
you can see here a same command prompt
then the first of all we have to do is
we just have to give a privilege to
mimikatz
so just right here privilege then to
Collins then debug and here you can see
that in the response card we got 20
which means successful then in order to
find hostname of a particular operating
system where we are using this mini cats
just write down here hostname and hit
enter here you will see that the host
name is root and we can just verify it
from here and then in order to find a
Windows password just write down here as
seek a URL si to Collins then log on
passwords hit enter and here you will
see a long output so let's read this so
here you can see that the username is
root and the domain name is root PC and
it will also give us the logon server
along with the login time and if I
scroll down here you will see that it
also showing the s ID and here you can
see the username is root and here you
can see the element ntlm hashes along
with the sha-1 hash of my password and
just below it you can find a username
root along with it password that is true
so here you can see that it's very very
simple tool which can be used in order
to find windows password in the
plaintext so here you can see that the
password it's displaying to assess to
and if I scroll down you will see a bit
more detail so this is how you can use
this tool in order to find windows
password in a plaintext so the thing is
that this tool uses a little memory
trick in order to find passwords but if
you use this tool in Windows 8 and
Windows 10 our Windows operating system
treat this tool as a malware so be sure
that you have to turn off your anti
viruses before running this tool so what
else you can do is you can just put this
tool in your USB Drive then you can
create one batch file
and if you plug in that USB Drive in any
operating system then it will start
running that batch file and it will
store the output of this tool in a
notepad file and then you can just plug
it off that USB Drive and in that USB
Drive you will get the password of the
operating system in which you will
inject that right so in this video we
have covered that how we can find
Windows password in a plain text by
using mini cats so thanks for watching
this video