hello everyone welcome to tutorials
point so in this video we'll talk about
key loggers so before going further let
me ask you one question
so have you ever been tried to check
that what's your friend or another
person is doing his computer so your
answer is key loggers so key loggers are
spyware or surveillance software which
we can use in order to track activity of
a particular user so the help of key
logger what we can do we can record a
keystroke that runs the user typing in
his keyboard and with the help of key
logger we can also take a screenshot of
that system so some key loggers are very
advanced and they are capable of
recording internet history so all we
have to do is we just have to install a
key logger program inside the targeted
system so once we install the key logger
then we can monitor all the activity of
a particular user and if you are a
parent then I recommend you to please
install key logger
in order to monitor that what's your
child do on internet so the key loggers
are available for Windows Linux Mac and
nowadays key loggers are also available
for smartphones even for iPhones also
now let's see how we can install one key
logger named as kid logger in our system
now let's use tit logger in order to
capture screenshots keystrokes as well
as audio messages well we can download
kit Locker from here from the official
website that is keyed logger dotnet and
this is a very handy key logger I have
ever used so let me just go here to
download and this key logger is
available for Windows OS Linux Android
phones and even for Blackberry phones
also so let me download it and it's a
zip archive file and here you can see a
zip file is created and here is the
setup so the password of this key logger
is one two three four five click on OK
and let's just install this key logger
and here you can see that the key logger
is installed now click on finish and
here you will see that our key logger
will be launched so this is the main
menu of this key logger so you can
capture the keystrokes of all the users
by just selecting that user so right now
in my system there is only one user that
is named as user so you can see here so
let me just check this up and if I go
here to options you will see the options
are the things which we want to record
or we want to capture so you can see
that this will store a keystrokes means
if I type anything in my keyboard that
will get stored and then it will also
take a record of USB removable
insertions then it will also record a
Skype chat and Roo messages and then it
will also take a snapshot or it will
also store the browser history and the
search phrases so what else we can do is
in order to protect this key logger and
if we want that nobody can't access this
key logger so we can also protect this
key logger application by clicking over
here password protected key logger and
we can set a particular password then
here you will see the output folder
means where this key logger stores the
file so this key logger will store the
file in local disk c program files kit
logger and here is one directory called
a logs and after 15 days all files will
be deleted so you can change some
settings from here so even you can
connect this key logger to your kit
logger dotnet account but for that you
have to buy a premium subscription of
this key logger and by going here to
sound recorder what we can do we can
even record a sound of a particular user
so here is the option of screen capture
so what the screen capture will do this
key logger will take a screenshot of
users computers after a particular
interval so let me go here let me close
this up and let's click on start
monitoring and here you will see that it
sends the message the kit logger has
been activated successfully so now I can
close this key logger now in order to
verify let me open notepad file
so I'm just right here anything we are
being monitored your hacked so just
write down anything someone is watching
us so let me close this notepad file now
in order to see that whether this key
logger is storing of a keystroke or not
what we can do is the there are two
things the first thing is we can stop
the key logger and then we can check on
the other hand we can directly go to
that local this.c directory where the
key logger is actually storing all the
stuff so it's Program Files and here is
a directory called a state logger so you
can see here and here is that directory
logs so this key logger key logger
stores all the data in HTML file so you
can see here that HTML file is created
and here is the date so let me open this
file and here you can see that it's a
new session for user so first of all
it's displaying that what what is the
application that the user is using so as
we know that we have open notepad so
that's why they so that's why it's list
it's listed here notepad then here is
the data which we have written so you
can see here and then we have open kid
logger and then we have open Mozilla
Firefox then we have opened notepad so
this key logger also take record of all
the applications which are being run in
that operating system so at the top here
you can see that we can also apply a
particular filter there are a lot of
filters like if I click on application
then it will list out all the
application that is opened by user so
you can see Kate logon then run the
notepad and even if I click on web it's
nothing because we haven't opened
anything yet but or if you are doing
Skype chat then this key logger will
also take a record of that Skype chat so
you can just look at that message that
Skype chat by clicking over here on
messages but at this time there are no
messages so let me select the by default
option that is select type and here you
will see all the stuff so this is how a
typical key logger works and in this
video we have discussed that what is key
logger and what are different types of
key loggers and how we can use gate
logger you know
to captures keystrokes so thanks for
watching this video