hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about ethical hacking faces or the steps
which one have to follow in order to
perform a successful heck so there are
five faces of ethical hacking recommends
scanning gaining access maintaining
access and clearing tracks so the first
phase of vertical hacking is recognized
so the term recommends also stands for
information gathering which means
gathering the information about our
target so our target could be anything
like a website person web server or so
on so what we can do is in this phase
recurrence or information gathering we
tries to find information about our
target so if our target is a website
then you can find the information of
that website like the IP address of that
website is that website hosted on a
shared server or a dedicated server or
the or that website is built with any
content management system or what kind
of frameworks are used in order to build
that website so if our target is a web
server then we can find out that what
are the open ports on that web server
and what other service is running on
them and if our target is a person then
we'll try to find the information about
the person history like where the where
that person works its contacts number
and something interesting information
from its social profile so that once we
complete with this first phase reference
then we'll jump into scanning so in the
scanning phase we actually scan each and
every component of the system or the
website in order to find the
vulnerabilities so once we found the
vulnerabilities then the next step is to
exploit that vulnerability which means
in order to take the access so once we
scan the system we found the
vulnerability then we will try to take
the access of that system by exploiting
that vulnerability so in the third phase
we actually take access and once we are
inside the system once we are
successfully expert in that system then
the first step which one have to perform
is we have to first make a backdoor so
what is backdoor just for example we are
inside one system and we somehow lost
the access from that system that what we
can do we are not able to get into that
system back so the first process is that
once we are inside system we tries to
maintain our access
so in order to maintain our access we
can upload any shell and even we can
generate our own vulnerability in that
system so that we can come back into
their system in order to take access so
this is what we do in maintaining access
phase there is fourth phase so once we
maintained our access once we have
exploited the system then the last one
is clearing tracks which means clearing
our records so we what we can do is we
can even leave the log files we can
clear the histories even we can change
them registry settings so these are the
five phases recurrence in which we find
the information then scanning in which
we stand the system and finds the
vulnerabilities then the third one is
gaining access in which we try to
exploit the system then maintaining
access in which we can upload any web
shell or we can make a backdoor so that
we can come back into that system in
order to take its access then in the
last clearing tracks so these are the
five phases which one have to follow to
perform a successful hack so in this
video we have covered there what are the
five phases of ethical hacking and
thanks for watching this video