hello everyone welcome to our new course
that is ethical hacking and cyber
security at tutorials point so in this
course we'll learn that what is ethical
hacking what are the different steps
which one have to perform for a
successful hack and we'll also talk
about some cybersecurity terms and
techniques so here you can see the
course overview so we will first of all
talk about that what is hacking and the
difference between hacking and ethical
hacking then we talk about some
information gathering techniques and the
faces which are the steps which one have
to perform an ethical hacking then we
will also talk about analyzing email
headers that why analyzing email header
is important and virtus email headers
then we'll talk about Kali Linux and how
we can install Kali Linux by using
virtualization so once we complete this
basic part then we jump into some
information security topics in which
we'll talk about cryptography encryption
algorithm and steganography
so these kept ography encryption
algorithm and Stegner of free are
actually three terms which ensures a
data protection or a data security then
we'll talk about some batch programming
that how we can make some batch files
and how we can turn batch programming
into some malicious programming then
we'll talk about system hacking in which
we will see that how we can crack
windows Password linux password and how
windows stores our password and some
password storage policy so in windows
hacking will also learn about that how
we can secure our system by enabling
drive security BitLocker we'll also talk
about some different new terms which
might be new for you in the security
then we will jump into some networking
concepts in the network security in
which we will talk about what are
proxies VPNs and how we can use them in
order to jump change over IP and in
order to bypass filters then we'll also
talk about some network security tools
like Skype e H ping then we'll see that
what is intrusion detection system what
is intrusion prevention system and we'll
also do one example of IDs and IP a
system that is snot
then we'll talk about some sniffing
attacks basically these kind of attacks
are network attacks are which are done
on the network like sniffing how we can
sniff the network either it could be
before you want to sniff the network a
wireless network you want to sniff an
LAN network then we'll talk about that
how we can
do em Itanium attack that is
man-in-the-middle attack by using our
poisoning technique then we'll see some
DNS poisoning technique and then we'll
talk about that how we can crack I
Triple E a two 2.11 protocol that is
wireless standard in which you will see
that how wireless security protocol
works and how we can connect different
wireless security protocols in the
wireless hacking then we'll talk about
that what is do DDoS attack
what is dos attack difference between
doors and doors and what are the
countermeasures which we can take in
order to protect our servers then we'll
talk about some malware like Trojans how
the trojan works how malware works how
viruses works then we'll also do some
malware analysis that is static analysis
dynamic malware analysis in order to see
that how malware works actually at the
background then we'll talk about some
penetration testing techniques some V
apt tools that we can use in order to do
penetration testing so then we'll talk
about social engineering toolkit which
is present inside Kali Linux and then in
the last of this course we'll talk about
digital forensics that what is digital
forensics and how we can investigate a
particular system if any cyber crime
happens so thanks for watching this
video hope to see in the next one