hello everyone now let's create some
malicious/bad files in order to see that
what else we can do with the help of
batch programming now let's create some
batch files in order to extend the
functionality of batch programming well
I will use the same window salmon
operating system in my VirtualBox in
order to test those files so first of
all we will make one batch file which
will delete all the files present inside
a particular directory or the files
which are present inside a particular
disk drive so let's go here to my
computer and here you will find one that
disk drive that is local disk key so
let's create some file inside that so
I'm creating a notepad file here let me
copy this up and paste it some for few
more times so here you will see that we
have created 29 files now let's go back
and let's open the notepad so here we
will write down the code which is
responsible for deleting all the files
so at the rate echo off then here we
will write on de el sol de L is actually
command in command prompt which is used
to delete a particular file or all the
files you can see here the delete
command is supported by a command prompt
and here we'll pass the two arguments F
and Q so F is f means forcefully and
then here we have to write down the path
of a particular folder or a path of a
particular disk drive of which we want
to delete the files and we will write
here local disk e and here I will just
put the star then dot then star again so
this symbol is actually used for
selecting all the files so you can also
check it here let's go here to local
disk E and if I just put it here you can
see that it has listed out all the files
present inside that particular directory
so let me save that file
so let's save this file as delete dot
dat click on save and you can see here
that the files come here so now if I
double click on this file or execute
this file and if I go back here to the
my computer local disk II you will see
that this file has actually deleted all
the files which are present inside local
disk II so similarly what you can do you
can specify here the path of a local
disk C and you note and you all know
that in local disk C our windows files
and configuration files are present and
if you want to make this file this batch
file as a malicious one you can just
point to system 32 directory and if this
file delete solve the file present
inside the system 32 directory then our
system will be corrupted and it will
never start once we shut down that
system now let's do one thing let's
create one more file which will shut
down a particular system and we'll give
a particular message to the user so
let's go here let me close this thing
and let's create a new notepad file so
we have to write down the same code at
the ready go off and here we will write
down message
so here the msg is actually command in a
command prompt in order to display a
particular message so we have to write
here an Asterix that is star and here we
have tried down the message you are
hacked and just hit enter and here we
will write down the command in order to
shut down a particular system so I'm
writing here shutdown followed by - s
means shutdown and here I will specify a
particular time like - T that after
particularly timer shift system will be
shut down so just right here you can
give any seconds that give it as 10 that
after 10 seconds our system will be shut
down and here we will give one more
argument that is -
so this is for actually displaying a
particular comment so let's right here
you are hacked by batch file and let me
close the double quotes and let's just
save this file on my desktop and you can
just rename it as anything like hello
dot bad so here you can see that if I
just double click on this file so the
first of all this file will display a
send message that you are hacked and if
I click on OK here you will see that
this is this message that is comment you
are hacked by the batch file and now you
can see that normal system is shutting
down so this is how you can also make
this kind of batch files in order to
shut down a particular system and you
can just convert it into dot exe file
and you can change its icon and you can
do a lot of things so now the next thing
we have to do is obviously we have to
start our Windows 7 operating system
again
so the next example which I want to show
you is actually a part of DNS poisoning
attack so first let me just log in so in
upcoming videos we will discuss about
DNS poisoning in which we can change the
DNS configuration of a particular system
and then we can redirect a user of a
particular website to another website so
as we all know that versus the function
of DNS is actually used for changing the
domain name into IP address so in look
in Microsoft Windows operating system
there is one files called as host file
which is used to mapping the domain name
into an IP address so that file that is
host file is present inside local disk c
windows and system 32 and here is one
directory called as drivers et Cie and
here you can see the host file present
inside this directory and if I open this
file in notepad you will see here that
it has listed out the sample
configuration so here you can see a
local host so it's a domain name and
once we type the local host in any
browser we just get redirected to this
IP address now what I am going to do is
I will create one entry inside this file
and I will point out and write down here
google.com and unknown IP which means if
anyone just IP in browser google comm he
just get redirected to that IP and that
IP and that IP is not actually a real
one so that's why the user will see her
a 404 not found message or any other
message now let's go here to our notepad
okay so let's write down a code for this
DNS poisoning attack so I'm just writing
over here at the ready go off and first
of all we will change our directory so
we will go to C then windows
and system32 then drivers and et Cie and
here we go so let's just verify this
part by clicking over here so see
windows system32 drivers and
et Cie so we have to write down this D
as testing okay let's go here now here
we will write down a command echo and
here we'll specify a first of all here
we will write down the IP address so
let's write here local host IP address
again and now let's add here the domain
name google.com and just we use this
redirection Allah crater in order to
save this output of echo in a particular
file and that file name is hosts so
let's do one more entry with the same IP
and now this time just slide down here
as to DP google.com let's do one more
time
let's not do it for HTTP
okay now let's save this file so here
you can see that this file is created on
my desktop and in order to run this file
we have to run this file with an
administrator privileges so let's go
here and just run this file as an
administrator now in order to verify let
us go back here and let's just open this
file again and see that whether we are
successfully able to make an entry in
that file or not and here you can see
our entries and here is our IP address
and here is that domain now let's go
here and let's start the internet
explorer let's just open a new tab so
now let's write here HTTP google.com and
let's see what happen
so here you can see that our inter
Explorer is displaying this error that
is an infant Explorer cannot display the
webpage why this is giving us an error
because as soon as we just write here as
TTP google.com and hit enter however
this domain just get mapped to this IP
that is this one localhost IP and there
is no local host server running so
that's why it's down so that's why we
are seeing this message so what else we
can do is so even you can just write
here a legitimate IP a public IP and if
just user open that page or particular
website he just get redirected to that
public IP so what attackers do they
actually map a particular systems into
their own IP which is a malicious one so
the same thing you can do for the
multiple domains so this was a small
introduction we can say for a DNS attack
which we will cover in the upcoming
video
now in the last let's create a last
batch file which will disable the mouse
by hitting the registry entries in our
Windows operating system so while doing
the windows hacking I also told you that
how we can copy the Sam file by going to
registry editor so first of all let's go
there
so let's write here agitate and here you
can see the registry editor now what I'm
going to do here is I will create a
batch file which will do a little
modification in the registry and will
actually disable the mouse of this
operating system so first of all let me
take you to that path or the registry
which holds the mouse settings so let's
go here to the H key local machine then
system then currentcontrolset and here
you will found one directory called a
services and here is one directory
called as most class
so let's directly go there and here you
can see the directory mouse mouse class
and here you can see that the mouse
class driver and here the file which is
we want to hit
so it's name is start and if I just
double click on it so by default it
value is 3 so if I just change its value
and make it as a4 and click on OK and if
I boot my system again then that time my
mouse will not work so now what we have
to do in our batch file we actually have
to hit this registry and we will try to
change the value of this file that is
start and the data type it's it's a
registry D word so let me just close
this thing and let's create a new
notepad file and now let's write here
echo had the ready go off and this file
also requires and administrative
privileges so first of all we'll write
down this command set key
and here we'll write down H key local
machine then system currentcontrolset
followed by the services then mas class
mo u CLA SS and now what we'll do first
of all we will delete the previous key
which is present inside that file and
that the start file and we'll write here
registry delete percentile key and then
we'll make a new entry that is our eg
registry add then key and here we'll
write here the file so we can specify a
file by writing here /v and the file
name we saw is start and we'll specify
one more parameter hi the /t and here
we'll write a data type so the T stands
for type and it's registry D word it's
not an integer
so and here we'll specify the value or
the data and that's for now let's just
cross check and verify so it's H key
local machine and system
currentcontrolset services an MOU class
okay everything looks perfect
now let's just save this file as reg dot
dat so you can see this file here
now let's run this file as an
administrative privileges
so first of all it asks us that whether
we want to delete the previous registry
just right on here why and now if we go
here to the start you will see that we
cannot add it okay nobody's let's just
restart this operating system and let me
just close this file and now here you
can see that our mouse is disabled you
can see here that here is my mouse on my
parent operating system and if I open
this one you will see that my mouse is
not working so this is a very annoying
trick which you can do and be sure that
what you are doing while using this
batch file because and also be sure to
write a particular registry path and if
suddenly you will write a wrong registry
path then it will cause a big problem
for you so in this video we have covered
that what else we can do by batch
programming and how we can turn a simple
batch programming into malicious one so
thanks for watching this video