hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about that how we can secure our Windows
data and how we can secure our Windows
hard drive so there is one utility in
Windows called as BitLocker so we can
use this utility in order to encrypt
entire hard drive or even we can encrypt
only our data and we can also add
password in order to protect it so now
let's see how we can use BitLocker in
our system now let's try to encrypt our
data and secure our drive by using
BitLocker so let me open my computer and
here you can see that right now in my
system there are three drives local disk
C then D and E so first of all we have
to select a drive which we want to
encrypt and log by BitLocker so just try
to click over here and here you will see
one option turn on BitLocker so if this
option is not available in your computer
which means your computer is not
supporting BitLocker so let me click
over here so when for the first time you
will open the bit Locker it will ask you
whether you want to protect your drive
by using password or you want to protect
your drive by using smart card so I
recommend you to protect your drive by
using password so here you have to add a
password so let me add a password here
click on next and then it asks you for
saving a recovery key so what happen is
when for the first time you are setting
the BitLocker you add a password then a
BitLocker will give you a one key and
with the help of that key you can
recover your data just for example you
forgot your password and you are not
able to retrieve your data so what you
can do is you can retrieve your data by
using the recovery key which the
BitLocker will give you so that's why
now BitLocker is saying that where we
want to save the recovery key so there
are different option we can even print
the recovery key we can save it to a
file and we can save this recovery key
to a particular USB Drive also and we
can even save this recovery key to our
Microsoft account so for the time being
I am saving that recovery key to a file
so that I can show you that how recovery
key looks like let me click here so I'm
say
during this recovery key on my desktop
you can see here BitLocker recovery key
click on save and it's a text file and
now click on next now the BitLocker
encryption is actually of two types the
first thing is whether you want to
encrypt entire data in a drive or you
want to encrypt entire Drive so just for
example if you are disk drive is of 50
gigs and your data inside that drive has
20 gates so the first option says that
you want to encrypt only 20 gigs data
then you can select one here so it's a
faster and if you want to encrypt entire
Drive that is 500 gigs then it's a
slower process you can see here so I'm
selecting the first one because I want
to encrypt my data not entire Drive so
click on next and now start encrypting
and it will take some time depending
upon your data and here you can see that
the drive encryption has been started so
here you can see the process so I'm
pausing this video and I will resume
this video once my encryption completes
and here you can see that the encryption
of that Drive is completed let me just
shut down and restart my system and then
I will resume this video so here you can
see that our this drive local disk D is
encrypted and is locked by BitLocker so
you can see a logged sign here and if I
just double click on it then it asks us
for the password so here you can see
that it's asking us for the password so
let me just write down here password and
click on unlock and then you can see
that we are able to retrieve our data
back and here you can see that now this
lock is unlocked so this is how
BitLocker works and let me also show you
that how recovery key looks like so if
you remember then we have saved this
recovery key on my desktop and you can
see that it's a text file and if I open
this recovery key so this is how the
recovery key looks like around a random
value so you can enable BitLocker in
order to protect your data and in this
video we have covered
that what is BitLocker and how BitLocker
works so thanks for watching this video