hello everyone in this video we will
talk about one of the most important
term used in cyber security called as
cryptography so now let's talk about it
so what is cryptography so cryptography
is actually an art of hiding our data in
order to protect that data from third
party people so we can even use
cryptography to convert our normal text
into an unreadable form so that it can
be remained safe from the third party
people so the main three principles of
cryptography is confidentiality
availability and integrity
so confidentiality ensures that our data
is secure and integrity ensure us that
data our data is not being tampered or
altered by another third party people
and availability ensure us that our data
is available whenever we need now let's
talk about one of the most popularly
used cryptography technique in order to
protect our data and that technique is
called as encryption so what is
encryption so encryption is actually a
process of converting our plaintext into
n ciphertext which means here you can
see that here is our plaintext hello and
after the encryption our text becomes
this that is an unreadable form and this
is called as ciphertext so you can see
here encryption is a process of
converting our data into a ciphertext so
that integrity of that data can be
maintained and the encryption is the
path of a cryptography technique now
let's talk about different types of
cryptography techniques so there are
three types of cryptography security
cryptography public key cryptography and
hash functions now let's talk about each
of them in detail so first of all we
will talk about secret key cryptography
so secret key cryptography is also
called as symmetric key encryption so
what it means it means while encrypting
the data the key which we will use in
encryption will be the same and while
the time of decrypting the data the key
which we will use is the same as of
encryption so here you can see that here
is our data and the while the time of
encrypting is this data our key is a
secret key and it's the same and once we
got our
encrypt
and we want to decrypt that so while the
time of decryption we will use the same
key which we used in order to encrypt
the data so this is in the case of
secret key cryptography now let us talk
about public key cryptography so in
public key cryptography there are two
keys so here you can see that the key
for encryption is different and the key
which is used while decrypting is
different so that is why public key
cryptography is also called as
asymmetric encryption now let's talk
about the last type of cryptography that
is hash functions so what is hash
function so hashing is actually a one
way conversion which means we have won
our text so here you can see we have one
text that is hello so once we convert
the hash of this hello so you can see
here that we got our hash and this is a
one-way conversion means once we got our
hash we are not be able to retrieve our
text back
so that is why hashing is called as
one-way conversion and it is not
recommended to use this technique in
order to protect your data now let's see
how hash functions and encryption works
now let's have a look at different
hashing algorithm and let's see how
encryption works with the help of one
Python program so in order to proceed we
have to download this Python language
and you can download the Python from
here from Python dot arc so python
language is available in two versions
Python 3 and Python 2.7 so the only
difference between these two versions
are the difference of syntax or the way
we write the code so for that program we
have to download this Python 2.7 and I
have already downloaded and install
Python 2.7 in my system so once you
install the Python so the next thing you
have to do is you have to download that
Python file that is called as Swiss
crypto so I have created this file and
name it as a Swiss crypto and you can
download this file from my github link
that is disk dot github.com slash
sharath kumar 97 so let me just click
over here so here you can see that the
file which I have created so
my name my name dit as a Swiss crypto
tool and it's purely written in Python
so it supports different hashing
algorithms and different encryption
algorithms so we can also send a secure
email by encrypting our body with the
help of private keys with the help of
this tool and this script is compatible
with Python 2.7
so before running the script we have to
install some Python libraries that is PI
crypto and TK Intel and all we also have
to resolve some dependencies issues so
if you face any problem while running
the script you can reach out to me at
this email address and if I scroll down
here you can see the Python code so
let's save this file click on draw
right-click and click on save page s and
let's save the script on my desktop with
the name as Swiss crypto so if I go here
on my desktop you will see this script
Swiss crypto and if you have Python
correctly installed then this will be
the icon of the script and here you can
see that it's written Python file so
let's right-click over here and click on
edit with ID ad so here you can see the
entire source code of the script so the
next thing you have to do is you have to
install PI crypto a library of Python
which contains lot of cryptographic
functions which I have imported in this
script so in order to install any Python
library so we have to go to python
directory that where the python is
installed so by default the python is
installed in local disk c and here you
will find a folder named as python 27 so
let me open this up and here you will
find one directory called as scripts so
let me double click over here so once we
are here just press shift and then click
on right mouse button and here you will
see one option that open command window
here so click over here and here you
will see that a command prompt is open
and here is the path that where we are
writin C Python 2.7 and sick
so we have two right here with then
install followed by the Python library
which we want to install so pip is a
program in Python which is used in to
install different Python libraries so
here you can write PI crypto so I have
already downloaded and install this
library so that's right same requirement
already satisfied so have to install the
spike crypto library and if still you
are facing some problems then you just
feel free to reach out to me so let me
just close this up let's open this thing
ok so now let's try to run this script
so in order to run it just click over
here run and run module so once we run
it here you will see a beautiful
graphical menu containing secure
messaging system and it contains a lot
of options in its menu that is hash
convertor encryption decryption and
secure email so but for in this video
we'll cover all the hashing algorithms
along with one encryption algorithm so
let's click over here hash converter and
here you will find a different hashing
algorithm like md5 sha-1 shot 256
shopify 112 just for example if I click
over here md5 and here it asks us for
entering the data so if I enter the data
hello and if I click on convert here you
will see that our data hello is actually
converted into md5 hash and here you can
find the hash of hello and behind the
script you can see here that in the
Python shell the hash of hello is
created and you can copy it from here so
as I told you earlier that hashing is
one way conversion that once we can
watch our text into a hash we are not
able to retrieve our text back so
depending upon the hashing algorithm you
are using you will get a complex hash so
just for example let's try to convert
our text by using sha-1 so let's try to
convert here sunlight let's try
something here called as
click on convert and you will see that
we now this time we got a hash but that
is a little bit longer than md5 and you
can even create a longest hash by using
this algorithm Shopify 112 that is 500
bucks and let's try to convert this text
only by using Shopify 112 and if I click
on convert you will see that we got a
very long hash you can see here the
hashing value and if I go back here you
will see that the chef I won 12 hash of
that text so you can also use this tool
in order to store passwords in your
database in hashes so this was all about
hashing algorithms now let's talk about
encryption that how encryption works so
as I told you earlier that in order to
encrypt the data we have to add one key
and in order to decrypt the data we have
to add the same key depending upon the
encryption algorithm we are using so let
us run this file again and now this time
let's go here to the encryption let us
click over here symmetric encryption
block cipher and in this video let's
concentrate on this stream ciphers and
let's select this algorithm a our
seafood that is driver cipher 4 so these
all kind of different algorithms I will
explain you in the next video but for
the sake of this video let's consider it
over here so it asks us for the key and
the data to convert so in the first
input field let's write here the secret
key and our secret key will be you can
write here anything like secret 1 2 3 4
5 so it's the secret key is it's just
like a password so once we add the
secret key here we have to add our data
which we want to encrypt so let's add
here let's add here any random string
that is password of Facebook click on
convert and here you will see that we
got our encrypted text and this text is
in the form of hex value so here you can
see that our encrypted text or we can
say that it's over
cyphertext because it's encrypted now in
order to decrypt this text we want this
encrypted text and along with this key
so now let us try to decrypt this text
click on description so may take
encryption and we have to select the
same algorithm which we have used while
encrypting so here Enter key to decrypt
so our key was secret one two three four
five and let us copy this in encrypted
text from here let's go back let's save
this text click on ok and here you will
see that we got our normal text back
that was password of Facebook and if I
go back to the Python shell you will see
here that the decrypted text is the
password of Facebook which we have
entered while encryption so this is how
a normal encryption decryption and
hashing algorithm works now let us try
to change a little modification in the
encrypted data so here you can see that
if I enter only a single word here like
P and if I change one key sum to
something random and if I click on OK
here you will see that it will give us
an error of odd length string which
means the key should be the same while
encryption of data and the data which we
got after an encryption should be the
same so in this video we have covered
that what is cryptography
what is hashing algorithms and virtus
encryption and we have a look at one
Python program which we can use in order
to encrypt something annual in order to
see that how hashing works thanks for
watching this video