hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about Google Docs so all of you might
familiar with the Google search engine
that how Google search engine works but
have never been thought that what else
we can search by using Google so just
for example let me ask you one question
that if you want to find out all the
admin pages of all the websites which
are present inside of the Google
database do you know what the curious or
what you will type in Google search bar
so another example is so what if if we
want to find all the public IP webcams
in Google or even if you want to find
out the MySQL database passwords of all
the websites by using Google do you know
what you will type in in the Google
search bar so our answer is Google Docs
now let's see what our Google Docs
so Google Docs are nothing but just some
special keywords or a special search
strings which we can use in order to get
the desired output from the Google
database so we can use Google Docs in
order to fetch interesting information
from Google so there is one website coil
as exploit DB com so this website
contains a database of called as Google
hacking database so in this Google
hacking database there is a collection
of Google Docs which we can use in order
to get some interesting information from
Google and all the Google Docs which are
present inside this Google hacking
database are founded by various security
researchers now let's see how we can use
Google Docs in order to get some
interesting information from Google now
let's see how we can extract some useful
information from Google by passing
malicious links into it called as Google
Doc strings well the Google Sports
various parameters or operators which we
can give in order to find some
interesting information so the first
parameter we can give is called as site
so site parameters will list out a
particular information of a particular
website only so just for example I have
written here site then colon so if I
just write here any website name like
tutorialspoint.com hit enter and here we
will see that each and every link of
this page is of tutorialspoint.com
so this is the one operator or one
parameter which we can use in order to
find out a particular information of a
particular website by using this site
operator so the next operator is file
type so we can also use this parameter
called as file type in order to find out
a particular files present in that
website so if I just write here file
type and you can write down any file
type like dog PDF XLS so I have written
here PDF and if I hit enter here you
will see that it has listed out all the
URLs which contains PDF files and here
you can see one of them so we can also
combine two three parameters to make our
custom string which can be used in order
to find out a particular data the next
parameter we can use is called as in URL
so in URL parameters return a particular
string which is present in that URL so
let me just erase all this thing so if I
just write here in URL then here we can
specify a string or we can specify a
particular path which will be present in
all the URLs which Google will return so
just for example you want to find login
pages so you can just write down here in
URL admin login dot PHP and here you
will see that the Google will list out
all the links of admin pages of a
different websites so you can see all of
them here I am opening these pages and
the next tab you can see here and each
of it is admin control panel so this is
how we can use in URL parameter so the
next parameter we can use is called as
in text so in text is used to find out
text in a particular website which means
if I just write here in text and if I
just write here hacking then it will
list out all the websites which contains
this word in their body so you can see
here each and every website contains
this word in their body so this is how
we can use in text parameter now let me
take you
to the database of Google hacking
database which is men st. maintained by
exploit DB so exploit DV dot-com
maintains a google hacking database
which means all the google hacking dots
is actually stored here in the database
of exploitable com and here you can see
the Google hacking database and if I
scroll down you can see here that all
the Google Docs strings are actually
divided into different categories like
the strings for web server detection
strings for file containing passwords
then strings for error messages strings
for burnable files so if I click over
here files containing password then here
you will see a list of Google Docs
strings which we can use in order to
find out the files which contains
password and here you can see all the
Google Docs strings so all these Google
Docs things are actually founded by
various cyber security researchers and
once they found the string then they
post it inside this google hacking
database so just for example let me
select this one the first google docs
string and here you can see the Google
Doc description so here is the Google
Doc string and what it does is actually
find out the password of MySQL database
so let's do one thing let me copy this
Google Doc string and let's open
google.com here and then let's just
paste this string and let's see what we
got
so you can see here that it has listed
out a various websites which contains
MySQL database password and if I open
this tab here you can see the password
so that the database name is invisible
so username is also invisible and DB one
password is visible so you can see here
that we can also got here authentication
keys secure key so similarly you can see
here the database user database password
and you can check here that the auth
user is also present the auth key and
various access tokens so this is how
Google Doc works now let's try some more
examples
so if you want to protect your website
from Google docking then make sure that
you disallow important directories or a
files from Google by adding them in
robots or txt file on your server so
what what else we can do is we can even
find out various online devices let's
check that what are the google doc
strings available for that so here you
can see google doc strings so let's just
check here webcam so here is that Google
Doc strings so what else you can do is
you can even combine this Google Doc
string with that site parameter in order
to find that whether that site contain
this Google Doc string or not and here
you can see that it has listed out all
the webcams of various countries so you
can see here a webcam and here you can
see the same webcam and it's saying that
contacting IP camera so this is how we
can use Google Doc in order to find out
interesting information so in this video
we have covered that what is google doc
strings and how we can use them so
thanks for watching this video