hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about one of the most important concept
of cyber security as well as networking
called as proxies so now what is a proxy
so a proxy is nothing but just a
middleman between us and a remote server
so you can see here that here is our
computer and here is our proxy and here
is our remote web server so you can see
here that a proxy is a middleman which
is sitting between us and a remote
server so by using proxy what happen is
if we made any request for that web
server so that requests have to be
passed from this proxy server so now
let's read here so a proxy the server
which act as a middleman between a
client and a server so proxy server
protects and hides computer from the
outside network so you can see here that
here is our IP address so if we made any
requests to google.com then that request
has to be passed from proxy and once a
proxy server receives our request then
the proxy server will hides over IP and
send that request with its IP so by
using proxy server we can hide several
IP address and one of the main benefit
of the proxy server is that you might
have seen in colleges that some of web
sites are blocked by network
administrator so we can bypass that
filters by using proxy now let's see
that how many types of proxy we can use
in our system so first of all we'll talk
about tab based proxies so tab based
proxies will only work in a particular
tab so there are some websites which
provides tab based proxies functionality
feature so here is the link of that
website
Zankou comm hide - dot-com so there are
many websites which provide the same
functionality but the thing to be notice
is that in tab based proxies the proxy
will so only a single tab will get
affected by that proxy but what if if we
want a proxy in entire browser so there
are some proxies which we can use in
order to infect our entire browser so
that proxies are called as browser based
proxies so how we can use browser based
proxies so what happen is there are some
websites in Internet which provides a
list of free proxy servers around the
world so here is some website free prop
stylist com
hide - calm so we can copy the IP
address from that websites and then we
can change our browser proxy settings
and then we can add that address in
order to affect our entire browser and
by using browser based proxy it doesn't
matter that how many tabs you open so
every tab you will open will get
affected by that proxy so that's why
browser-based proxies are best now let
us talk about anonymous proxy so
nonnamous proxy is called a store proxy
so tor proxy is an example of an
animal's proxy and tor is an open source
software which is designed to hop into
different proxy addresses and then our
request will went to that server so tor
proxy is one of the most secure proxy
which is is being used nowadays so what
happen is if we made any request by
using tor proxy then that request will
hop into different servers and then it
will went to a remote IP address or a
remote server so the Tor proxy comes
with the tor browser and you can use tor
proxy and download it from here
tor project.org and tor proxy is
available for different operating system
Microsoft Linux OS and even smartphone
also so what if if you want an entire
system entire operating system that will
be affected by that proxy so there is
one operating system called as Unix
so we can use monique's operating system
in order to use proxy for entire
operating system so what happen is even
if you pick a particular website then
our ping request will also be affected
by tor proxy by using a unix so 1x
operating system comes to the unix
gateway so what happen is if we made any
request from UNIX operating system then
that request will go to the UNIX gateway
and in UNIX gateway there is a tor proxy
which is waiting for our request so this
is how onyx works and we can also use
phonics in order to do some internet
fraud scamming because UNIX hides our
real IP address now let's talk about
three different types of proxies so here
you can see that there are three proxy
anonymous light transparent so these are
the proxies categories which we can use
so the first one is anonymous so as I
told you earlier that anonymous proxy is
one of the most secure proxy we can use
and then the another proxy type is a lie
so life proxies are also secure and they
also hide our IP address so whereas the
transparent blocks proxies change over
IP address but they are not secure so
transparent proxies are not secure
that's why the speed of transparent
proxy is very high whereas the speed of
anonymous proxies and the light proxies
are very slow so these are the types of
proxies which we can use now let's see
how we can use proxies in our operating
system now let's use tab based browser
waste and system based proxy so let me
open my Mozilla Firefox well I told you
earlier that in tab based proxy the
proxy will only work in a particular tab
and here you can see that I have opened
this tab and here is this website Zankou
comm so this website provide us the
feature of tab based proxy so once you
open this website you will see an input
box here so just for example if I write
here google.com and hit enter so here
you will see that the Google of
Netherland is open which means there is
a proxy which is set it up only in this
tab and in order to confirm we can check
our IP address by going here to what is
my IP address comm and here you can see
the IP address along with the ISP detail
services and country so this proxy will
work only in this tab in order to
confirm let me open another tab and
let's just write here what is my IP
address comm and you will see here that
our original IP addresses of India so
similar to this website center.com so
there is one more website called as hide
proxy dot m-mean so this is a website
length so its height dot a mean slash
slash proxy so this also provide us the
feature of tab based proxy so we can
write down here web address which we
want to open so let me write here
google.com and this website also provide
us the feature of selecting the proxy
location whether you want to use a proxy
server of USA Germany or Netherland
click over here to Germany and you can
click over here nan visit anonymously
and you will see here that the Google of
Germany is open knowledge just verify
and here you can see the ISP our IP
address along with the country name so
you can use these two websites in order
to use tab based proxies but what if if
we want to use browser-based proxy so
that if you open different tabs and that
will also get affected by that proxies
so before starting with that
browser-based proxy the first thing we
have to know is that browser-based
proxies works after configuring the
browser network settings so which means
first of all what we have to do is we
have to find out a proxy which is
available and listening and then we can
use that proxy or that IP address in our
browser network settings so here you can
see that here is one website called as
free proxy lists dotnet and it provide
us the free proxy lists so you can see
here all the IP addresses so these IP
addresses are of the proxy server along
with the port here you can see the
protocol anonymity along with the
country and uptime and response and
transfer rate so depending upon your
need you can select one of them so just
for example if I want to use this proxy
so I can copy this IP address then what
I have to do is I have to go to here to
my browser settings so I'm using Mozilla
Firefox so let's just go here to options
then advanced then we have to go here to
the network and here you can see
configure how Firefox connect to the
Internet now click on settings then here
by default our browser works with this
use system proxy settings and here we
want to manually configure the proxy
settings so let's paste IP address here
which we want to use as a proxy and here
we have to write down the port so let's
go back here and you can see that the
pour test
8:08 one so let me just write down here
the port number that is eight oh
8:1 and if you want to use this proxy
for a CD PS protocol also an FTP
protocol also then you can just check
this checkbox and click on OK now if I
in next step I open google.com and in
the next tab let me open what is my IP
address comm so you can see here now our
IP address is of Russia here you can see
the country along with IP address which
means now our entire browser is affected
by this proxy so this is how browser
based proxies work so there are a lot of
websites from where you can get the free
proxy lists so another example of the
web this website is us proxy dot org and
here you can also get the free proxy
lists so this is how browser based
proxies work but but if if you want to
use a proxy for your entire system means
if your system is making any requests to
the internet and you want that that
request will pass through a proxy then
what we can do is there any solution yes
there are some operating systems or
there are some system proxies tool which
we can use in order to set our system
behind the proxy server so there is one
most commonly used system based proxy
operating system that is called as Unix
so you can download the UNIX from here
from their official website runing stark
and the UNIX operating system is
actually based on tar tar proxy so if
you don't know what is todd proxy so the
official website of tar proxy is in the
star project.org so tor proxy is
actually one of the best anonymous proxy
which we can use in order to open any
web application or any website so tor
proxy comes with the tor browser which
means once the tar proxy is set it up
then we can access that a particular
website by using tor proxy and by using
this tor browser so you can download the
tor browser from here if you don't want
to use system proxy and you only want to
use tor browser then you can download
the store browser from here and it's an
open source
so this morning's operating system is
actually comes with a UNIX gateway and
any request which we will made by UNIX
operating system will pass through the
UNIX gateway and then it will went to
different tower proxy nodes so let me
show you here to their official website
so here you can see the architecture of
UNIX workstation so here you can see
that in the green boxes these are the
applications which we will use in the
UNIX workstation so you can use any
application so similarly see we can say
that it's a Firefox browser so any
request which we will made through UNIX
workstation will pass through the UNIX
gateway and then it will went to the
different nodes and here you can see our
first node so the first node is actually
or you can say that it's a proxy then it
will go to the second proxy server then
the third proxy server and the third
node is also called as exit node from
where our request will exit and here
finally our website will went to a
website which we want to open so this is
how wanax workstation works and you can
download UNIX workstation for Windows
Linux and OS depending upon your
operating system so I have already
downloaded UNIX operating system and I
have also installed UNIX operating
system so once you install the UNIX
operating system you will notice that in
VirtualBox there will be two virtual
machines which will be created by this
one X so if I open my VirtualBox and
here you can see the two virtual
machines named as Linux workstation and
Muniz gateways created by Phonics so let
me just close this VirtualBox and here
you can see that on my desktop there is
one icon of called as Linux for Windows
so I have installed this fonox operating
system so let me open this application
and here are two options start onyx and
advanced so let me click over here start
Unix so as soon as I click over here to
start onyx the two virtual machines
which is UNIX workstation and UNIX
gateway is open and here you can see
that it's a UNIX workstation so let me
start this
UNIX workstation and right after it
bonus gate was also running here you can
see so let's wait
and here you can see that our UNIX
workstation is up and running here you
can see its desktop and now let's see
how onyx gateway looks like and here you
can see the varnish gateway so you can
change all the network settings from
uniess gateway and the effect of that
settings can be seen at UNIX workstation
so now let me go to the UNIX workstation
and let me show you how onyx works so
here you can see the UNIX workstation
and let me go here let me go to Internet
and let me click over here tar so it's
same tor browser is currently not
installed but no worries we can open
Firefox also
now here you can see that as soon as we
start UNIX workstation this Finnish
workstation will entirely covered by tor
proxy and if I open and and if I open my
Mozilla Firefox and open what's my IP
address com here you will see that there
is no need of setting up the proxy
settings or there is no need to use
proxy because this one is workstation is
a proxy in itself and here you can see
that our IP address you can see the ISP
University of Waterloo and here you can
see that it's at our exit node which
means it's a large store server from
wherever request is going out and even
if you ping a particular website then
your ping request will also be covered
by the tor proxy servers so let me open
this console and let me pin google.com
and here you can see that it will take a
little bit time why because our request
will first of all pass through different
tower nodes and then it will reach at
google.com so this is how we can use
UNIX Delta the system proxy and then tab
based proxies and browser based proxies
you know in order to hide our IP address
and to be anonymous so in this video we
have covered that what is proxy and how
we can use different proxies in order to
hide our IP address and to surf internet
anonymously so thanks for watching this
video